There's a mineral underground. Doctor!
Deep substrate foliated kalkite.
Should we fail to find any alternatives,
we will have to control
ghorman with a hand firm enough
to silence any resistance,
and you've been selected to
help plan for that possibility.
You need a radical
insurgency you can count on.
You need ghorman rebels you
can depend on to do the wrong thing.
Ghorman is a single-product economy.
We import almost
everything we need to survive.
I am constantly begging
my people to stay calm
and do nothing that
might make things worse.
The plan... your plan to bait
ghorman as a prize for outside agitators
needs to begin somewhere.
Luthen wants to know
if you're ready to work.
What does he need me for?
Isb supervisor, dedra meero.
She's there in ghorman.
She's there waiting to be killed.
We're drowning in rumors, syril.
Many people are starting to think this
new building is more than just an annex.
I'm not sure why the empire would
build an armory in the middle of palmo,
but I'm running out of answers.
There is, apparently,
no suitable replacement
or synthetic alternative for
the ghorman substrate material.
I don't know the science,
but it's bad luck ghorman.
She's in there.
She sleeps in the building.
I've seen her on the terrace.
I have a room at the
front, facing the Plaza.
Perfect.
You know, most guests don't
say that anymore. It can be loud.
I'm a deep sleeper.
You walk a very narrow path, dedra.
Syril must never know
what this is all really about.
Good things are waiting for us.
We'll be out of here soon.
We'll be back in
Coruscant. We'll be together.
We'll be rewarded.
For what? What have we accomplished?
Captain kaido is arriving today.
He'll be bringing a variety of
personnel to help manage the situation.
You're aware, sir, that the
insurgents have weapons at this point.
We're counting on it.
Let's go!
I want it done quickly. Double time!
Get that one ready next!
Help him, then.
One on each side.
Come on, soldier, look lively!
Keep it moving. Keep it moving.
Come on, you! Look lively!
Get that one ready next!
Move with purpose. Let's go!
Cassian.
What is all this?
Did you know about this?
Know about what?
They're pulling it all in.
Pulling what from where?
The barricades. What's going on here?
- They're opening the Plaza.
- You hear that?
- I'm looking at it.
- They're not opening anything.
They're putting a shell
around the building.
- What do you mean?
- I won't get a shot from here.
They're building a fortress.
- Apologies.
- I know you've been waiting.
There's reports coming
in from the countryside.
They're saying we've landed mining rigs.
You seem animated.
Rumors spread quickly these days.
Well, I'm sure captain kaido
has his assets in position.
That's why I thought it urgent we speak.
He's given orders to
barricade the building.
I saw that. Seems a wise idea.
The mining equipment. Already on site.
Is that a story director
krennic wants to be telling?
We're done with local rumors.
The only story that matters
is ghorman aggression.
The threats. The inexplicable
resistance to imperial norms.
We need what's in the ground.
The empire has been
patient long enough.
Our struggles with ghorman
are well documented at this point.
Samm.
The continued and inexplicable
ghorman resistance to imperial norms.
Many people, even some
ghormans, have already been asking
how long the empire's
Patience can be tested.
And here we are this morning
with rumors of a general
strike and mass demonstrations
how the imperial authorities
can calm the situation down.
The casualties from yesterday's
bombing of the naval depot
are still yet to be finalized.
The fear is the numbers will be
minimized to lower the temperature here.
If that is the case, it certainly
doesn't seem to be working.
There were mass
curfew violations last night
and rumors of a general
strike this morning.
Sorry, sir. Comms are
down. We're making rounds.
Imperial employees are to report
immediately to the ioc building.
Nache-band or!
We are the ghor! The galaxy is watching!
We are the ghor!
You! Karn!
You dare walk our streets?
You dare walk among us?
All this time, you...
How could we be so foolish?
I meant you no harm.
How do you say that?
How do you speak the words?
You've destroyed us.
I was here to trap outside agitators.
Look at you. Even now...
People know what you're doing.
We've had reports all night.
There's mining equipment
being dropped all over the planet.
- Rigs and droids and...
- that's a rumor!
Are you mad?
That I'd believe that?
That it's worth saying?
What kind of a being are you?
What's in our ground?
What is it you've been
sent to steal from us?
We are the ghor! The galaxy is watching!
Everything as you wanted?
What I want is a comfortable ride home.
But let's not confuse
the chain of command.
I'm the trigger, supervisor.
You're the finger.
Make sure you're available.
I'm not sure I'll be back.
Not to worry. You were never here.
Didn't log you in.
Hey, I hope things work out for you.
Rebellions are built on hope.
We are the ghor! The galaxy is watching!
Help him. Radio.
Don't make me look for you again.
No, sir.
Get the south steps unit on the line.
The galaxy is watching!
We are the ghor! The galaxy is watching!
A peaceful demonstration,
local insurgents
the galaxy is watching!
We are the ghor! The galaxy is watching!
Enza!
The galaxy is watching!
We are the ghor! The galaxy is watching!
Can you hear me?
- Cassian!
- Where are you?
Wil?
Can you hear me?
Where are you?
Repeat. Where are you? Talk to me.
- No way through.
- I work here.
- Hey! Hey! Over here!
- Let him in.
He knows me.
Even though imperial officials strive
to desperately negotiate
a peaceful demonstration,
the local insurgents spread
rumors through the night
and have organized this...
This highly volatile insurrection
you see behind me now.
Sir, we need to go.
I need to get upstairs.
Just be a minute, sir.
Just making sure we're all safe.
Over here.
Just be a minute until things calm down.
We are the ghor! The galaxy is watching!
Close all the exits.
Yes, sir.
Channel five is open?
Standing by, sir.
South gate, unit one, come in.
It'll be all right. Stay with cap so.
I have to go find my friend.
Patrol, sir? Within the crowd?
Was that not my order?
They're green, sir. They're useless.
I see imperial uniforms, sergeant.
I see a barricade Lane to the
memorial that I need kept open.
You will march them out there
immediately and secure the area.
Or you can all finish your
days in an imperial brig.
Stand to!
We are the ghor! The galaxy is watching!
Wait! Hang on, I said wait!
What have you done?
Get out.
Close it.
What are we doing here?
Following orders.
How long have you known about all this?
How long?
We can discuss this later.
It is too late already.
Syril, please.
You're gonna tell me what
this has really been about.
- You're hurting me.
- And you are going to tell me
what the mining ships are doing here.
- They're not...
- there is an armada up there!
They're already unloading
in jel-novi and leequa.
- You couldn't even wait.
- No
don't.
You tell me it's a rumor and I
will throw you out that window.
What have we been doing here?
There's a stone.
Something in the dirt here.
They need it. It's the energy program.
It's directly from the emperor.
It's something they can't do
without. They need the planet.
How long have you known this?
We're going home, syril.
We're going home as heroes.
This began long before we got here.
They've been planning it for years.
They're doing this no matter what.
We wanted to be together.
You didn't seem to mind the promotions.
Good luck, dedra.
Move out.
Eyes open. Keep it moving.
Sir.
Sir!
Find syril. Bring him back. Do
not let him leave the building.
Partagaz is on the line.
Move out!
Close! Close!
- Wilmon.
- Tell me where you are.
West Side. The
columns by the cafhouse.
- Find me.
- I can't hear you.
Find me.
Hold the line!
Orders, please.
Supervisor meero.
Proceed.
Put him on.
Channel five? Open.
One transmit five. One calling five.
Five online. Standing by.
Fire at will. Repeat. Fire at will.
Get back! Get back!
Withdraw! Withdraw!
Withdraw!
Man down! Get him out of here!
Open fire!
Behind you!
Retreat and fire!
Keep the formation!
Incoming!
Bottle!
Get down!
Balor!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Get back! Get back!
Run!
He's out there.
Supervisor, it's not safe.
Put them out there.
Get back! Come on!
Run!
Help! Help!
Who are you?
Cassian!
Come on, let's go.
Come on. Yeah.
You okay?
I'm okay. I'm okay.
We need to move.
Capso! Hey!
Where's dreena?
She ran. She was with
us. We never had a chance.
Where is she?
They went for the radio.
She might have been with them.
I have to find my brother!
Hey, hey! What are you doing?
- I'm not leaving without dreena.
- No, no, no, no, no!
- I've gotta find her!
- Wilmon, stop!
- We have to leave.
- It's not far.
Hey. Everything is far.
We need a ride to the ship.
Look at me!
Run!
Don't stop!
Get up, get up! Get up!
Cassian!
Is it dead?
You killed it.
Hey, I know you.
- Samm.
- I remember you.
Thank you.
I have to get to the hq.
That's where I'm going.
- Okay.
- No, we're leaving!
I told you I can't.
You go. I'll be all right. You'll see.
Wil, please.
I can't leave her behind.
Tell people what happened here, cass.
Ferrix.
Stone and sky.
Wait!
One last favor.
Palmo one.
This is palmo one. This
is the voice of ghorman.
This is palmo one making
an emergency broadcast
on all open channels.
This is palmo one! This is palmo one.
We are under siege.
We're being slaughtered.
The imperial murder
of ghorman has begun.
There are hundreds
of bodies this moment.
As I say these words,
hundreds of murdered
ghormans lay dead in palmo Plaza.
Thousands more on the
streets. More every minute.
We're being destroyed!
This is ghorman reaching for
any open channel that can hear me!
If you can... if you can hear me...
If you believe in truth, if
you have any faith left in truth,
please, please Mark this
message and pass it forward.
This is murder!
The empire built this fire.
They made this fire and
led us to the slaughter.
Now they expect us to
die without knowing why.
The conspiracy we've feared is real!
It's here today!
Imperial ships are already landing across
no!
Help us!
Is there no one who can help us?
Is there no one?
Dreena!
I found you.
We gotta let people know
what happened. Help me.
Even as imperial security forces
are still assessing casualties,
even as our fallen heroes are
beginning their final journeys home,
questions are being asked about
how an insurrection of this scale
could be mounted
without the aid and support
of outside rebel assistance.
In the days to come,
as the imperial martyrs
of ghorman are mourned,
we're sure to learn a great deal
more about what happened here today
and the price we'll
pay for our own safety.