Something's wrong on Two.
Something's really wrong on Two.
Look at me.
It takes a week for one word
to get all the way up here.
You're panicking about something
that's happening
on the other side of the building!
You think they're listening?
Like you would know.
I know this.
They don't need to care.
All they need to do
is turn this floor on twice a day
and keep their numbers rolling.
I need a loan.
You have someone in mind.
It's not a long list.
And yet you're afraid to say who it is.
Davo Sculdun.
He is not a banker.
He's a thug.
Your breathing sounds weak.
The doctor was here yesterday.
You really don't know where he is?
New man on the floor!
Hold your positions!
I have a new idea.
Anto Kreegyr.
- I want you to meet him.
- Anto Kreegyr?
He's been probing
the Imperial power station at Spellhaus.
We've got a rebel pilot in custody.
One of Anto Kreegyr's group.
We don't think Kreegyr knows
he's gone missing yet.
What if we foul the ship?
Have the pilot found dead in the cockpit.
Make it so.
Top priority. Quickly and carefully.
We leave no trace.
- What, you can't save him?
- There's nothing to save.
He's had a massive stroke.
What happened down on Two?
A man who was just released on Four
ended up back on Two the next day.
Word got out on the floor,
and then they killed them all.
No one's getting out, are they?
Not now.
Not after this.
We need to go tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
- You heard me.
Go where?
Anywhere.
It has to be tomorrow.
- Tomorrow.
- We can't wait.
We'll never have a better chance.
- You sound insane.
- No, listen to me.
They don't have enough guards,
and they know it.
They're afraid. Right now, they're afraid.
Afraid? Afraid of what?
They just killed a hundred men
to keep them quiet.
- What would you call that?
- I'd call that power.
Power? Power doesn't panic.
Five thousand men are about to find out
they're never leaving here alive.
Don't you think
that worries them upstairs?
Whatever we're making here,
it's clearly something they need.
They can't afford to be surprised again.
There'll never be less guards
than tomorrow. You know that.
On-Program.
Everyday we wait, they get stronger.
- It might be wise to have a plan.
- We have a plan.
Oh, what? You and Birnok and Melshi?
You don't have time to be stupid!
Come on!
The plan works around
the new man coming down.
They'll replace Ulaf tomorrow.
That might not happen again
until it's too late.
I'd rather die trying to take them down
than die giving them what they want.
We won't have a better chance.
It has to be tomorrow.
Program.
Home Blue,
proceed directly to your cell.
Keef, where is he?
He's dead.
He didn't make it?
What happened?
He's dead. Can't you see that?
- Who was it?
- Ulaf, the old guy.
New man tomorrow.
What's going on?
Tell them.
Collapsed in the walk way.
- Tell them!
- Tell us what?
What happened?
A doctor came out.
He didn't do much, did he?
Kino?
We will have immediate
facility compliance
or we will begin activating floors
without warning.
Keef! Floor!
What's going on?
The doctor told us
what happened down on Two.
It's true, isn't it?
They fried the whole bridge.
It is worse than that.
- It's why.
- Louder.
He said they made a mistake,
and sent back a man
who'd just been released.
- They fried two shifts to keep it quiet.
- You heard him say this?
How would he know?
I don't believe it.
He's a doctor,
they would never tell...
No one is getting out!
It's true.
The rumors are true.
He said it's true.
They're not letting us go.
Ever.
We're gonna die here,
or in the next place.
So let's get out heads back in our cells,
and start figuring this out.
Kreegyr's men took the bait.
They're asking for a landing bay.
- They found it?
- They're towing it, sir.
"Pilot dead. Ship adrift.
"Port of origin unknown.
"Kafrene Rescue Salvage
reports unresponsive, GPE 7000.
"Operator appears to have frozen following
hydraulic failure on hyperspace re-entry."
It worked.
Now we hang back and wait.
- Suggestion, sir?
- Yes.
I don't think we should step away.
- Go on.
- We should do what we normally do.
Unidentified ship, dead pilot.
We'd want to take a look, wouldn't we?
Let's assume Kreegyr's watching.
The least suspicious thing to do
would be to take an interest.
That is exactly what we will do.
Listen up!
We are done with counting shifts.
There is only then and now.
There is only one way out.
Play it how you want.
But I'm gonna assume I'm already dead,
and take it from there.
There's no sense
in warning the night shift.
They'll hear about it
one way or another soon enough.
Let's make it look good.
New protocol announcement.
All sky bridge transfers will be On-Program
and silent until further notice.
Any shift not in full compliance
will be punished collectively.
On-Program now.
On-Program!
And turn.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
Doctor Mullmoy,
we're just not sure what to do.
She needs her meds, she knows it,
but we caught her hiding them now,
and when I asked her
what she thought she was up to
she said your pills put her off of food,
and she'd rather keep eating
than let you keep pretending.
Okay, where is she?
- It's over there.
- Got it. Thanks.
I was here once, 30 years ago.
I'd just left Chandrila,
and my boss at the time
thought I'd enjoy seeing it.
Has it changed much?
I can't tell.
Didn't pay enough attention.
Suppose I thought
I'd be coming back regularly.
It's State property.
The rules are strict on décor.
Our choices for change are limited.
It's a bit old, isn't it?
I like new.
I know it's tasteless and cliché,
but one of the indulgences of great wealth
is freedom from other people's opinions.
You've made your point.
Yes, everyone says you're very direct.
The Senator has many obligations,
she's learned to manage
her time accordingly.
I like when things are clear.
But then I always get to thinking,
what's around the corner?
Mmm, your curiosity
has clearly been profitable.
I've met your husband several times.
I'm sure.
I take it that's not a corner
we're turning in this conversation.
It is not.
Many cultures don't fully appreciate
the clarity of the Chandrilan marriage.
Even our own people are confused at times.
Boundaries can be liberating.
The old ways have value.
Good.
We understand each other.
So, searching for a more
fluid banking situation, are we?
We've discussed all this, Davo.
I'd like to hear her say it.
Yes.
We're exploring alternative
financing arrangements for our foundation.
As Tay has no doubt
already told you,
we've reached a scale in our holdings
that permits
a great variety of transactions
to be bundled in ways
that make outside observation impossible.
Yes, I've been informed.
What's unfortunate
is that people such as yourself,
those with immaculate reputations,
sometimes feel that by taking advantage
of the opportunity
they're somehow tarnished.
The money is yours.
Family wealth is a thing to be proud of
and you ought to be able to move it
as you like with your privacy intact.
The Empire's new regulations, made without
Senate consultation, I might add,
are as cumbersome as they are avoidable.
They've made a game of it and we play.
This is a charitable fund
we're establishing.
So I've been told.
- What will it cost?
- My fee?
We assume it's a percentage
of funds transferred.
I want no fee.
Money means very little to me
at this point.
Charity, isn't it?
- I insist.
- And I refuse.
Please take no offense,
I'd prefer not to owe any favors.
I'd feel far more comfortable
paying you for your trouble.
A drop of discomfort
may be the price of doing business.
Let's have it.
I'd like a return invitation.
I'd like to come back here at least once.
I'm sure that's something
that can be arranged.
I have a 14-year-old son.
I'd like to bring him with me.
You can't be serious.
- I'm not asking for betrothal.
- Then what are we talking about?
An introduction.
Your daughter is 13.
She'll soon come of age.
Two young people.
Attractive and privileged
Chandrilan citizens.
What makes you think
I approve of that tradition?
Our position sometimes makes decisions
for us, don't you find, Senator?
Neither of us have lived a life
that encourages nonconformity.
Is that your only offer?
I'm afraid so.
Tay will see you out.
Of course.
- It's a lot to think about.
- I'm not thinking about it.
That's the first untrue thing you've said.
It's been a pleasure.
There was a mark on the fountain.
Could be anything.
That's what I thought,
so I went to the stairs.
The rail was gone.
A clean break. Fresh.
He wants a meeting, face to face.
There goes the day.
I don't like it.
Not now, I don't like the timing.
You don't like anything.
At the very least
you need to let me go.
Take the Fondor, go to safety
and I'll take care of it.
You know that's not happening.
Stop wasting time.
It's been a year.
I'm surprised he waited this long.
Then if it's a trap?
Oh, if it's a trap, we've already lost.
Hands away.
Are we really doing this?
- You're still on board?
- I want out. Don't care how.
I'm dead. I'm dead.
- Hey, hey, hey!
- I'm pretending to be dead.
Don't die until you put up a fight.
One way out.
Come on!
Keep it moving!
Pick it up.
Right now, I'm two racks behind!
And we are not
gonna close out the shift like that!
Stop right there.
On-Program. Hands on your head.
Eyes front. Feet down.
Keep it moving!
Come on, come on.
Come on!
Step forward, move, stop there.
Zap-rod.
If I have to use this,
you'll remember it, yes? Yes?
We owe a check on Three.
- Do that now.
- We're already behind.
- Stepping off.
- You're good.
I said eyes front.
Where is he?
- Are they even watching?
- Calm down.
- How?
- I thought you were dead already.
New man ready on 5-2-D,
requesting unit override.
How's it looking out there?
Copy that, coming up.
Looks good.
Okay, go.
Oh, no.
On-Program.
New man on the floor.
Everyone hold positions.
New man on the floor!
Hold your positions!
Lift engaged.
- What'd you say to me?
- I said nothing.
If you wanna say something,
you should say it now.
You start...
Hey! You lot, back on program!
You lot, back on program!
Get back on program!
Whoa, what's going on? What's that?
Now!
What's going on out there?
Go! Go!
- Clear the target.
- What are you doing?
- Come on! Help them!
- Let's go!
Attack!
Spark the floor! Spark the floor!
Get on the tables!
Get on the tables! Get up on the tables!
Spark the floor!
Talk to me!
Right, are you all right?
- You all right? You good?
- I'm okay.
Attack!
We have a situation on 5-2-D.
Repeat, we have a situation...
No! Xaul!
Come on!
Hey!
They're down!
Come on! Climb!
We're in!
Right.
Gimme a hand.
That's it. Go.
Got it.
- Hey, did you see that?
- Yeah, hold up.
What's that?
Where's that coming from?
Hand it off.
Move!
- Kino, come on!
- We need to hold the level!
- Let someone else do that.
- Go! Go!
Blow the consoles!
Keep the doors open!
- What's going on down there?
- I'm not sure, Sir...
I'm looking at a water break.
I've got service warnings on every panel.
Get over there
and check it out. Now.
Check out 5-2-D. Now!
Let's go. Okay.
Go, go.
- Jemboc!
- Taga, come on, let's go!
Let's go!
Let's go. Fall in. Come on.
Go! Go! Go!
One way out!
Come and fight!
What?
Come on.
- Ah!
- We're leaving! Join us!
Climb! Use whatever you can!
Go!
This is a facility-wide
emergency announcement.
Complete program protocol
will commence in 40 seconds.
Any deviation or failure to comply
will result in unit-wide activation.
- Start the count.
- Count engaged.
How much longer
to find the water break?
Techs waiting for a secure floor.
Isolate Five.
Locked in.
5-5, 5-3, 5-6. Burn a firewall around it.
Fry the whole Level.
Make the epicenter 5-2.
Too late.
- There's nobody there.
- You shouldn't be here.
- Turn it off.
- Excuse me?
Turn it off!
That could mean so many things.
I... I'll turn it off.
Step away.
Now!
- Shut down the floors. Everywhere.
- Do it.
No.
Don't just turn it off.
Cut the power.
It's all hydro.
Once we turn it off it takes months
to get it back up and running ag...
I don't have it.
He has the Hydro Gens.
That's the backup power supply.
Get out of there.
There.
With him.
Move!
On-Program! Now!
All yours.
Kino.
Tell them what to do.
It has to be you.
Come on, Kino.
You do this every day.
Tell them what to do.
My name is Kino Loy.
I'm the day shift manager on Level Five.
I'm speaking to you
from the command center on Level Eight.
We are, at this moment,
in control of the facility.
Is that the best you got?
How long we hang on, how far we get,
how many of us make it out,
all of that is now up to us.
We have deactivated
every floor in the facility.
All floors are cold.
Wherever you are right now,
get up, stop the work.
Get out of your cells,
take charge and start climbing.
They don't have enough guards
and they know it.
If we wait until they figure that out,
it'll be too late.
We will never have
a better chance than this
and "I would rather die
trying to take them down
"than giving them what they want."
We know they fried
a hundred men on Level Two.
We know that they are making up
our sentences as we go along.
We know that no one outside here
knows what's happening.
And now we know,
that when they say we are being released,
we are being transferred
to some other prison
to go and die and that ends today!
There is one way out.
Right now, the building is ours.
You need to run, climb, kill!
You need to help each other.
You see someone who's confused,
someone who is lost,
you get them moving
and you keep them moving
until we put this place behind us.
There are 5,000 of us.
If we can fight half as hard
as we've been working,
we will be home in no time.
One way out!
- One way out!
- One way out! One way out!
One way out!
One way out! One way out...
Come on!
Let's get out of here!
Quiet.
One way out!
Whatever happens now, we made it!
What's wrong?
Can't swim.
- What?
- What did he say?
I can't swim!
If this is a trap,
press the buttons for 215.
We'll have privacy.
We're running express.
First of all, congratulations.
- On what?
- Your daughter.
Healthy. Beautiful. You must be pleased.
Is that meant to scare me?
Well, it's been a year
since we've had a chance to catch up.
You've become a father.
- It's not worth mentioning?
- It's not fair.
You knowing.
Watching me.
Do you ever think
how it might feel from my side?
I think about you constantly.
Why are we here tonight, Lonni?
There's a new supervisor rising.
Dedra Meero.
She's focused
on a suspect she's calling Axis.
She thinks he's building a rebel network.
She started looking
into stolen Imperial Naval equipment
and now she's looking
for a link to Aldhani.
Dedra Meero.
There was an incident on Ferrix
a few months ago.
She thinks there's a link.
She's been tearing the place apart.
They're searching
for a thief and the middleman.
Huh. "Axis."
She's gathering interest.
Partagaz likes her.
Well, this is good.
Encourage this.
Why is this good?
Because she's wasting time.
You had nothing to do with Aldhani?
Well, almost nothing.
We were invited, but declined.
They got lucky. We don't build on luck.
But this can't be why you're here.
She just captured a Rebel pilot
running supplies for Anto Kreegyr.
They turned him immediately
and staged an accident.
We know that there's a raid planned
on the power station at Spellhaus.
If Kreegyr attacks, they'll be waiting.
And if he doesn't,
they'll know something's amiss.
They'll be slaughtered.
It's 50 men.
- You're worth more than that.
- You have to warn them.
To what end?
Ruin everything?
What better way to reassure the ISB
there's no leak in security
than sacrificing Kreegyr.
I'm doing this for you
as much as anything.
Tell me
why we're really here today, Lonni?
I can't do this anymore.
I'm a father now.
I had no idea how it would feel.
We took a vow.
I'm giving you Dedra Meero.
I'm giving you Spellhaus.
I'm warning you about Ferrix.
I'm honoring my vow.
I've been working my way
through there for six years.
Working my way up.
Alone.
So, what was your plan?
Gather a big basket of goodies for me
as a farewell gift?
What were you planning to tell the ISB?
My health.
My wife's family has an import business.
Even as you say the words,
you know it's impossible.
We can't let you go, Lonni.
We can't spare you.
We've been grooming you for too long.
And yes, you've been alone,
but your career has profited greatly
from information that we've provided.
Information that cost me dearly.
You love your daughter.
Kreegyr's men will be dying
to make sure she has a father.
You're trapped, Lonni.
There's no pleasure in saying it
but you're going nowhere.
My sacrifice?
It means nothing to you, does it?
I said I think of you constantly and I do.
Your investment in the Rebellion is epic.
A double life? Every day a performance?
The stress of that?
We need heroes, Lonni, and here you are.
And what do you sacrifice?
Calm.
Kindness. Kinship.
Love.
I've given up all chance at inner peace.
I've made my mind a sunless space.
I share my dreams with ghosts.
I wake up every day
to an equation I wrote 15 years ago
from which there's only one conclusion,
I'm damned for what I do.
My anger, my ego,
my unwillingness to yield,
my eagerness to fight,
they've set me on a path
from which there is no escape.
I yearned to be a savior against injustice
without contemplating the cost
and by the time I looked down
there was no longer
any ground beneath my feet.
What is my sacrifice?
I'm condemned to use
the tools of my enemy to defeat them.
I burn my decency
for someone else's future.
I burn my life to make a sunrise
that I know I'll never see.
And the ego that started this fight
will never have a mirror
or an audience or the light of gratitude.
So what do I sacrifice?
Everything!
You'll stay with me, Lonni.
I need all the heroes I can get.