You need a radical
insurgency you can count on.
You need ghorman rebels you
can depend on to do the wrong thing.
We're safe here.
Then why are we being so paranoid?
- Just trying to protect us.
- You mean me?
You're being cast aside.
You're being discarded
and too naive to see it.
I'm in charge here, mother.
This is the bureau of
standards field office in ghorman.
You were here. I'd fixed
it. You'd made it back.
You'd found a woman actually
willing to make a life with you,
and you just walk away?
Such a pleasure to finally meet you.
Finally indeed.
- I'm not buying another spider.
- This one's free.
You're right. You're not a tourist.
Perhaps you wish to know
more about where you live.
They made contact. I've
been invited to a meeting.
- A meeting with who?
- I don't know.
It's public. It's a town hall.
But this is them. It's
ghorman front. I know it.
Mark my words!
We're drowning in rumors.
Many people are starting to think
this new building is
more than just an annex.
I'm not sure why the empire would
build an armory in the middle of palmo,
but I'm running out of answers.
Carro rylanz. He's
running the ghorman front.
I need an assessment.
I'm not sure about the group.
And bix?
No. You'd have to go alone.
Think of it, comrades. Fuel on demand.
All the rhydo that you can steal.
Not many old pipe-poachers out there.
Not many who've lived to tell the tale.
Which variation?
You'll teach them all.
But I need to leave tomorrow.
There was an agreement.
This was negotiated.
You're here till I get what I need.
Ryloth 7-4-8.
Maybe you'll find a husband and I'll.
I basically hold him in that room
and say, "all right. Stay there."
"Stay In that corner forever." Yeah?
Corell ia 2-2-2.
Ryloth 7-4-8.
I feel like ever since we moved in here...
Really uncomfortable, if I grabbed...
Sculdun 3-4-3.
- We're not to be interrupted.
- Yes, sir.
Well?
It's a forgery.
- It's a good one, but...
- It should be.
It certainly cost enough.
I won't tell you what I paid for it.
Unfortunately, the
dealer... you're up early.
Anything urgent?
Not yet.
And our friend's on his way?
Stop.
Someone here!
Can I help you?
Ghorman?
Visiting friends?
Why do you ask?
I'm curious by nature.
I have friends everywhere.
Bon!
What do we have for ghorman?
Your name is varian Skye.
You were born in tahini
and moved to Coruscant with
your brother when you were 12.
Your brother, patrio,
soon returned home,
but you'd found an apprenticeship
in a dressmaking studio
and decided to stay.
After your apprenticeship,
you moved to the fashion district
where you found work as
an assistant to a designer.
Just wanted to let you know
I'm coming home this weekend.
What a pleasant surprise!
I'm just worried if I don't
come now, it might be a while.
There's a rumor they might be
tightening up the travel restrictions here.
I thought you were in charge.
This is hardly a bureau
of standards issue.
I hope someone who knows
what they're doing is watching out.
For what?
Your safety.
Well, they're definitely watching out.
What they're looking for is a mystery.
There's not much in
the way of danger here.
- When would you arrive?
- Hang on.
- I gotta go, mother, I'll let you know.
- Wait
listen up!
I need everybody to step
away from their workstations
and leave the room immediately.
What's going on here?
They're telling us all to leave.
No, stay where you are.
Syril karn?
Yes?
I'm attendant grymish from isb tech.
We have reason to believe there
are listening devices in this office.
- Excuse me?
- You heard me.
We need everyone out immediately.
I'm afraid you'll have to wait.
We're in the middle of an audit.
What you're in the middle
of, sir, is an isb tech sweep.
Everyone in here will be in
custody until we finish our evaluation.
What do you mean "custody?"
On whose authority? This is my office.
Are you refusing a direct imperial order?
This is insane.
Take him.
Are you... come...
everybody... everybody out!
- Calling headquarters!
- Yeah, good luck with that.
Anyone else wanna argue?
Sculdun 3-4-3.
- We're not to be interrupted.
- Yes, sir.
Well?
It's a forgery.
It's a good one, but
it should be. It certainly cost enough.
I won't tell you what I paid for it.
Unfortunately, the dealer
I bought it from is dead.
He's lucky he's dead.
Well, he may have been
fooled as much as we were.
As of this moment, everything
in the room is under suspicion.
What else have we missed?
Even the finest collections
have problems now and then.
One problem is too many. I want
everything vetted once and for all.
- Everything?
- Everything!
- We have the exhibition...
- all of it!
- I want it inspected and re-certified.
- Everything!
You... get...
This is your first trip to ghorman.
As a fashion designer,
it's a rite of passage.
You've lived in the same
place for the last five years.
51457, level 4888,
east narcene, Coruscant.
It's a small unit, but it's
above your design studio
where you do most of your work.
There was a...
Listening device...
In my office.
How long it's been there, or if
it's even operational are unknown.
You will all now have the
pleasure of thorough isb interview,
and there will be new security
measures going forward.
Because, of course...
We're bugging our own office!
Hello.
- We were worried.
- You seem upset.
We saw isb come into the building.
Yes. Yes, I am... upset.
They tore my office apart.
I was interrogated for
two hours like a criminal.
For coming to the meeting?
No... no, no. It's nothing
to do with that. They were...
They were looking
for a listening device...
Which, of course, I either
condoned or ignored,
or put in myself for some reason.
Or else the whole thing was a
ruse for them to put something in.
I don't know. They...
They do what they want.
- Without explanation?
- It's the isb.
They have their own
rules. No one else matters.
A lesson for all of us.
It's humiliating.
I take my work seriously.
It's outrageous.
Many of us believe the emperor has
no idea what's being done on his behalf.
We think the isb is running
a shadow government.
To be honest, nothing would
surprise me at this point.
And believe me, you
don't know the half of it.
What if we could help the
empire by working together?
How would we do that?
We need to know
what's on those carriers.
You know who we are and
you see what's happening here.
We need to know what kind of facility
it is before things get out of hand.
I told you. I don't have plans.
We want to focus on deliveries.
We need to know what's
on those transports, syril.
It's... construction material.
That's what comes across my desk.
- And the rest of it?
- Not every transport has a bill of lading.
Those are the ones we'd be interested in.
No.
No, no. Not that.
He's fine. He'll be home soon enough.
I came to see about you.
Here I am.
This old place.
Not many safe houses have a view.
- You want a drink?
- No, I can't stay that long.
This isn't fun, is it?
The nights are fun.
I've slept here twice.
Not in a very long time, but... For fun?
No. False alarm.
Never ends, does it?
All the hiding.
It will. We'll bring them
down, or die trying.
What else is there?
I'm not as strong as you.
That's just tonight talking.
That's being stuck here in this box.
Or maybe you're not as strong as I think.
Maybe not.
I'll try to find someplace else
for you to stay. I'll have a look.
I'm not loving Coruscant.
It's overwhelming. I know you...
You've been struggling.
Is that what he told you?
I'm better than he thinks I am.
All he does is sing your praises.
We need you, bix. We need you healthy.
You came here to offer me something.
You wanted something.
And you changed your mind.
Not lost your eye, have you? It
was just another weapons appraisal.
I have alternatives. We'll
find something more exciting.
You should rest. You should
be here when he gets back.
Give it.
I use it for sleep.
It works for a while.
But the dreams come
back worse when you stop.
Be careful.
You need me healthy.
Yeah.
Variation five... So that's thirds...
Watch the line.
Take your time.
Be sure.
Careful.
One to the right.
And we're all dead.
We're doing station five, right?
Well, if you close the pipe completely,
- it'll spark when it comes back on.
- I knew that. I knew that. I'm an idiot.
It's right here.
Well, it's a lot to take in.
It doesn't seem to bother you.
Eight variations. Saw thinks there's
eight things I have to remember.
He doesn't realize all the primes,
all the sifting factors, the tools...
How did you ever learn
this? Who taught you?
No more questions. Sorry.
I can't leave until you get this.
Come on.
Mid sift, variation two.
- What time's your flight?
- I'll make it.
I'm just backing up all
our transport schedules.
I'd hate to think what would happen
if those isb idiots hit the wrong button.
- We can do that for you.
- Just get the audit back on track.
Make sure to lock up tight.
I don't want any more security questions.
Yes, sir.
Traveling, are we?
Something to take home?
Yeah, I'll take one for my mother.
Well, you'll want a good one.
We're fine. Nobody's watching.
Man of taste. Best spider
on the Plaza. Come back safe.
Thank you.
Yes...
We were wondering if we should offer it
up to sculdun as a gift for the exhibition.
It's short notice but
if there was interest,
we might find time for
an immediate installation.
It's remarkable, yes,
but, um, between us? I wouldn't do it.
There's been some question about
the provenance of a certain piece
nothing to do with luthen,
but sculdun is in a rage about it
and they are taking
everything out of there
the day after the party for re-appraisal.
"Military security required."
Thank you.
Checking in?
Varian Skye.
Holo-screen, air flow and window blinds,
they all work through the
single console on the nightstand.
Is that where it happened?
The monument?
It is.
Really?
Wow. Right there.
Some people don't think it's a good idea
to commemorate a
massacre in the center of town.
- Is that you?
- Do I mind?
Yeah.
No. Doesn't matter to me.
I'm sure you have an opinion.
I needn't be reminded. I was there.
How old were you?
Twelve.
Grand moff tarkin, right?
Will there be anything else, sir?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Didn't mean to make you uncomfortable.
Here, thank you.
We've been asked not
to speak of it with guests.
I'm just a designer.
I'm curious.
I've been hearing about
ghorman my whole life.
It was moff tarkin.
People wouldn't clear
and he wanted to land...
And more of us kept coming.
We thought there
was safety in numbers.
Who would land a cruiser on a crowd
full of unarmed citizens?
I was with my father.
He was killed saving me.
Sorry to hear that.
Haven't gone very far, have I?
My wife thinks it's insane we stay here.
Do let me know if there's
anything else you might need.
Hey.
Thank you.
It's good to meet you.
I was safe.
I was careful all the way.
I know. I had you followed.
Partagaz insisted.
- How long can I stay?
- An hour.
Are you kidding?
Do you think they're really
watching eedy's apartment?
No. But we've put too much in now
to have it go wrong
for something so small.
An hour.
Turn out the lights.
Can't believe you had me followed.
Varian Skye?
Yes.
- Enza. The house of rylanz.
- Enza!
You've just arrived.
Yeah. Yeah.
Already out and about? How intrepid.
And you... how observant.
Well, the times demand
it, don't you think?
I was planning to make
an appointment tomorrow
and here you are.
- May I?
- Yes, please.
How timely.
You're a designer?
Trying.
This cafe used to be full of designers...
And weavers and buyers.
People fought for tables.
Look at us now.
Is your hotel even half full?
I just checked in.
I happen to know it's not.
What is it you think you're doing?
You don't know me.
Let's start over.
My friend suggested I meet your father.
Your friend might have come himself.
Unless, I'm the friend, right?
Or maybe I'm a snitch,
and you're my payday.
Maybe I'm isb.
Maybe you just put everyone
you care about into a cell.
I am who you want me to be,
but that's just you getting lucky.
People die rushing.
You have no idea who I am.
You need to be more careful.
It's hard to be patient when
your world is falling apart.
My father's very proud.
And I can't wait to meet him.
I need fabric.
When is a good time for me to
come by the showroom tomorrow?
I'll, send word in the morning.
Thanks for stopping by.
Hey, the people you have following
me, they're just drawing attention.
Send them home.
Nice to meet you.
Open.
Does it have a name?
It's your spider.
Perhaps I'll call it "syril."
That's an interesting choice.
What a comfort that will be.
The silence.
The brooding.
The disregard for common sense.
Be almost like having you here.
Welcome back to good
morning, Coruscant!
It's that time of the year, toffi!
Senate investiture. I
absolutely adore this holiday.
I know you wanna talk
about the politics of it all.
- I do.
- I want to talk parties.
- Political parties?
- No!
It's vesty week!
I wanna know who's
going where with who.
I wanna talk clothes. I wanna
know where you've been invited.
You are the one on
everybody's gala guest list.
And the must-have accessories!
Why don't you tell everyone
where you're going on the big night?
Come on, you know I don't
pick favorites. The imperial ball.
- Toffi!
- Well, it's true.
That's why you, dear viewers,
will be getting the inside story
from the hottest ticket in town.
Don't say she doesn't give you anything.
The time of selflessness.
Welcome to the house of rylanz.
My pleasure.
- Thank you.
- Welcome.
Please.
Varian Skye.
Carro rylanz. Welcome to ghorman.
I've waited far too long in
coming. Your showroom is fantastic.
Nineteen generations.
One of the youngest twilleries in palmo.
Amazing. Amazing.
Our webberie estates are quite far away,
but they are certainly worth
a visit if you find the time.
Can I show you?
I've been told about your
conversation last night.
Apparently, we have a lot to learn.
Is it safe to talk in here?
We sweep for listening devices daily.
That must draw attention.
Every twillery on the Plaza does
the same. It's a competitive market.
There was a rebel pilot
trapped in the mountains.
We saved him.
You were given a special radio.
The person that sent
you is but a voice to me.
We've spoken, we've
exchanged messages,
but I have no idea, really,
who's at the other end of the line.
That won't change. But
it's for everyone's benefit.
I do have this.
It's a fresh code-crystal for the radio.
It's one-of-a-kind.
It will only fit the
transmitter you were given.
I offer that as a bond.
The new imperial
building. You've seen it?
Well, it's hard to miss.
- They're building an armory.
- In the center of town?
We don't know why. They deny it.
It's in violation of the imperial charter.
We've had sightings. We've slipped
people into some of the work crews,
but we were unsure until now.
I'm only meeting you because we
find ourselves with a unique opportunity.
We have a source inside.
- An imperial source?
- I'll not say.
Feeding false
information is what they do.
You're aware of that?
They're... they're pretty good at it.
The information is reliable.
Shipments come by
cargo-carrier from the south depot
at night through the city.
We've been tracking
the routes and schedules.
Now we know which transports to target.
The ones you think have weapons.
We know what they are
doing. Now we need proof.
What do you mean by "target"?
Take it. Take it down.
We need to catch them in their lie.
We need to let the people of
ghorman know the undeniable truth.
What about the weapons?
We start our own armory.
Ever done anything like this before?
Steal?
It's a military transport.
It won't be easy.
Quiet, both of you.
Tactical expertise is not our strong suit.
We need an advisor.
I'm gonna need some
swatches sent over.
You're gonna want to check the radio.
And, if everything is fine,
I would love to get a
tour of palmo by night.
- You can call for me at the hotel.
- As you wish.
Thank you.
You're convinced we're connecting
to the ghorman front leadership?
I am, sir.
Carro rylanz is a prominent
businessman and politician in palmo.
I've been dealing with him directly.
And we're sure they're buying this story?
We're skeptically confident, sir.
Words to live by.
I think they're planning already.
They're inexperienced but very eager.
How often those attributes align.
They'll need help, sir.
The plan... your plan to bait
ghorman as a prize for outside agitators
needs to begin somewhere.
This could be that moment.
How may we assist?
Transport schedules
need to remain consistent.
The information I pass
them needs to be accurate.
I'll need oversight on military security.
- Done.
- If they pull it off,
when it's over, we need to
calibrate retribution carefully.
We want them growing bolder.
They need to see what winning feels like.
I'll make sure things
don't get out of hand.
Excellent work, syril.
Thank you, sir.
We'll keep you briefed.
If I say this is the
greatest day of my life...
Does it spoil everything?
It's good to see you happy.
I know all the variations, in
theory. I just need more practice.
So we can lose the boy?
He's seen too much.
If you're ready, then I'll get rid of him.
He's a good engineer.
A great one, maybe.
- But we have you!
- What about the people who sent him?
Accidents happen.
I was hoping he could come along.
You lack confidence, pluti.
Until you tell me the station we're
hitting, this is gonna be on edge.
The number of variations I'm
carrying right now is driving me crazy.
If I could focus on one
single variation, one,
I'd have the confidence
you're looking for.
Markez moon. Neen valley.
Station four junction.
We leave tomorrow night.
Tubes has all of the pipe numbers.
Thank you.
Wilmon?
We'll keep him for now.
The tinian codex in
sculdun's office collection.
What about it?
What have you heard?
I need some good news.
You'll have to wait on that.
There's another piece.
The coryio chalice.
Apparently, it's a forgery.
They're going to examine
everything in the collection.
They'll find our microphone.
You heard this on the bug?
They're taking everything
out the day after the party.
They never send more
than three at a time.
The ones we're interested
in always travel alone.
Thirty meters down, we
have a transport waiting.
We slide the cargo to
the bottom and disappear.
- Let's keep making avoidable mistakes.
- Let's keep overreacting.
I wouldn't be so upset
if I hadn't predicted it!
This solves nothing.
- And for what? What have we ever heard?
- Are you done?
"Let's put a bug in davo sculdun's
office that leads directly back to us."
It didn't seem to bother you
when we caught yularen lying.
- Seriously.
- The holo-news buyout.
Sculdun courting the grand vizier!
Bits and pieces. That's all we ever got.
- Two years of bits and pieces!
- You agreed to it!
- I let you talk me into it!
- You're becoming insufferable!
I can't keep track anymore!
All these lines we've
laid. All this information.
The radios, the frequencies,
the messages flying around!
We're drowning.
And you keep pretending
it's all under control.
Are you done?
We have to take it out at the party.
And if we can't?
We should be prepared.
- Is he ready?
- Yes.
Ready enough to do it on
his own? No help from you?
I think so.
You think
or you know?
It's "neither." I've done what I can.
I've done everything you've asked for.
And if I don't show up back home, there
traitor!
- What happened?
- He's a traitor.
Show them!
He's been transmitting to the empire.
What?
There's an ambush waiting for
us at the markez moon pipeline.
But we... We will be many parsecs away
drinking our rhydo in peace.
Move quickly, comrades.
Whatever you don't take, we burn.
We will not be back this way again.
It's on you, boy.
So...
Are you running away or
running to find us reinforcements?
That won't be up to me.
Surely you have an opinion.
Hijacking the carrier?
Yes, can be done.
But can you and your people do it alone?
I don't think so.
How much help do we need?
It's not stealing things that's difficult.
It's getting away.
But you won't be doing that.
You'll be living at the scene of the crime.
Worse than that... You're planning
to advertise what you've done.
So then what?
Let it continue?
Let them build what they want?
Let them persecute us for no reason
and tighten the noose
every time we cry out?
Is that what you suggest?
Is that truly your recommendation?
I have more questions
than recommendations.
Not much of a revolutionary, are you?
Perhaps not.
Good day to you.
And tell your friend I'm not impressed.
I was younger than you are now.
I was a prisoner.
They made a work camp in the jungle.
No droids, no beasts,
just men and cargo.
Onderon jungle.
Real jungle.
Hot, wet, blistering jungle.
Old men died fast.
Just dropped where they stood.
We came back the next day,
there'd be nothing but a bone
or two where they went down.
Our clothes, just... just melted away.
So they worked us naked.
Two, three hundred men.
Boys, really.
Back and forth until the only thing
you could remember was back and forth.
Then one day, everyone started to itch.
Everyone, all at once.
Even the guards.
You could feel your skin coming alive.
It was the rhydo.
They had a leak.
You could feel it
before you could smell it.
So they all panicked and ran away...
But it was new to me.
It's done.
I'm gonna open the valve now.
I have always loved you.
What are you doing?
- There it is.
- How can you do that?
Because I understand it.
Because she's my sister
rhydo, and she loves me!
That itch, that burn...
You feel how badly
she wants to explode?
Remember this.
Remember this moment!
This perfect night.
You think I'm crazy?
Yes, I am.
Revolution is not for the sane.
Look at us.
Unloved.
Hunted.
Cannon fodder.
We'll all be dead before
the republic is back
and yet... here we are.
Where are you, boy?
You're here! You're not
with luthen. You're here!
You're right here, and
you're ready to fight!
We're the rhydo, kid. We're the fuel.
We're the thing that explodes when
there's too much friction in the air.
Let it in, boy! That's freedom calling!
Let it in. Let it run!
Let it run wild!