Revolution is not for the sane.
And yet... here we are.
Where are you, boy?
You're here! You're not
with luthen. You're here!
You're right here, and
you're ready to fight!
Spiders are not the most
unique thing in ghorman.
There's a mineral underground. Doctor!
Deep substrate foliated kalkite.
Should we fail to find any alternatives,
we will have to control
ghorman with a hand firm enough
to silence any resistance.
Grand moff tarkin killed 500
peaceful, unarmed ghormans
in the middle of that Plaza.
You can imagine how
upset we would be to find out
there's an imperial military facility
rising over the monument to the fallen.
Is that where it happened?
I was with my father.
He was killed saving me.
I can't support the bill because
I can't risk chafing the emperor.
Why ghorman is being
persecuted so intently
are questions no one
seems prepared to answer.
Hasn't there always been something
slightly arrogant about the ghor?
With the right ideas planted in the
right markets in the right sequence,
we can now weaponize
this galactic opinion.
Propaganda will only get you so far.
You need a radical
insurgency you can count on.
You need ghorman rebels you
can depend on to do the wrong thing.
Luthen should have told
me you were in trouble.
We're worth more to him
separately than together.
Well, that's something we'll
have to talk to him about.
- Jacquème! Jacquème!
- Lo stique sassor!
Nache mik balor! Sim ro nache telpó!
I'm not loving Coruscant.
It's overwhelming, I know you...
You've been struggling.
You come to the house
and you mess with bix?
You mess with her behind my back?
You realize what you're
putting at risk right now?
- I give you everything.
- This is everything?
Violating every protocol we live by?
Bix has to pull it together.
Or you Will have to decide at what
point it becomes too large a problem.
Whatever the mission is, I'm coming.
Shadow-six, you are
clear for open pad one.
Go for tower, 0-1-1.
Listen up! New rules!
No vouchers, no food, no rack until
you check in with your duty officer.
You'll find your duty officer
listed on the health certificate
waiting for you in the clinic
following your medical approval.
Stay to the group and
mind the freight paths.
Take your shirt off.
And don't tell me it's better.
- Turn around.
- I'm gonna be late.
What's more important?
Easy. Easy.
That was easy.
- Pick another spot.
- Just relax.
Yeah? What are you gonna do?
Anything I want.
Hey.
Look at this.
- I can come back.
- Don't you dare.
I was about to send a search party.
- Hey.
- When did you get back?
- Just now.
- Where have you been?
- I was on a repair.
It took a while getting back.
- You check in?
- Not yet.
Things are getting really
organized around here.
Tell me about it.
- Here.
- That's all right. I've got it. Thanks.
Back from where?
- Here and there.
- This is here.
I'm asking you where you were.
He just got in.
She's been more worried
about you than I have.
Thanks.
Where were you?
Luthen wants to know
if you're ready to work.
Ready for what?
He knows you were hurt.
If he does, it's because you told him.
He's been trying to reach you.
Ready for what?
He just wants to know
if he can count on you.
- Well, he's not making it easy.
- Whose fault is that?
You trust this place? All these people?
New faces every day?
We need an army.
Everything's a risk.
All we do here is get ready.
Luthen is making things happen.
Is he?
What do you want, wil?
You wanna fight?
Or you wanna win?
Going it alone doesn't cut it anymore.
Well, maybe you should tell him yourself.
Maybe you should tell
us where you've been.
The continued and
inexplicable ghorman resistance
to imperial norms.
Terrorism strikes again in ghorman.
Just three weeks after
events in corei and jel-novi,
there was a firebombing last
night at the naval terminal in palmo.
You can see, behind me,
vapor and thermal smoke
still rising from the site...
The number of imperial
casualties is still unknown.
Admiral tyzen is expected
to comment later today,
but we've already seen
an escalated response level.
Curfew was reinstated for the entire city.
Local leaders are urging calm,
and so far, there's been no
statement, or claim of credit,
from any local terrorist groups.
You can feel this city,
which was already on edge these
past few months, tightening up...
Ghorman? For luthen?
All these side runs. That's
what you've been doing?
It's being destroyed.
He must be thrilled.
He's wanted it long enough.
Dragging you out there? For what?
Help him torch the place?
It's not like that.
Not now.
It's the empire with the
torches. They've gone insane.
So?
What does he need me for?
Her.
Isb supervisor, dedra meero.
She destroyed ferrix.
She killed my father.
You know her.
She's there in ghorman.
In the open, I've seen her.
She's there now, and she's
there waiting to be killed,
and I know you're gonna
say it's for revenge, but it's not.
She's been coming
for luthen since ferrix.
She's been coming after him,
and you, and all of us,
and everyone we know.
She's just sitting there, cass.
She keeps winning.
You know she has to be stopped!
I'm late for my briefing.
You need to calm down, and check in.
You act like luthen's the enemy.
That would be easier.
She's a monster.
We won't have a better chance.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
The emperor has taken a
great interest in the situation.
Director krennic's still with him now,
but they wanted me to pass along the
affirmative message to you immediately.
We are moving forward
with the original plan.
There is, apparently,
no suitable replacement
or synthetic alternative for
the ghorman substrate material.
I see.
It's not for lack of effort.
Krennic's had the lab in
eadu working overtime all year.
I don't know the science, but...
It's bad luck ghorman.
We need what's in the
ground, and when we're done,
there won't be much left to call "home."
When?
The fleet will be fully
positioned in 48 hours.
They're fiddling with the calendar,
but to commence a
full-enforced resettlement
that fits krennic's schedule,
we'll need a declaration of
martial domain as soon as possible.
Where is she?
She's unavailable at the moment.
I asked you "where?"
Captain kaido is arriving today.
- He's here.
- He's outside my office. Who is he?
He is a crisis specialist.
He'll be bringing a variety of
personnel to help manage the situation.
We have plenty of security.
What I need now is
some clarity on how exactly
dedra. Calmly.
Let the image of professional
ascendance settle your nerves.
A successful conclusion to this problem
will reinforce the isb's
position at the emperor's side.
You've done excellent
work bringing this forward.
Everyone that matters knows
how well you've played this.
Captain kaido knows the objective.
He will answer to you operationally.
The tactical details, however,
will be at his discretion.
You're aware, sir, that the
insurgents have weapons at this point.
We're counting on it.
Bombing at the naval depot?
I can't even get in there.
It's being investigated.
The rumor is it's a set-up.
They're running it down.
Who? And who's this tactical
guy in your control room?
There's evidence of outside agitators.
You serious?
That's what I came here for.
That is what I've been
trying to do since I got here.
That is what you told me
you wanted, and now...
Now there's evidence I have to beg for?
We are trying to prevent an incident.
By keeping me in the dark.
My sources say this is nonsense.
- Stop.
- What am I doing here?
Syril, please.
You need to go home and pack
and be ready to leave when I tell you.
What?
Good things are waiting for us.
We'll be out of here soon.
We'll be back in
Coruscant. We'll be together.
We'll be rewarded.
For what? What have we accomplished?
Be careful.
Me?
Do what I told you.
Thank you, kloris.
Are you planning to
go to the office today?
Eventually. It's lovely
out. I'm sure we'll walk.
It's just, they're asking
for schedules this week.
Parking and movement.
Who's asking?
Senate security.
Ridiculous.
I'll speak to them. Thank you.
I'm requesting a new driver.
Don't. They might send someone smart.
We lead from ghorman
again this morning
with reports of another
terrorist attack overnight
as a series of explosions
rocked the naval terminal in palmo.
Perhaps as many as three,
rising over the imperial
naval terminal, where...
With ghorman already under
curfew and increased security,
this represents a turning
point in the terror campaign
that's been escalating for the past year.
Freezing ghorman assets galaxy-wide
and calling for an immediate and
complete blockade of material assistance
until the incident can be fully explained
and the terrorists have
been brought to justice.
Senator mothma.
Apologies. I've been awaiting your arrival.
A word, if you please.
- I'll see you upstairs.
- Okay.
Senator oran.
Any news?
Only bad news for the ghormans.
I'm afraid we're near
the point of no return.
How can I help?
Turn back the clock.
Send everyone home.
How I wish I could make that so.
This bombing last night...
They have no shame, do they?
They don't even bother
to lie badly anymore.
I suppose that's the final humiliation.
We're assembling a petition, and
I know how... sad that must sound.
It takes more than failed
legislation to upset me these days.
I came here to thank you, mon.
Your constant courage.
The brave face you put to the world.
I've done a poor job letting you
know how much I admire your grace...
And energy.
Protect yourself.
Seriously?
What?
You could've just asked me.
You would've said no.
- Then what are we doing here?
- What's the harm?
You're lucky maarva is not here.
I'm not the one she'd
be straightening out.
- She hated force healers.
- She hated one force healer,
- 10 years ago.
- One was enough.
Doesn't mean the whole thing's a scam.
They wouldn't be faking
something if it never worked.
Why not? What does that even mean?
You know what I don't understand?
If I was in pain, I'd try to
do everything I could to fix it.
You just run around
pretending like nothing's wrong
and everyone knows it's not true.
What's the risk?
What is this?
- I don't know.
- You set this up.
No. No.
Who are you?
Nobody.
I was just walking
home. We're just leaving.
Can you wait? Please.
Give us a moment. I'll be back.
Sorry.
For what?
I was about to ask how I know you, but.
I'm realizing now that's not it at all.
I'm late already.
I'll see you back there.
He's got a blaster burn that's not healing.
Your right shoulder.
Tell her.
Yes.
May I?
Thank you.
"Thank you" for what?
The clarity.
That feeling.
It's been a very long time.
I thought it had gone for good.
It's so easy to lose faith.
They come, no matter what.
Sometimes it even works. But this...
You...
All that you've been gathering.
The strength of spirit.
Surely you must feel it.
I'll work on that.
I'll come back and let you know.
You saw something.
Why do you keep pushing?
Why are you so upset?
I asked you not to do this.
Stay if you want.
You scared him.
I'm sorry.
It's not easy to do.
Who is he?
A pilot.
A soldier.
Tell me what you saw.
I sense the weight of
things, things I can't see.
Pain, fear...
Need.
Most beings carry the
things that shaped them.
They carry the past.
But some... very few...
Your pilot...
They're gathering as they
go. There's a purpose to it.
He's a messenger.
There's some place he needs to be.
Have you known him long?
I don't remember not knowing him.
Maybe you're the place he needs to be.
Enza.
- Don't you know there's a curfew?
- I needed to see you.
Then have a good look.
I... think there's a way out of
this before things go too far.
My people are convinced you're
being coordinated by outside agitators.
If I had something to offer,
if we could lay this
off on outsiders, then...
It's better, isn't it?
That must be confusing.
She asked me who you
were. I said you were a pilot.
Don't tell people what I do.
What happened when she touched you?
She's a cook in the mess hall.
And you're more than a pilot.
It's ridiculous.
She knew you were there.
She felt it from across the
yard. She wasn't making that up.
That wasn't a scam.
- What was it, then?
- I don't know.
I don't even think she knows.
But it happened, and I could sense it,
and I'm not afraid to say that.
I've felt it before, cass.
She called you a messenger.
I've had dreams like that.
Why are you doing this?
What if it's important?
I know you felt something.
That's why you're so upset.
Let it in.
It can only be good.
There's no other reason.
What's all this?
We filed an exit plan.
Without a destination.
It's a personal trip.
This ship's to be fitted with
hyper-comms tomorrow.
We'll be back soon.
That is unacceptable, and you know it.
- This isn't a base for privateers.
- All set. Clear.
Those who enjoy the security of
yavin must proclaim their loyalties.
Don't push too hard.
You know where I stand.
The day I need permission
to come and go, I'm gone.
That day is near.
Fall out! Quick time!
Tighten up! Look lively!
Yes, sir.
Fall in!
Form up!
- Sergeant.
- Sir.
Get these men shaped up
and ready for presentation.
There's not a man amongst
them, sir, but I'll do what I can.
Am I gonna have a problem with you?
Duly noted, sir. Problem-free.
What is that supposed to be?
All right, listen in!
He's got a number of
units coming in today.
Attention!
Left turn!
They look like children.
Quick march!
Talk to me.
Twelve hundred at the Mark.
What are you doing?
- What?
- Look where you're going.
You said come in low, right?
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Hello.
And you.
Haven't seen you in a while.
I know.
Everyone's so busy.
Anything you can talk about?
Well, I'm here now. I'll be around.
I'm doin' intakes.
Scaring the new recruits.
No more smuggling?
I needed a break.
It's good to hear you say that.
I was getting reckless.
You're looking for cassian, aren't you?
No.
They sent me to talk to you.
Draven. Dodonna.
They need him, bix.
They're on the verge of promoting him,
and then he goes and does
something like this morning.
I know you.
I know how deeply you
believe in what we're doing.
We're not luthen's puppets anymore.
We're not a bunch of maniacs
running around aldhani.
We're building a real army.
Cassian is a leader now.
We've all given so much.
A little discipline doesn't
seem too much to ask.
He'll be there when you need him.
I'll pass that along.
When did this happen?
It's been a few months.
I've gotta get going.
What if the comms don't work?
We'll test first thing.
If that's a fail, we'll meet here.
Our secondary would be the ship.
Second floor, third from the left.
She's in there.
She sleeps in the building.
The locals say she's on the
Plaza once or twice a day.
She's easy to spot.
She doesn't stay any place very long.
The glass? It might need two shots.
I don't know.
It's old, but I can ask.
All right, here comes my guy.
Comms, first thing.
Ferrix.
Stone and sky.
Welcome.
Thank you.
Here.
You'll have to scan for them.
Ronni goo...
Goo-jah.
- Goo-jah.
- Mid-rim news.
Never heard of it.
We're trying to change that.
I don't see an entry stamp.
Journalists require imperial approval.
I... I know. Yeah. I just got in. I
I didn't wanna risk the... the curfew.
You'll have to go over there
tomorrow and sort it out.
- Yeah.
- We're required to notify them.
Of course. Yeah.
The Alderaan group. Their
shuttle's been canceled.
Again?
Good luck with that.
I have a room at the
front, facing the Plaza.
Perfect.
You know, most guests don't
say that anymore. It can be loud.
I'm a deep sleeper.
She will report it.
We turn over our guest
list each afternoon.
Good to know.
And you'll have to carry
your own bag this time.
You know the way.
Thank you.
Is this the weather center?
Clear skies tonight.
We'll be updating the
forecast at first light.
I'll make sure to listen.
We're always here.