[♪ captivating music playing]
[♪ music fades]
[♪ soft music playing]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ music fades]
[Ferrix Anvil Gong sounding]
[droid chittering]
- [powering up]
- [rhythmic warbling]
- [device beeping]
- [warbling speeds up]
[warbling intensifies]
[droid chittering]
[trooper 1] If there
was a schedule,
if they simply rotated the roster,
that would make it so much easier.
- [trooper 2] Exactly.
- [trooper 1] Who's gonna
be out in front of that?
Pick the wrong day to raise your
hand and they'll reassign...
- Niya.
- [Niya] Yes.
How's it look?
It's good. It's prepped for
a test flight in the morning.
The password tonight is Kafrene.
Kafrene.
- Got the key?
- [inhales sharply]
We have to wait for my supervisor
to leave. He never stays late.
Are we safe here?
You're a new test pilot.
You've just arrived,
you're excited.
You wanted to look around
before you went to bed.
- We started flirting...
- I like that. [chuckles]
[gasps]
Sorry. [stutters] I was
told not to look at you.
- I didn't see anything.
- Hey, it's okay. It's okay.
I'm so nervous.
[sighs] Nervous is good.
Keeps us awake.
It's gonna be fine.
I'm never coming back here.
It's a big sacrifice.
I... I've had fun here.
That must sound strange.
- No, not at all.
- [breath trembling]
Now everything changes.
- You're very brave.
- Am I?
- My hand's shaking.
- [footsteps approaching]
Hey.
There you are.
Who is this?
[Niya] New pilot. He couldn't
sleep. We were just talking.
Hello, pilot.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Welcome aboard.
[whispers indistinctly]
[Niya chuckles softly]
What was that?
She said you were cute.
Have you been part of
this for very long?
[gasps]
I shouldn't ask. I'm sorry.
You're risking everything.
You can ask what you want.
[sighs]
If I die tonight,
was it worth it?
You've done this before. You
must have thought about it.
This makes it worth it.
This. Right now.
Being with you. Being here at the
moment you step into the circle.
Look at me.
You made this decision long
ago. The Empire cannot win.
You'll never feel right unless you're
doing what you can to stop them.
[softly] You're coming
home to yourself.
You've become more
than your fear.
Let that protect you.
Thank you.
Okay.
- I need a 12-minute head start.
- Is that enough?
I'll see you along the road.
[wind howling]
[door mechanism beeping]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[droid chittering]
[beeping in alarm]
[Cassian] What is this?
[powering up]
Uh... [sighs]
Okay. Okay, okay, I got this.
I got this.
- [chirps]
- [beeping]
[metallic whirring]
[exhales]
[engines power up]
Oh, yes.
- [grunts]
- [alarm blaring]
Shit!
Come on!
[trooper] What the...
Fire at will!
Shots fired!
[Cassian] No, no,
no, no, no, no!
[grunts]
[beeping]
[switch powers down]
[switch clicking]
No.
- [switch beeps]
- [laser fires]
[powering up]
[grunting]
- [alarm blaring]
- [breathing heavily]
- [ship powering down]
- No! No.
No. Oh, come on.
[rapid beeping]
[beeping intensifies]
- [buzzes]
- [gasps]
[ship powering on]
Come on!
Come on. Come on.
[grunts]
[exhales] Okay.
- No, no, no, no, no, no!
- [screeching]
[♪ dramatic music continues]
[grunts]
[straining]
[breathing heavily]
[grunts]
Come on.
[panting]
[insects chittering]
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[groaning]
[screaming] No! No!
- No! No!
- [Brasso] Bix. Wake up.
- Wake up! Hey!
- No!
Shh. Bix, listen. Shh. Listen.
You're okay. You're okay.
You're fine.
We're safe.
Hey, Bix. Right
here, look at me.
It's Talia.
- What happened?
- [B2EMO] She had an-another dream.
Go back to bed. She'll be fine.
[B2EMO] C-Cassian
will want to know.
- [Brasso] She'll deal with that.
- He'll be home t-tomorrow.
We'll talk about
this in the morning.
[♪ intriguing music playing]
[girl laughing]
[Peer Maid] Really?
Are we allowed?
[Leida] Not if you
don't do what I say.
Quiet. And no
peeking. I'm serious.
And stop.
- You can look now.
- [girl gasping]
- [Peer Maid 2] Oh, Leida!
- [girls exclaiming]
[Sordo] Took a wedding to
get her out of the house!
- Here comes the party.
- [Sordo] Perrin! My favorite nephew.
Sordo, my favorite reprobate.
- How are you?
- Mon.
Praise Mothma. What a
glorious turn of events.
So good to see you.
And looking younger
every season.
- How effortlessly you lie.
- [chuckles]
And my dear boy...
I feel you lurking, Erskin.
Governor Klavin has a new ship.
We have limited space
on the docking platform.
They've taken two spots and
don't seem eager to move.
- And you've asked them nicely?
- I've tried.
What's all this?
More parking problems.
The Governor's ego apparently
won't fit into our lot.
Is this about his new ship?
He's your friend, darling.
You and Erskin sort it out.
[Sordo] So, what do
you think, Perrin?
Wait for them here or get
a head start on the bar?
[Perrin] I think
the bar, don't you?
[♪ soft dramatic music playing]
[man 1] Greetings, Senator.
Senator Mothma.
Have you seen who's here?
[man 2] Congratulations.
- [Mon] Morning.
- [man 3] Senator.
- [Mon] Senator Beeva.
- Senator.
So good to see you.
There you are.
- [Mon] Tay!
- How's the bride-to-be?
Very spoiled at the moment.
- If not now, when, right?
- I suppose.
We're having lunch on the
terrace. You'll see for yourself.
Uh, Mon. Mon, I was hoping
for a chance to speak.
I'm afraid I'm a bit
of a blur right now.
But I know you left
word. I saw your message.
It's just... Well, it's, uh,
quite the production. [chuckles]
Is there something urgent?
No.
Just... looking to catch up.
- I'll find you later.
- Oh, something to look forward to.
[Luthen laughs] Ah. Beautiful.
Thank you. That's the last one.
- [Mon] Luthen.
- Oh, dear, you found me.
[Mon] What are you doing here?
I'm afraid that's a secret.
Away! Away! No chatting, Luthen.
- No spoiling.
- [Luthen chuckles]
- Away with you.
- [Mon] What's going on here?
You'll ruin my surprise.
You've told her nothing, I hope.
Well, I only just arrived.
Oh, he's terrible
at keeping secrets.
- Oh, I've been practicing.
- We'll see about that.
You'll see when I'm ready.
Now, surely there's something
that desperately requires
your presence elsewhere.
- Very well.
- [chuckles]
But I will get it out of him.
What's he doing here?
He's with Sculdun.
- For what?
- Apparently, it's a secret.
[Luthen] Cassian?
The team at Sienar
confirmed he got away clean.
That's it?
It was a pulse code.
Not a conversation.
We should've heard
from him by now.
I can't transmit
from here, Luthen.
I told you when we landed.
That's off the table.
There's already a crowd
at the docking platform.
We're naked here. There's
nowhere to hide a signal.
Keep listening.
[♪ serene music playing]
[insects chittering]
[Bix grunts]
Ugh.
- Let me try the thick one.
- [Wilmon] You know it's not gonna last.
Well, it'll get them
through the harvest.
I can make a new part
tonight. Reforge the old pin.
- Thirsty?
- What?
- You better pull it together.
- Can you just be normal?
She seems awfully determined.
Please.
It's a long walk from the silos.
That's 'cause her mother
doesn't like me coming around.
Why?
We're toolies.
[Bix] There's all
kinds of people here.
Yeah, with shares and visas.
Well, they all
started somewhere.
It's not that easy.
Doesn't seem to be
stopping Talia and Brasso.
Please.
Just give it a rest.
[machine whining]
Hello, Beela.
Hi. [panting]
You've been out here so
long. I brought water.
What a lovely surprise. Wil was
just telling me how thirsty he is.
[chuckles]
What is it?
[Beela] I'm not sure.
[Wilmon] It's Imperial.
Have you seen 'em before?
Maybe once when I was little.
My father will know.
Well, it's not as
cold as it was.
I can't believe you
came all the way out.
Yes, you can.
[♪ tense music playing]
[powering down]
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
Porko!
[Gerdis] You can
stop right there!
You got 15 blasters
pointed at you right now!
[Bardi] Don't tell him that!
[Gerdis] He's surrounded!
- He needs to know it.
- [Bardi] The number?
- The actual number?
- [Gerdis] Are you kidding?
- [Bardi] You are talking to the enemy!
- [Gerdis] I knew you would do this!
I'm not an Imperial pilot!
[Gerdis] Yeah, and I'm not
gonna put a bolt through you!
[Bardi] Toss the blaster
and get on the ground!
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[Krennic] No notes.
No records.
None of you were here.
Nobody puts this
in their calendar.
All service and transport droids
will be data-wiped once we're done.
Your colleagues? Superiors?
If they're not in this room,
they're not cleared
for the project.
Colonel Yularen, Governor
Tarkin, all senior commanders
will be notified by the Emperor
at the time of his choosing.
Now, the group in this
room is, of this moment,
the tightest of closed circles.
Any security violation...
will be brought to the
Emperor's personal attention.
[video playing intro
music on projector]
[Traditional Ghorman
Valley horn sounding]
[narrator on video] Chances are,
if you've heard that sound before,
you've been to the Great
Valleys of Ghorman.
But it's a sure thing no matter
where you are in the galaxy,
you've had your eye on
something made of Ghorman twill.
Elegance and durability available
in all weights and weaves,
the Ghorman marque of
excellence is known everywhere
as the standard of
luxury and quality.
But where does this magic begin?
[horn blows]
That's the traditional
Ghorman Valley Horn
sounding the wake-up call for the
creatures who've made this planet
the success it is today.
Time to rise and start spinning.
Meet the Ghorman spider.
The experts have a fancier
word. Don't they always?
They call them "Ghorlectipods."
Whatever you call them, there's no
denying their dedicated work habits.
Spinning from dawn till dusk,
never stopping to feed or sleep
until the Ghorman sun has set.
Forty billion Ghorlectipods housed
in webberies across the planet
will spin the fiber from which
60 million bolts of Ghorman twill
will be processed just
this season alone.
It's a planetary-wide effort,
with each of Ghorman's nine
provinces pulling together
to provide a single processing
and delivery system.
All that gorgeous material
gathered for display and sale
in the capital city, Palmo.
The perfect setting for buyers and
designers from around the galaxy
to tour the showrooms
and brokerages
of this peaceful and
elegant metropolis.
"Ghorman pride" is a
term you'll often hear.
And it will only take you
a few hours on the ground
- to understand the source of that term.
- [Krennic] Thank you.
Ghorman...
is of great interest
to the Empire.
[Cassian] What happened
to my ship? It's ruined.
[Bardi] Hold him. Get his feet.
- [Cassian] Where's Porko?
- [Gerdis] Shut up.
[Cassian] Somebody tell
me what's going on here.
- [Gerdis] Somebody hit him.
- [grunting]
- Who are you?
- Who is he?
- He's an Impy pilot.
- Can I just do this, please?
Then do it.
- Who are...
- Let's see. We're waiting.
- [Gerdis] Let me know when you're done.
- I'm here to meet a friend. Where is he?
- We ask the questions.
- Wow.
Big move. Now you can
ask him who he is.
Maybe I'll get an answer.
That's a stolen ship.
There was another pilot here,
waiting to take it forward.
Stolen for who?
- For the Rebellion.
- Whose rebellion?
Where is the pilot
I'm supposed to meet?
- Where is he?
- Your friend was not friendly.
He took a shot at us.
Tried to make a run for it.
Big mistake.
[Rika] He's lying anyway.
- This guy is a test pilot.
- [all groan]
[Krennic] I doubt anyone here is
unaware of the difficulties we've had
making the Emperor's dream of
energy independence a reality.
Now, I hear the rumors.
I know the stories.
Delays. Setbacks.
Groveling for Senate funding.
I met with the
Emperor yesterday.
And he suggested, I remind
you that the Energy Initiative
remains the centerpiece
of his agenda.
Access to stable,
unlimited power
will transform the
galactic economy
and solidify Imperial authority.
And it turns out,
spiders are not the most
unique thing in Ghorman.
There's a mineral
underground. Doctor?
Deep substrate foliated Kalkite.
[Krennic] Kalkite.
Synthetic Kalkite.
Kalkite alternatives.
Kalkite substitutes.
I mean, the amount of time spent
pondering this grubby little bit of rock
is sadly astonishing.
Now, we've promised
delivery in three years.
That delivery is dependent on
some version of Ghorman Kalkite
to coat the reactor lenses.
Now...
should we fail to
find any alternatives,
we will have to control Ghorman
with a hand firm enough...
[whispers] ...to silence... [in
normal voice] ...any resistance,
and you've been selected
to help plan for
that possibility.
[Rika] There are lights on but there
is no power. I don't understand.
[Bardi] This should
not be that difficult.
- [Rika] Where is the power coming from?
- [flicking switch]
[Bardi] Maybe on that side.
- [Rika] Bardi.
- [Bardi] Right.
- Please...
- [Bardi] Will you be able to do it?
Nothing's where
it's supposed to be.
[Cassian] I wouldn't touch that.
- [Bardi] What is it?
- I'm not sure.
What is that?
No clue.
So, how did you get here?
I guess it's my
lucky day. [scoffs]
You think this is funny?
Listen. There is
no manual. Okay?
Hey, we're trying to focus here.
What do you think?
Can you fly it?
[woman] I don't know.
[sighs] It's all new.
[Gerdis] He can fly it.
We need all the room we can get.
Do the math. We don't all fit.
Is there anything
to eat in there?
- [Bardi] No!
- [woman] No!
The Kalkite extraction. I'm
assuming it's an invasive process.
It would present stark challenges
to the local population.
Meaning what?
The extent of our withdrawal
may render the planet unstable.
It's gouge mining.
There would be stress
on the planet's core.
There is a risk
of... total collapse.
[Admiral Daysar] Nine cities.
Eight-hundred thousand Ghormans.
[Krennic] Well,
relocation would be ideal.
But we need to plan
for alternatives,
all of which will
require preparation.
[Partagaz] Ghorman is neither
obscure nor without political power.
They will not go quietly.
Which is exactly
why you're here.
[Bardi] If Rika says
she can fly it, she can.
She's not saying that. I...
I don't hear you saying that.
- It's confusing.
- He's gotta teach her.
Why would he do that?
If he doesn't, we'll kill him.
- [Gerdis] That's your plan?
- [Bardi] He's gotta know we mean business.
You'd never make it.
Alone? No. No way.
[Bardi] We're in charge.
We call the shots.
But the two of us, we could
be out of here by now.
[Gerdis] Having Rika kill us
- on take-off is not a plan.
- [scoffs]
[Bardi] She just
needs some basics.
He can't teach her if he's dead.
Everything with you is negative.
[Gerdis] Like killing
the only pilot we have?
Well, we gotta have one of 'em.
She just needs a little time.
- [Plug] How long will it take?
- And where do we go?
So, what is it?
- [Rika] Well, we can't stay here.
- Do they really trust you?
Or they just think
you're stupid?
You know I don't need
an excuse to hit you.
I get it.
Two days, no food.
Makes everyone cranky, right?
How do you know how
long we've been here?
- Hmm?
- [scoffs]
You were not here three
days ago when I left.
- We still have the same problem.
- [Flek] He's right.
- Who goes and who stays?
- We make trips.
- And who goes first?
- There it is.
Right there. There's
our real problem.
- Me?
- The lack of trust.
Your brother dumped us here and ran
away, and you wanna talk about trust?
- He went back for survivors.
- Nobody believes that.
Rika, Neek, Nazy, Rowd...
- Oh, we know what really happened.
- [Cassian] Maya Pei.
You're the Maya Pei Brigade.
What? What did you tell him?
- This is on you.
- Crab?
- What's the rub? He can see we're stuck.
- [chuckling] I know Maya.
- Maya's dead.
- According to you.
- Only he saw her.
- I was trying to save her.
We got ambushed. We lost
6 ships, 40 fighters.
- My brother was the only who...
- Your brother ran away!
- How do you know Maya?
- She was a customer.
We've been supplying
you along the way.
[pants] Argue all you want, but
we're all part of the same rebellion.
Your friend was hostile.
He was on a mission. [scoffs]
We're stealing an
Imperial test ship.
- For who? Who are you with?
- [pants]
I'm not telling you that.
We told you.
Yeah, well, you should
be more careful.
You scobbing jack pad!
- No, no, no!
- No. No. No.
- Hey, stop!
- Stop it!
Crab, you gotta stop it!
We're not here to... to
gloss over any difficulties.
The suppression of Ghorman is not
a decision to be taken lightly.
This is not our first
meeting on the subject.
Dee Shambo, Nisus Osar
will be our partners from the
Ministry of Enlightenment.
- Gentlemen...
- Thank you, Director. [clears throat]
Some of what you're thinking about
Ghormans at this very moment exists
because we put it there.
Hasn't there always been something
slightly arrogant about the Ghor?
Oh, we all feel
it. What is that?
Last year, when the shipping
lanes had to be shut down,
how hard would it have been to
simply allow the Imperial inspections
that most other planets welcome?
And didn't it seem as if the Ghor
were doing what they always do?
Putting themselves first.
Did a dedicated
Imperial Naval Inspector
really have to die to
protect Ghorman pride?
We did that.
We made the story. We
shaped it. We blew it up.
We decided when it was over.
With the right ideas
planted in the right market,
in the right sequence,
we can now weaponize
this galactic opinion.
[Osar] Now, we love the spiders.
Oh. Oh, it's an image
we can build on.
Aggressive, unpleasant,
keeping to themselves.
Now, is it just coincidence
that the Ghorman personality
seems so in tune
with these creatures?
The secrecy, the overcharging,
mocking Imperial protocols.
- Laughing at us...
- Okay.
Yep. We, uh... We get the idea.
[clicks tongue] You're
wasting daylight.
There must be food and
water out there somewhere.
- There's beasts out there.
- No talking.
I don't take orders from Bardi.
What kind of beasts?
You'll hear 'em tonight.
[chuckles softly]
- [Gerdis] I'm not saying I trust him.
- Supposed to be an intake gauge.
- But you'd let him fly us.
- If that's the only choice.
Once we're in the
air, he's in control.
- Why are there two?
- You're not getting anywhere.
You're not letting her concentrate!
Rika has to learn how to fly this plane.
Well, she's not...
So, who's really in charge here?
[all scream]
[animals screeching]
It's harder than it looks.
[Gerdis] Are you insane?
Why not have a plague? Or
stage some natural disaster?
That'd motivate them to leave
the place of their own accord.
We've actually gamed that out.
It gets unpredictable
very quickly.
The drilling equipment's
being assembled now
and warehoused for
transport when needed.
And once that's all ready,
how quickly can you mobilize?
- Once we're tucked away...
- Mmm.
...the drilling is easy. We can be
up and running in a matter of weeks.
[breathes deeply]
It's the administration and
security issues that are troubling.
We don't have a large presence
on Ghorman at the moment.
He's planned for that.
We're building a
new armory in Palmo.
Excuse me?
We're starting tomorrow.
You're awfully
quiet, aren't you?
- It's a lot to take in.
- [Krennic inhales] Oh!
I heard you learn quickly.
I like to know what
I'm talking about.
You're here at my request.
I don't get to Coruscant
much these days,
but I do keep my
ear to the ground.
Now, some people might not have
recovered from an incident like Ferrix.
You're not inspired by the
anti-Ghorman whispering campaign?
I'm still forming an opinion.
Piece of advice.
You think you're hard to read?
You need to get over that.
Now you have a plan already. You had
it before they finished speaking.
I want your assessment.
- [sighs]
- Propaganda will only get you so far.
You need a radical
insurgency you can count on.
Count on for what?
You need Ghorman rebels you can
depend on to do the wrong thing...
Director.
[♪ solemn music playing]
[B2EMO stuttering]
I was waiting.
And here I am.
Not for you.
Cassian.
[sighs] He'll be back soon.
[B2EMO whines]
I spoke to Kellen. He said they
haven't done this in years.
I've been here for eight.
I've never seen it.
What are they doing?
An Imperial Supply Census.
It's an audit. A spot check.
They wanna know what they've
got, where it's coming from.
- What about who's doing it?
- [Brasso] He's asking.
I guess right now, they're
focused on Council Five Hundred.
That's what we saw
out there today.
If they're checking
visas, we have a problem.
- He knows that.
- It's gonna be fine.
No one here is about to
let anything happen to you.
We'll know more tomorrow.
Nothing from Cassian?
I'll have a listen.
[radio static]
[Talia] Come here you.
Cassian?
- Nothing from Porko?
- [sighs]
I've been down there
scrubbing frequencies all day.
We know Cassian got off Sienar.
We know Porko was waiting.
What are we looking at?
I'm looking for a drink.
The monitor's on.
Hope for the best.
[♪ upbeat music playing]
[indistinct conversation]
He came last week.
- Jodi. Done.
- All right.
Leida won't be easy.
You'd know best.
Is he tough enough?
Not by half. He'll
either learn or be led.
[scoffs]
Well, I wish him luck.
Well, it's a proud
tradition in our family.
Uh, we've all treasured
our Naval service.
And where are you stationed?
I've been training on Steergard,
but we're all being transferred now.
Really? Where's everyone going?
Mmm.
[scoffs]
- Quite the event.
- Hmm.
Pace yourself. There's
two more days to go.
I always wondered
where you came from.
More reason to
doubt me, I'm sure.
That's hardly fair.
What are you doing here?
Sculdun's a client. We brought
a gift for the betrothed.
I'm working.
Are we pretending we just met?
No, you've been by the shop.
Just two single women
surveying the prospects.
[sighs]
You've been avoiding me.
You can't be serious.
- [chuckles]
- I'm overly sensitive.
- Huh.
It's been a rough few days.
Is everything all right?
I've had some business go sour.
Things have gone to a head.
I'm sorry.
I'm hoping to stay the
weekend, but... we'll see.
Is Marni joining you?
We're living apart
at the moment.
I'm surprised you haven't heard.
- I have not.
- Hmm.
So much for the gossiping
biddies of Chandrila.
It's a recent development.
[clicks tongue] And it's not what
I wanted to talk to you about.
I know you said
you got my message.
I was hoping we could
discuss the Foundation.
Is there a problem?
[smacks lips] Not like that. No.
[Runai] Oh, Mon. There you are.
- Hello, Tay. Yeah.
- Hello.
- They've had their first fight.
- Oh, dear.
Hmm. Leida's run off.
- You'll have to excuse me.
- Of course.
We'll find time together.
[Runai] Davo just told
me about you and Marni...
[server] Thank you.
- [Leida whimpering]
- Leida...
Oh...
[sniffles]
Darling.
What's happened?
[crying] He's a child.
Tell me.
What happened?
He won't hold my hand.
I keep trying and he
keeps pushing me away.
I'm sorry.
So...
terribly sorry.
[animals screeching]
[Bardi] It has been two days.
He could've been captured.
He could've run away.
[Gerdis] What you are
talking about is a mutiny.
It's not a mutiny if
no one's in charge.
[chuckles] I was always
Maya's number two.
- In your dreams!
- I was always
- supposed to be in charge.
- I ain't never heard that.
- 'Cause you never listen, skug.
- I wanna hear it from Maya.
- That might take a while.
- She's dead.
- [Nazy] She's not.
- You saw nothing.
- You were hiding in the bunker.
- That's a lie.
- I saw you.
- Yeah, you tell him, Rika.
Step off, Rowd!
Maya comes back and we're not here,
there's gonna be noise about it.
- You take it back.
- Get stuffed!
- See what you've done?
- Your brother stole our ship.
Say it again!
- [all exclaim]
- [Nazy] Bad idea, Crab.
Tell him to put it down.
Crab, come on, man.
- He took off...
- [man] You're a cheater!
[man 2] Easy, easy.
[Crab] Call me a liar.
You're not even good at that.
[grunts]
- Skug!
- [man 3] Why?
- Why'd you do that?
- Go. Go, go, go!
[woman] Go! Go, go, go!
[man 3] Drop it,
drop it! Drop it!
- Stay down!
- [gasping]
- [man 4] Run. Run!
- [all shouting indistinctly]
[man 3] All right, get him up!
Get him up! Come on, come on!
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ music fades]