It's that time of the year, toffi!
Senate investiture. I
absolutely adore this holiday.
I want to talk parties.
I wanna know who's
going where with who.
I wanna know where you've been invited.
Dedra meero is running ghorman.
She's been on it all year.
All this time. Hiding it.
What's the obsession with ghorman?
- What are they after?
- I don't know.
I'm trying to rethink this all with her
in the picture. It doesn't make sense.
I need an assessment. Carro rylanz.
He's running the ghorman
front. I'm not sure about the group.
And bix?
No. You'd have to go alone.
I'm not loving Coruscant.
It's overwhelming. I know you...
You've been struggling.
- No! No! No!
- Hey.
We need you, bix. We need you healthy.
No word from your friend?
Cinta? No.
Luthen knows but he won't tell me.
That's not acceptable.
If she wanted to see me, she would.
I'm only meeting you
because we find ourselves
with a unique opportunity.
We have a source inside.
- An imperial source?
- I'll not say.
Feeding false
information is what they do.
They're pretty good at it.
The information is reliable.
They'll need help, sir.
How may we assist?
Transport schedules
need to remain consistent.
The information I pass
them needs to be accurate.
Done.
Let it continue? Let them
build what they want?
Is that truly your recommendation?
I have more questions
than recommendations.
Not much of a revolutionary, are you?
It's a forgery.
What else have we missed?
Even the finest collections
have problems now and then.
"Let's put a bug in davo sculdun's
office that leads directly back to us."
You agreed to it!
We're drowning.
And you keep pretending
it's all under control.
We have to take it out at the party.
And if we can't?
We should be prepared.
- You're late.
- Yeah.
We had a spot inspection
coming out of ghorman.
Preflight check complete.
Hold on.
Set for Coruscant.
Calculating for Coruscant.
Calculation complete.
Look at you.
What's his name?
Varian Skye.
Not bad.
Tell me about the ghorman
front. You weren't there very long.
Don't get involved.
That's your assessment? Just like that.
Two days in. You barely looked around.
How do you know what I did?
We heard it didn't go very well.
You heard? Really? I
only left this morning.
Well, they sent word. They're
very prompt, the ghormans.
What they are is impatient.
They started too late.
Now they're rushing.
That's awfully definitive.
They're not ready, luthen.
I think they know that.
That's why we sent you.
The empire is building an
armory in the center of town.
They say it's a new complex
office, but everyone knows the truth.
There's nothing to be done about it now,
and the more trouble they
make, the worse it will be.
- There's always something to be done.
- Yeah?
Yeah? They have a plan.
They want to hijack an imperial transport
to prove something that
everybody already knows is true.
Who's gonna care about it?
The empire will care about it.
Exactly.
In a place where they know nothing
about fighting. They'll be crushed.
They're finally wanting to do
something and you tell them to be careful.
It doesn't matter to you, does it?
It doesn't matter? Ghorman in play?
A new front line against the empire?
The chance for that? That's a triumph.
You're thinking small.
You're thinking like a thief.
I'm thinking like a soldier.
Think like a leader.
Think about a planet
like ghorman in rebellion.
A planet of wealth and status.
And... if it goes up in flames?
It will burn... very brightly.
I'll skip this one.
Will you excuse me a moment?
Yes?
Waste of time. This
piece isn't what we need.
We knew that already.
I thought seeing it in person
would make a difference.
I have a customer waiting.
You were sourcing another item.
It's being delivered as we speak.
Visiting friends?
- Why do you ask?
- I'm curious by nature.
I have friends everywhere.
I had a feeling you were on your way.
Hi.
Look at this place.
You cleaned it up.
We're here. Might as well.
Yeah. The flowers...
They're expensive. But they are beautiful.
The trip? Okay?
Different.
Who were you?
I was varian Skye.
I was a fashion designer.
Yeah.
I was very, very pretty.
I'm sorry I missed that.
Fresh blue suit.
Coruscanti shirt.
Polished shoes.
Just your kinda guy.
Well, you're gonna have to
bring him home some night.
You... you must be hungry.
Hey.
You okay?
Was it dangerous?
Ghorman? No.
Just... all talk. A waste of time.
It's luthen that scared me.
Yeah. Tell me about it.
He came after you left.
I didn't realize how
shabby the place looked.
What? He came?
Yeah, he was gonna ask
me for a weapons appraisal
but he changed his mind.
Go out? On your own?
He waits... he waits for me to
leave? He comes when you're alone?
He changed his mind, so
I rode back with him this
afternoon, he never mentioned it.
- It happened.
- I know it happened, bix.
That... that's not what I'm saying.
What is that?
He knows you need a rest.
- I would have gone if he asked.
- That's not the point.
He's so pissed off,
he's not gonna tell me?
He has to know we're
having this conversation.
He doesn't do anything without a reason.
Maybe he just wants us to
waste our time talking about it.
Maybe.
That leaves senator rhodi,
senator plada, danascar,
we can't possibly make them all...
If we... if we skip the girvan banquet,
then we could just about
make the whole night work.
And we can't leave sculdun's early.
No, no, no. We'll finish there.
Why so difficult this
season? You never struggle.
It's these dinners.
I mean, how many years did you
serve before we held a ceremony dinner?
I count eighty. Eighty new senators,
all hosting "investiture banquets."
It's tough squeezing a whole year's
worth of insincerity into three nights.
You'll figure it out.
This was a very poor decision.
You come to the house
and you mess with bix?
You mess with her behind my back?
You realize what you're
putting at risk right now?
It would have been so
easy for you to tell me.
When you leave here,
and that will be immediately,
you'll have brought a medallion
that was missing from a shipment
that kleya took this
afternoon. A darvian medallion.
So, thank you for this.
Coming all this way.
What's wrong with you?
This is the second time
today you let me down.
You had to know she would tell me.
I thought it would be
interesting if she didn't,
but now you've both disappointed me.
And that's what's most important, right?
- How it goes for you!
- What's most important is the cause!
"Kill me or take me in."
You're in!
"But ghorman looks too
painful. Bix is too vulnerable."
- I give you everything.
- This is everything?
This fury? This lack of control?
Violating every protocol we live by?
Soft on ghorman but willing
to protect bix at any cost.
We... we are not droids, luthen.
We are not who we
were when we started.
Bix has to pull it together.
Or you will have to decide at what
point it becomes too large a problem.
Unless that's what
you're doing right now.
No. No, no, no, no, no, no.
That's gonna be up to you.
I want her as strong as you do.
It would just be easier if I was alone.
I came with you to be part of something.
You want my blood?
You help me work this out.
Thank you for the medallion.
Coming all this way.
Morning, gentlemen.
Just who I wanted to
see. Save us all a meeting.
Dr. Gorst. Success invites scrutiny.
Our cousins in military
intelligence have been salivating
over our interrogation results
and have convinced the emperor
that Dr. Gorst is too valuable
to be a one-man, isb asset.
He's to be expanded into a program.
Sorry to hear that, sir.
The Navy's donated a
facility here in Coruscant.
I want the two of you to
represent our interests in this.
I'm counting on you to
keep watch on these idiots.
An honor, sir.
Really?
It's an assignment.
Calibrate your enthusiasm.
Yes, sir.
We'll have a brief sent down.
You're taking the lead on this.
Why did I say that?
- Fill me in after you've read the brief.
- What?
Any trouble getting through?
It was easy.
My hair.
I like it.
I forget about it.
The gear?
The kid took it.
- Do you know where it's going?
- It's not far.
Thought we should meet first.
I was told they don't
know what they are doing.
That's why we're not doing much.
It's fast, it's simple.
You brought the fuses?
More than enough.
We get a look at it tonight?
And the crew. Whole thing.
If we don't like it, we walk.
I told luthen that I would only take
this assignment if you were on it.
You're the only reason I'm here.
I had an accident.
I told him not to tell
you. I knew you'd worry.
What happened?
I'll tell you about it someday.
It's been a long year.
I had to rest up for a while.
Quite a while.
I had time to think.
Wish I'd known.
I thought about you.
Can I help you?
Um, I'll have what she's having.
- Our friend in ghorman?
- He's just reached out, sir.
There's an isb field agent on-site.
They believe a rebel attack is imminent.
There's been a rapid
increase in local activity.
- And the shipments are running smoothly?
- Yes, sir.
You walk a very narrow path, dedra.
Syril must never know
what this is all really about.
I remind myself constantly, sir.
What's the fastest they could get here?
Eight minutes. And
we can slow them down.
Let's call it six minutes.
That's six minutes from
the moment we go loud.
Time's up.
We leave with what we
have. We don't get greedy.
We need all the weapons we can get.
We're not just here to make a point.
Some of us want to protect ourselves.
Don't.
- "Don't" what?
- Don't talk.
Don't think.
Do as you are told.
If you can't manage that,
you don't belong here.
The staging area feels right.
There should be just enough
time between the transports
to do what we need to do.
Tell me about the neighborhood.
Three families here.
Another two at the back.
- Both with children.
- This building is empty at night.
But there is five units here,
two in front, three at the alley.
Do we control these rooftops?
Most of them.
And we can always lock a few doors.
Fine. Let's talk about the back end.
Every person in this room needs
at least two alternative exit plans.
Down below, you're
driving the transport, right?
That's our ride out.
You're the end of our line.
Which means you do not
move under any circumstances
until you are told to do so.
By who? By you?
I live here. We've put a lot into this.
Your time means nothing.
Prep is useless if you can't follow orders.
You ready?
It's not so hard.
Show me.
It's a good plan.
You've picked the right spot.
Nobody needs weapons.
Everyone has a way out.
But right now, it is just a plan.
We're here because you've
never done anything like this.
I can't stress this enough.
You're all going to need to
respect the chain of command.
Cinta and I will have
blasters. Nobody else.
And I mean nobody.
We will drop the carrier.
We'll drop it and cover
you for six minutes after that.
But we do not go
unless everyone here agrees to
do exactly as they've been told.
If that's not possible, this
would be the time to say so.
- You mean, now?
- Right now.
When are you planning to do this?
Tomorrow night.
Intelligence gets stale.
You might be too late already.
Tomorrow it is.
Bix?
It's flashing.
Whatever the mission is, I'm coming.
Do you hear me?
Hey. Hey.
You'll come with me.
What do you think?
Well, they're not stupid.
We have the trigger.
If it doesn't feel right, we'll walk away.
The driver, dreena...
She should be up top with us.
Did she say something else?
Just a feeling.
They must have another driver.
I'm sorry I hurt you.
I was...
Confused.
I don't know who I am sometimes.
I'm not perfect either.
You make yourself change.
I've never done that.
Luthen should have told
me you were in trouble.
I wasn't thinking clearly.
All the more reason.
He shouldn't have let you say no.
He should have told me.
We're worth more to him
separately than together.
Well, that's something we'll
have to talk to him about.
Upon my life and honor...
Life and honor...
For the peace and bounty of all beings...
Peace and bounty... My full allegiance...
Full allegiance... A galaxy of worlds...
A galaxy of worlds...
A galaxy assembled...
A galaxy assembled... An empire!
Driver's here.
Senator mothma.
Senator organ a.
- Perrin.
- Bail. How are you?
I'm free. That was my last
investiture party of the season.
Don't tell me you've left
poor breha up there all alone.
No, we had to split up to cover
the rounds. I drew sculdun.
- Yes. We almost did that. But...
- not tonight.
No, you're family now.
You're in for the show. Good luck with it.
This is an imperial security protocol.
I need all personnel
to exit the control center
immediately for security reasons.
Let's go.
Apologies for any inconvenience.
Senator mothma, over here!
- There you are. Party trail refugees.
- We made it.
Took us long enough.
Have you spoken to the
children since they've been back?
- We must.
- We must absolutely.
When the festivities are over.
Thank you, senator mothma.
They're just setting up now.
Are we on schedule with
the targeted shipment?
Yes, sir. We're all set here.
- How do they seem?
- They're on time.
Be careful in that tunnel.
Pre-carvian. Third millennium.
It's a good guess.
The stone is carvian,
but it's older, isn't it?
We think it's lost empire.
My word, luthen. And you wear it out?
I thought one of you thieves
might make me an offer.
It takes one to know one, luthen.
I don't know what to do, kleya.
I am sick about this forgery.
- I'm sorry.
- Sculdun's been relentless.
Yeah, I'm sure.
You haven't told luthen about
the reappraisals, have you?
No, I promised, didn't I?
- Yeah, sorry...
- Don't worry.
This is actually better than my fantasy.
Soak it up. We'll never
be back here again.
Speak for yourself.
How did you two get in here?
We come every year.
Partagaz had an emergency
and tossed us the invites.
- Where's your buddy?
- He'll be here.
What are we drinking?
Kali coolers, and they're amazing.
This is my third one.
Dispatch confirmed. We're in the queue.
Repeat, we're up next.
Everyone take your
positions and be ready.
Thank you.
A new season of legislative initiative.
How thrilling.
Always looking on the bright side.
I haven't heard from my cousin.
She's probably just being careful.
Well, tell her to check in with me.
Something urgent she needs knowing?
Yes. I care about her.
Showtime. The sculdun collection awaits.
We're discreetly gathering the chosen.
What fun. I just happen to
have my history teacher with me.
Yeah, we're coming, we're
coming. We'll see you there.
Lonni.
Perhaps you remember me. Kleya.
You came by the shop to
find something for your wife.
- What are you doing here?
- We had a fascinating conversation.
Your friends will think we're flirting.
There's no harm in that, is there?
Are you out of your mind?
Do as I say and everything will be fine.
Target is en route.
We always like to feature something
fresh to the collection up front,
and this is our latest addition.
And the miracle man who helped
secure this very special piece
is actually here with us tonight.
Director krennic, luthen rael.
What a pleasure.
How kind you are.
Senator mothma, perrin fertha,
I'm sure you've met before.
Yes. I've been a guest at her
committee on several occasions.
How pleasant to see you
free of the witness stand.
What a festive evening this has become.
So, tell me what we're looking at.
Yes. The lost tairn. This
is a very rare, special piece
we're very lucky to have acquired.
I'm showing you something special.
Is it from carmeen?
Do you have any idea
who's in this room right now?
You're not smiling.
This is suicide.
It's my favorite object in the collection.
I was heartbroken when we sold it.
Luthen will tell them that's why
I'm so keen on visiting with it.
They've done it. The carrier's down.
Repeat, the carrier is down.
We're in play.
There's only three like it that we know of.
This... this is the one
that was left behind
during the battle of carmeen.
There's a stone carving that
depicts three identical tairns
mounted on the altar of the
grand carmeenian forest...
- Isn't it beautiful?
- You're risking everything.
Move slightly to your left.
Tell me what you're doing.
I'm removing a listening
device from this piece
and you're going to help
me by blocking the view.
You can't possibly be serious.
The tinian codex was
forged 2000 years ago
on a planet where sight
was considered a disability.
And what were you
gonna do if I wasn't here?
Anything I had to.
This is do-or-die, lonni,
so move to your left,
and listen closely
because we may be tested.
That's a great story.
Go.
That one, open.
We're good, move.
We're good.
This piece will eventually,
as my greed subsides
join its sisters in the whole of history.
We'll make an event of it.
Don't rush. Smooth is faster.
There's a bit of a theme
on this side of the gallery.
There's a carmeenian helmet.
It's a few centuries
after the grand conflict.
We studied the battle of
carmeen at the isb academy.
Well, it wasn't much of a battle, was it?
No, how right you are... Tinians believed
all language could be reduced to touch.
Their skin was so sensitive.
Very few carmeenians
lived to tell the tale.
You know how it is.
Insurgencies have a long
history of puffing up their failures.
We were taught it was
a systematic execution.
Well, that is exactly my point.
Criminals love to lie.
After all, who wants to
die for "lawless ineptitude"?
Well... How much longer?
It's stuck.
They're offloading.
I count at least six.
They're using the spillway
tunnels. They're moving quickly.
The shedian word for
"memory" is almost identical
to their word for "revenge"...
What are you doing?
- Shift right.
- They're almost here.
I'm walking away.
Do as I say.
Was meant to be a cathartic
curse written into the stone.
Zippe, zippe, zippe!
You seem fixated on defining
people by their resistance to power.
Words do still have meaning.
As I'm sure we can still agree on that.
What's the word for
people like the carmeen
who simply wish to be left alone?
Vulnerable.
What's the word for people
who skin trespassers alive?
- Is that what they did?
- It was a very long time ago.
Well, they had their
own code of conduct.
My rebel is your terrorist.
Something like that?
What a swell party this is.
Let us continue.
- Put both hands on top.
- Why?
Hold it steady.
One minute warning.
Have you seen dreena?
Let's go. Last few boxes.
- She's not here.
- She wandered off.
- We're not waiting.
- We have a minute.
I'll clean up the fuses.
Help them finish.
Okay, let's wrap it up. We're leaving now.
This piece was just laying in
plain sight. Totally unrecognized.
Not as a cloak rack, but as a
ballast for a swamp freighter.
Shots fired.
One shot.
No. No.
I can't see it from here.
- I can't move.
- Never mind that.
Call the response team.
And come in loud, make sure
they know we're on the way.
Jacquème! Jacquème! Lo stique sassor!
Nache mik balor! Sim ro nache telpó!
Hey, you need to stand, we
have to move. Look at me.
I... I need help.
We have to go, okay? We have to go.
I can take her. I can take her.
Tinian codex...
Isn't it lovely?
I understand that this piece is...
It's a favorite of yours.
It's very special.
Why?
It's a book.
You read by touch, your hand.
It's from a planet where
blindness was considered a gift.
Well, I'm sure we can
all think of some people
who would be right at home.
Feel free to touch.
I often find myself wandering
by and closing my eyes...
To wonder at another world.
Come on. We have to go.
Are you crying?
Are you?
Look at me.
Look at me!
There's no place to hide. Look at me.
I'm not going to say "remember
this," because I don't have to.
This is on you now.
This is like skin.
You're taking her with you wherever
you go for the rest of your useless life.
Don't you look away from me.
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
- She was a warrior.
She was everything that
you have daydreamed about.
She was a blooded, fearless warrior
whose loss will be mourned in
ways that you will never understand.
She was a miracle.
And you...
To die like this because of you...
Some whining, simpering, foolish child.
Don't you dare cry.
You'll make up for this forever.
What fun.
You're welcome.
My face hurts from smiling.
Complain all you like, it worked.
We should have killed
krennic while we were up there.
That's the spirit.
Get in the chair.
- I know you.
- Get in the chair!
How do I know
it will only feel like forever.
Hey! Who are you?
Nobody's allowed in here.