So, searching for a more fluid
banking situation, are we?
What will it cost?
I have a 14-year-old son.
I'd like to bring him with me.
- I'm not asking for betrothal.
- Then what are we talking about?
[Davo] An introduction.
Your daughter is 13.
She'll soon come of age.
Two young people.
Attractive and privileged
Chandrilan citizens.
What makes you think I
approve of that tradition?
Our position sometimes makes
decisions for us, don't you find?
[Krole] I'm only here for
another couple of days.
Maybe you'd like to join me.
I'm not sure my
husband would approve.
Is he here?
[Gerdis] You can
stop right there!
You got 15 blasters
pointed at you right now!
[grunting]
[Krole] Does he worry about you?
In what way?
[Krole] We've just shut
down all the comms.
We freeze the zone
during an audit.
It's supposed to stop things sneaking
away while we're doing all our counting.
[Kleya] Nothing.
Radio silence.
Nobody's checked in.
I need to be at the gallery.
I can't help anyone from
here. I need serious comms.
[Dedra] Is that everything?
I was sure if I went
shopping, you'd be delayed,
and we wouldn't have to do this.
No such luck.
We could... pretend
that you're not back.
I have concerns. The
Foundation is up and running.
Your financial blemishes
have been smoothed over
without anyone being the wiser.
Davo Sculdun obviously
has what he came for.
Everyone seems quite pleased
with how they've landed,
and I'm left wondering about
the risk I've taken on.
[Luthen] It's very troubling.
We'll find a number.
Is there any chance
he'd go to Sculdun?
No, he wouldn't dare.
He can't.
[indistinct shouting]
Let your weapon fall.
[grunts]
[indistinct shouting]
He's out! He's getting away!
Come on!
Bring it down!
[♪ thrilling music playing]
[♪ music fades]
[♪ captivating music playing]
[♪ intriguing music playing]
[♪ music ends]
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[device beeps]
- [crackles]
- [whooshes]
[B2EMO] G-G-Go!
We're g-getting away!
- They'll never catch us now.
- [little girl] He's coming back!
[AGR9] Behind you, Bee.
[B2EMO] C-C-Clear the way.
Thank you.
Look out.
[indistinct chatter]
[Brasso] Here she comes.
[farmer 1] Mmm. There's
a place right here.
[Brasso] Yeah. Pay
him no mind, Talia.
[farmer 2] Some of us
haven't had seconds yet.
[Brasso] Some of us
need more than others.
[all laughing]
[Talia] All your whinin'.
Like you don't all eat your
fill every time you sit down.
And, uh, who's helping me bring all
that's left back up the mound tonight?
Oh, I think we have a volunteer.
[all laughing]
[vehicle approaching]
Be back in a minute. Keep an
eye on my bowl, would you?
[farmer 3] No guarantee.
Sorry, I tried to get
here earlier, but...
[sighs] You've got
a lot going on.
Still no Cassian?
I got the call from Six
Hundred this morning.
I wish I had better news.
We're next on the
inspection schedule.
How soon?
They finished there today, so...
tomorrow?
- Are they checking visas?
- It's random.
They found a group hiding
last night in Six Hundred.
Sometimes, they walk right by.
It's a big risk.
Where can we go?
This is the best I could do.
It's an Emergency Work Order
for the Eight Hundred Block.
Three sweepers that need fixing.
You head out tonight, wait till
they finish poking around here,
then circle back
'round in a few days.
Is it legit?
I had to change the date.
You only use it tonight
if you got stopped.
Sorry about this, Kellen.
- You've been a savior.
- Please.
You know Cassian's friend?
The big boss?
If you do and don't want
to say so, that's fine.
But someone needs to tell
him what's going on here.
It's going on everywhere.
[sighs]
Why can't they just
leave us in peace?
Keep your head down.
- [indistinct chatter]
- [woman laughing]
[indistinct chatter]
Ah. [chuckles softly]
I was getting worried.
My gown got snagged.
Oh, no. Is it all right?
I think I stopped in time.
It's fine.
Really is.
Are you nervous?
Of course I'm nervous.
I was awake all night
worrying about you.
Are they all out there?
They can wait.
My mother was drunk when
I got married. [chuckles]
This room.
Right here. [chuckles]
Just like this.
I was so angry, I don't
think I ever forgave her.
But I could never understand why
she'd done it until just now.
What are you doing?
I need to tell you
- what my mother never told me.
- [woman laughs]
Look at me.
Nothing on the other side
of that door matters.
Not the guests, not the gifts, not
the... trouble that's gone into it,
none of it matters.
Money, embarrassment,
pressure...
Wha... What are you saying?
We can walk out there right now,
tell them all to have
a lovely afternoon,
but that it's not yet
time for a marriage.
We can put it off.
[breath trembling]
And it will be remembered
as an act of great bravery,
I promise you.
You do not have to
go through with this.
I wish you were drunk.
[♪ pensive music playing]
Wait.
You're to stand behind me.
[speaking Chandrilan]
[♪ rhythmic drum playing]
[inhales]
[♪ rhythmic drum continues]
[♪ drum stops]
[Perrin speaking Chandrilan]
[♪ rhythmic drum playing]
[♪ drum stops]
[♪ pleasant music playing]
[♪ pleasant music continues]
[breathes deeply]
[♪ music fades]
[doorbell chiming]
[exhaling]
- Mother.
- Hello.
Hello.
Oh. [chuckles]
[kisses] Hmm.
Um, Mother...
this is Dedra.
Eedy, please.
It's such a pleasure
to finally meet you.
Finally, indeed. [laughs]
[laughs nervously]
My word! It's a palace.
Thank you. It's home.
You look nothing
like what I expected.
[Syril chuckles softly]
Here, let me... get your coat.
- Ah!
- [Syril clears throat]
How refreshing.
One longs for courtesy,
don't you think?
Yes, absolutely.
And there is so little of it.
What can I get you to drink?
Don't you wonder what I
thought you'd look like?
I'm afraid to ask.
Do you have spiced tea?
- Since when are you drinking spiced tea?
- "When?"
I see you so rarely.
Are we not allowed
to change? [chuckles]
Well, we don't have spiced tea.
Uh...
They're still open downstairs.
Syril, please, no.
No. I'll have what
you're having.
There's a shop in the arcade.
No, please.
I did not come all this way
to see Syril disappear again.
Show me your wonderful home.
[signal beeping]
[device warbling]
[static buzzing]
[Kleya] Coruscant Forecast
2665, clearing open signal.
Please identify and repeat.
I need a weather report.
What's your location?
I'm in transit.
[Kleya] And where's our freighter?
We've had no word from the relay pilot.
You won't be hearing from him.
It's just me. I... I'm calling
you from the freighter.
[Kleya] Let's start over.
What's your location?
This is not the ship I was
trained to fly. Did you know that?
Did anyone know that?
I can't fly the ship.
The drop is compromised.
I've been upside
down for two days!
Find me someplace safe. And dry.
Let me work on that,
keep this signal open.
- I need to call home.
- No.
Don't do that.
Come again?
[Kleya sighs] It's very
crowded there right now.
What does that mean?
Just give me a few minutes.
[Cassian] Why can't I call home?
You won't get through,
there's a frequency blockade.
[Cassian] What's going on there?
I don't know, which is why I'm telling
you to keep the signal open and...
[high-pitched ringing]
- [♪ tense music playing]
- [scoffs]
[whirring]
[Eedy] Children have
so much to teach us.
It's a lesson that never ends.
Syril's imagination had
always fascinated me.
- Mother, you're dripping.
- It's fine.
I suppose we're fascinated by the
things we don't understand. [chuckling]
Now, Syril's father fancied
himself an adventurer.
It was an expensive delusion.
One day, suddenly, he was gone.
And all we had was each other.
A young, delicate boy with only a
mother's love and determination.
If not for the charity
of his Uncle Harlo,
I can't imagine where we'd be.
What a difficult time
that must have been.
Syril's shared
the story with me.
Really?
Oh! [chuckles]
Well, isn't this
a day to remember?
Can I say how
pleasing it is to hear
he's found someone with whom
he can actually communicate?
- Mother, would you like some...
- I'll get there.
Yeah. Yup. Okay.
- [sighs]
- [Eedy chuckles]
- [Syril clears throat]
- He's embarrassed.
About what?
Doesn't like being
called delicate.
I was just asking if you
wanted some more sauce.
Hmm. Oh!
Tell me about your family.
I don't have one.
My parents were criminals.
They were arrested
when I was three.
I was raised in an
Imperial Kinder-block.
Well... [smacks lips]
Nothing delicate
about that, is there?
We had everything we needed.
[smacks lips] Except
a mother's love.
We didn't know what
we were missing.
[cutlery clatters]
[emcee] Please welcome the freshly
unbraided and forever united
- Leida and Stekan.
- [bells tinkling]
[guests gasp]
[indistinct chatter]
[♪ tense music playing]
Where's the other ammo box?
Blanket crate.
If Bee sees you doing
that, he's gonna panic.
He's off with Talia
and his buddy.
[grunts]
Who's gonna tell him?
I'll do it.
We'll wait to break down a cab.
- When are we pullin' out?
- Sundown.
You never cleaned these tools?
We'll do it when we get there.
[♪ music fades]
[spoon banging on plate]
These are lovely.
Not too sweet.
I was told you like them.
Pleasures of Coruscant.
[sniffles] I told Syril,
when he insisted on playing
at police work on Morlana,
that the benefits of life here
would become clear by contrast.
What are you saying? That
I came home for the cakes?
[chuckling] Well, less said
about that, the better.
And I wasn't
playing at anything.
[Eedy] Of course not.
Main thing is, we're
all here together now.
[scoffs]
Yeah.
Be right back. [coughs]
You'll toughen him up.
I have a different plan in mind.
Mmm, but when I say the word "plan,"
that makes it sound optional,
which is not the impression
you should be taking away.
This game ends now.
You want Syril in your life?
You will think before you speak.
I'll make sure he
visits twice a month.
I'll make sure
that he calls you.
I will guarantee a level of engagement,
but it will be inversely proportional
to the volume of anxiety
you generate in our lives.
- Quite a mouthful.
- I'm not done.
You can spare me the
Uncle Harlo testimonials.
I've had a look at his
ISB criminal files,
and that is not a story
you want to be advertising.
[♪ tense music playing]
[Eedy chuckles]
[Dedra] Apparently I've lost
count. He's been promoted twice.
[Eedy] Wonderful.
[Dedra] More caf?
[Eedy] Please.
- Dedra.
- [breathes deeply]
[clears throat]
Oh, Syril.
Dedra was just telling me
how well you're doing here.
Was she?
And I told her that came
as no surprise to me.
[Syril] That's interesting.
Perhaps some more cakes?
[Syril clears throat]
[all gasping]
[Davo] Yes, it is real.
[all laughing]
For those of you who are visiting
today, this is a Chandi Merle.
It's a temple figure, one of 12
that was stolen 25,000 years ago
when Chandrila was sacked
by Rakatan invaders.
Until today, there were only
eight of these accounted for.
And only five that had
made their way back home.
This is Luthen Rael, everybody,
- for those of you who've not met.
- [indistinct chatter]
Luthen came to me
last year with a rumor
that became a possibility,
that became an adventure.
[all laughing]
And here we are.
Leida...
Stekan...
I gift you this
piece of our history.
May it bind you to the
land and each other.
[all] Teema!
And welcome home, number nine.
- [all] Teema!
- [bells tinkling]
- Teema!
- [all] Teema!
Teema!
So in the pantheon of Chandrilan
weddings, how would you rate it?
I'm afraid it's my first.
Oh, I thought you
were a local boy.
Ah, not really.
Well, my father's Chandrilan.
I was born in Naboo.
- My mother's Ghorman.
- Oh.
He was married.
It was a scandal.
Where were you raised?
Well, we weren't really
welcome anywhere for a while.
We bounced around until she passed
away, and then Mon stepped in.
Oh! Sorry. Erskin, excuse me.
[chuckles]
[indistinct chatter]
- Sagrona.
- [Mon] Mmm. Sagrona Teema.
Ever thought you'd have a
Chandi Merle in your ballroom?
- [Mon chuckles]
- [Squidna] Mon, we'll see you there.
- Come on, Sordo.
- [Sordo] Yes, I'm coming.
He puts on quite a
show, doesn't he?
- [Tay] Yeah.
- [indistinct conversation]
[Tay] He's a lesson for us all.
- What would that be?
- Well...
Speak up, stand up,
make your point.
Every time I'm with him, I'm
reminded how timid I've become.
Every time you're with him?
- Is that a regular occurrence?
- I hope so.
He could be very
helpful to me right now.
But we'll, we'll discuss all
this on Coruscant next week.
[♪ uneasy music playing]
Of course.
It's good timing.
Listen, I came by now,
I have to leave a little early.
And I don't want to keep
abusing your good spirits.
I appreciate that.
I'll call Erskin to
set up a meeting.
[sighs]
Sagrona Teema.
[Mon] Hmm.
[emcee] Ladies and gentlemen,
if you'd please clear the
dance floor at this time.
Thank you.
[♪ uneasy music continues]
[chuckles] Please.
[♪ music fades]
[♪ enchanting instrumental
music playing]
[indistinct]
[♪ enchanting instrumental
music continues]
[all cheering]
Teema!
When were you going
to t-t-t-tell me?
I'm telling you now, Bee.
N-N-Now it's t-t-too late.
We won't be away long.
It's too l-l-long already.
Talia has your charger.
How will C-Cassian
know where to g-go?
[Brasso] You'll be
right here, won't you?
You'll be up on the
hill with Talia,
[whispers] who's
nicer than I am.
[in normal voice] And she's smarter
than I am, prettier than I am.
She knows all your friends and how to
make sure you rest when you need to.
[Talia] We'll be fine, Bee.
We'll have so much fun,
we'll forget all about them.
[B2EMO whines]
[ship approaching]
[♪ tense music playing]
[switches clicking]
[indistinct radio chatter]
[static noise]
Hey, did you see
that ship go by?
I keep hoping it's
gonna be Cassian.
I don't think we should
wait till sundown.
They're sweepin' the far fields.
And they'll be coming back.
We could get pinned down here.
We gotta move.
- Where's Wil?
- I thought he was with you.
His speeder's gone.
Are you kidding me?
[sighs]
I have to go.
You have to tell me where.
It's just best you don't know.
- Until when?
- I don't know. Until they leave.
There's just no choice.
[♪ pensive music playing]
- [Beela] What's this?
- [Wilmon] Stop.
Is that a blaster?
[scoffs]
[transport approaching]
[Beela gasps]
[♪ tense music playing]
[whispering] My speeder.
- What?
- I left it out front.
[Imperial guard
speaking indistinctly]
[Krole] There you are.
- Where's the boss?
- He's at the silos.
I want these men fed.
And, uh, save two meals.
We'll be back in a bit.
- Sergeant Stang.
- [Stang] Yes, sir.
[Krole] We'll be
back in an hour.
[Stang] Understood, sir.
[Imperial guard
speaking indistinctly]
Get inside.
I won't tell you again.
[♪ tense music playing]
[panting]
[indistinct chatter]
You told me he'd stay
away from Sculdun.
- He's been pestering him since he arrived.
- I know.
I warned you from the start.
[whispering] I just can't believe
it. I've known him my whole life.
People fail. That's our curse.
What would've happened if I wasn't
here? Would you have told me?
I'm meeting him next week.
Yes, yes, I would have told you.
I'll warn him off. I'll
find what it takes.
I'll get a number.
You know the number.
We'd be vulnerable forever.
You need to be protected.
I'm not sure what you're saying.
[clicks tongue]
How nice for you.
[♪ upbeat music playing]
[guests cheering]
[♪ tense music playing]
[♪ upbeat music playing]
Mon. How weird is this?
- Oh.
- [both chuckle]
- Here.
- Oh.
- Have an extra celebration.
- Oh, really? [chuckles]
Come. Come dance. Come.
Come on.
[signal beeping]
[radio static]
- Cass?
- [Cassian] Hello?
Hello?
Stone and Sky.
- Cass.
- [Cassian] Are you there?
- Come in.
- Cass.
[♪ tense music playing]
[radio switches off]
Hello.
Where is everybody?
They're in the far fields.
Ah.
No sign of your husband?
He'll be back.
[♪ tense music continues]
Looks like you're, uh,
packing up.
There's an emergency repair
in the Eight Hundred, so...
That's a long way to go.
There's no one closer?
It's harvest. Everyone's busy.
- [blaster whines]
- [stormtrooper] Stop right there.
I got one.
- [♪ upbeat music playing]
- [guests cheering]
- [♪ tense music playing]
- [panting]
[♪ music fades]
[sighs] Doesn't look
very comfortable.
We like it.
I think permanent is
what I meant to say.
I know you're illegal.
We've been counting visas.
It's a tough spot for everyone.
The Councils need the help
or there's no harvest.
The help is undocumented.
The rules are clear,
but the situation
requires... nuance.
[scoffs]
It all ends up on me.
[breathes deeply]
That can't be easy.
It's stressful.
I'm always looking
for ways to... relax.
[♪ uneasy music playing]
My shoulders get sore.
All the hard work...
You must have...
strong hands.
- [♪ tense music playing]
- [beeping]
[whirring]
[stormtrooper 1] Keep moving.
You're not a local, are you?
He's one of the mechs
up the road, isn't he?
You're gonna pretend
you didn't tell 'em?
[chuckling]
I'm gonna kill you.
[Stang] On him! Hold him!
[Brasso] You betraying bastard!
[grunts]
[stormtrooper 2] Don't move!
Use us up. Turn us in.
You'll pay for this,
Kell... [grunts]
You're lucky we were here.
[breathing heavily]
You wanna think this through.
Please don't.
Please. [breath trembling]
I'm begging you.
Oh, but it's such
a simple choice.
I said no!
- [grunts]
- [screams]
[breathing heavily]
- [♪ upbeat music playing]
- [whooping]
[all singing] Niamos!
[Krole] Oh, no, you don't!
[both grunting]
[Krole screams]
Hey! Hey. Hey.
Calm yourself down.
[both grunting]
[grunts]
[Krole breathing heavily]
[Bix grunting]
[Krole grunting]
[grunts]
[Bix yells]
[screaming]
[both breathing heavily]
- [screaming]
- [yells]
Unit Two. Unit Two. We
have a problem out here.
Trouble on site.
[soldier] All right, stand by.
Sergeant!
Sergeant Stang.
[Pyke over radio] Unit Two.
Unit Two. We need help.
[♪ tense music playing]
- [Stang] Corporal Pyke?
- [Pyke] Lieutenant!
[Stang] Come in, Unit One.
[Krole grunts]
[Stang] Unit One, are you there?
Sir.
[groans]
[grunts]
- Where's he gone?
- It sounded like they were under attack.
Mount up!
Six with me, you five
with the prisoner!
- [soldier 1] Let's go!
- [stormtrooper 1] Heading out.
- [Stang] Let's roll!
- [soldier 2] Move, move!
- [soldier 3] Go, go, go!
- [stormtrooper 2] Move, move!
[♪ tense music continues]
[♪ music fades]
You've got five seconds
to show your face
before I turn the
cannon on that shack.
He tried to rape me.
[Pyke] He's dead.
Step out slowly.
[♪ tense music playing]
[exhales]
- [♪ upbeat music playing]
- [guests cheering]
[♪ upbeat music
playing in distance]
- Thanks.
- Thank you, sir.
- Tay Kolma?
- Yes.
I wasn't sure.
- Where's Otto?
- I don't know.
- I was just called to fill in.
- Mmm.
- I was afraid I wouldn't find you.
- And here I am.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[breathes heavily]
Who called that in?
[beeping]
[♪ tense music playing]
- [soldier 1] The transport!
- [soldier 2] What's he done?
- [soldier 3] That's a TIE fighter.
- [soldier 4] That's insane.
[soldier 1] Get those comms up.
- Hey!
- [stormtrooper 1] He's getting away!
[stormtrooper 2]
Move, move, move!
[soldier 5] Hit the speeder!
- [stormtrooper 3] Go, go, go!
- [soldier 5] Get him, get him!
[stormtroopers screaming]
[device trilling]
[stormtrooper 4] Whoa, whoa!
- Look out! Look out!
- [stormtrooper 5] Go, go, go, go!
[stormtroopers screaming]
[beeping]
- It's Cassian.
- Has to be.
Get the speeder.
[panting]
Brasso!
Come on. Hey.
Hey, Brasso...
[breathing heavily]
Come on.
- [sniffles]
- [♪ somber music playing]
Cassian!
[Wilmon] Cass!
[Bix] Cassian!
[Cassian] Hey!
What happened?
We need to go.
We need Brasso.
Get in. Get in!
Come on. Come on!
[♪ upbeat music playing]
[all singing] Niamos!
[all cheering]
[♪ upbeat music continues]
[♪ music stops]
[♪ somber music playing]
[♪ music fades]
[♪ serene instrumental
music playing]
[♪ music fades]