[Cassian] How's it look?
[Niya] It's prepped for a
test flight in the morning.
- The password tonight is Kafrene.
- Kafrene.
[powering up]
[engines roaring]
[Cassian] Okay, I got this.
[Tay] There you are.
- [Mon] Tay!
- How's the bride-to-be?
[Mon] Very spoiled
at the moment.
[Tay] If not now, when, right?
[Krennic] No notes.
No records.
None of you were here.
Your colleagues? Superiors?
If they're not in this room,
they're not cleared
for the project.
[powering down]
[Gerdis] You can
stop right there!
You got 15 blasters
pointed at you right now!
[grunting]
- He's gotta teach her.
- Why would he do that?
- If he doesn't, we'll kill him.
- He can't teach her if he's dead.
Everything with you is negative.
[Gerdis] Like killing
the only pilot we have?
[Flek] We gotta have one of 'em.
You think you're hard to read?
Now you have a plan already. You had
it before they finished speaking.
I want your assessment.
Propaganda will
only get you so far.
You need a radical
insurgency you can count on.
You need Ghorman rebels you can
depend on to do the wrong thing.
Once we're in the
air, he's in control.
- Why are there two?
- You're not getting anywhere.
You're not letting
her concentrate!
So, who's really in charge here?
[all scream]
We should've heard
from him by now.
I can't transmit
from here, Luthen.
I told you when we landed.
That's off the table.
What is it?
[Beela] I'm not sure.
[Brasso] I spoke to Kellen. He said
they haven't done this in years.
[Bix] What are they doing?
An Imperial Supply
Census. It's an audit.
If they're checking
visas, we have a problem.
He knows that.
I know you said
you got my message.
I was hoping we could
discuss the Foundation.
Is there a problem?
[Rika] You were
hiding in the bunker.
- [Crab] You take it back.
- [Rika] Get stuffed!
- Skug!
- [man 3] Why?
All right, get him up! Get
him up! Come on, come on!
[all shouting]
[♪ captivating music playing]
[♪ music fades]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[thunder rumbling]
[rain pattering]
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[Plug] What is she doing?
[Gerdis] She's gotta be close.
[Flek] If Crab was alive,
we'd be hearing him.
[Bayso] She should be
searching the middle.
Is that what she's doing?
I can't tell.
[grunts]
- [Rowd] Anything?
- [Bardi] Not yet.
[Tick] He should've
been back by now.
- [grunting]
- [Bardi] Nazy!
There's nothin' here!
[Bardi] Keep looking!
[Nazy] I'm telling
you there's nothing!
What did you do
with Rika's body?
- [Gerdis] What?
- [Plug] Rika's body?
[Bayso] What is
he talking about?
[Flek] They can't
find her either.
[Gerdis] It's a trap.
[Plug] They've got to
be out there somewhere.
They're messing with us.
[thunder rumbling]
[♪ tense music builds]
- [Snee] No!
- [gasps]
[♪ tense music playing]
[in Huttese] E chu ta!
[Nazy yelps]
- [Snee] Don't shoot! It's me!
- [Gerdis] Don't shoot her!
- [Tick] Nazy, move!
- [Bardi] Hold your fire!
[Gerdis] In! In! In!
[Nazy whimpering]
- What's that?
- It's Rika's goggles.
That's all there was.
[breathes heavily]
No body. Just a boot.
- Crab's boot?
- You just left it out there?
His foot was still in it!
A stump of bloody foot.
- Animals got 'em.
- [Bayso] What else could it be?
- [Gerdis] You sure?
- I picked it up.
[Cassian] Hey! It's
not gonna rain forever.
You might wanna bank some water.
There's a tarp over there.
Before we go in...
I don't want the
Ghorman project.
I've thought it through all
night. And I don't want it.
Humbling, isn't it?
Both of us reminded of our
place in the chain of command.
I'm not sure I know
what you mean, sir.
Did Krennic offer you the job?
- You know that he did.
- Then it's done. We're in it.
And what about Axis?
That's where I belong.
I can't do both.
Axis?
You've invested
almost two years.
You've built the legend and
delivered almost nothing.
We're getting
closer all the time.
"He's here. He's there.
He's everywhere."
He's nowhere!
Next time, catch them first.
Then make them famous.
This will appear
to be a demotion.
You'll have to play the part.
It will heat up soon enough.
This is good news, Dedra.
Ghorman will be yours to run as you
wish. You'll only answer to Krennic
and he's got no time for
anything but results.
Ghorman is a gift.
Take it.
Then win it.
[ ♪ somber music playing]
[Luthen] Please.
You wanna turn it.
Help him.
Guide that. That's it.
[indistinct chatter]
[Kleya] It's still in one piece?
Good luck getting
it out of here.
Now what? We sit all day?
Well, we'll site
it. We'll light it.
Sculdun will change his
mind and we'll move it.
Then he'll reconsider.
Clean it up and we'll
make it lovely and...
Gently there!
Then we'll sit all day.
Nothing.
Radio silence.
Nobody's checked in.
I know I said we shouldn't
broadcast from here,
but I tried to reach out to Bix.
I never got through.
Mina-Rau's been shut down.
"Temporary reception outage
for Imperial inspection."
What kind of inspection?
Wouldn't that be nice to know.
I need to be at the gallery.
I can't help anyone from
here. I need serious comms.
I can't leave. You'd
have to get a ride.
I've found one.
[Mon] Good morning.
You ate already.
I was up early.
[Perrin] They're sneaking
in Sculdun's surprise.
I'm sure you've heard
what it is by now.
Is it really a Chandi Merle?
Yeah, one of them.
It's a bit gross, don't you think? It's
probably worth more than the house.
- You'll want to put that in your speech.
- [chuckles]
Last night was successful.
- Two more to go.
- Mmm.
You should tell your
boyfriend to back off the nog.
And who's my boyfriend?
Oh. What have you done?
- Thrown him over?
- [scoffs]
I don't know who
we're talking about.
Tay Kolma. Is he not your lover?
Haven't heard that
nonsense in a while.
His wife has run off,
so the field is clear.
- He's all yours now.
- Stop.
Well, maybe you've all dropped him.
That would explain a great deal.
Like what?
It's always best to let them down
gently, or so I've been told.
We have a long day, Perrin.
Tay had a bit too much
First Night punch.
He had to be taken home.
I mean, it's a full-on
Chandi wedding.
He grew up four valleys
away, he should know better.
Pace yourself or pay the price.
He was always weak.
[♪ gentle music playing]
[creaking]
[droid chirping]
Did they remember the juice?
[Aneth] Finally.
[Kellen] I'll load
in when I get back.
How's it going?
We're getting there.
I spoke to my friend
at Five Hundred.
She thinks they'll finish
inspecting up there today.
Where they go next should tell us
what direction they're moving, but...
How many are there?
[Kellen] On the ground?
She counted about 40. We don't
know what they have in the air.
- What if they come this way?
- Look, they need the grain.
They know we need help and
they know everyone isn't legal.
How hard they look,
what they do...
It's been ten years since the
last audit. Nobody's happy.
- Talia thinks they'd let us slide.
- We can't count on that.
- What if they ask where we came from?
- I wouldn't mention Ferrix.
- What if we stay ahead of them?
- [Kellen] I'd be careful.
They caught someone
running at Five Hundred.
[♪ uneasy music playing]
I'll find out what I can.
Cassian?
He'll be here.
[Brasso] Thank you, friend.
[Kellen] We'll get through it.
I'll stop by later.
[Brasso] Be careful.
[birds chirping]
[Gerdis] Meal bars?
- [Bayso] Nine.
- [Plug] That's it?
- Well, two look a bit moldy.
- That's all that's left?
- You voted to eat.
- And you should've told us "no."
- [Plug] How many snak-pods?
- [Bayso] Wet or dry?
- [grunts]
- [Plug] I'm not eating moldy.
[Snur] You get hungry enough...
Look, six dry, eight wet.
I'd rather be hungry than sick.
Let's give him a moldy
and see what happens.
[Cassian] You know...
they've gone very
quiet over there.
You need a perimeter.
I was just about to do that.
That's a good idea.
[Flek] They must be starving.
[all groaning]
[Neek] How can it smell
that bad that fast?
[Bardi] Try it.
[Neek retches] No. No.
I don't know.
[grunts]
- Eat it.
- Why me?
You'll eat anything.
You ate those trogs.
- That was a dare.
- Okay, I dare you.
Give it.
If it tastes like it smells...
- [breathing heavily]
- [all groan]
[♪ gentle music playing]
[Syril] There are no small jobs
here at the Bureau of Standards.
You may hear that and wonder
how that can be true, but...
not that long ago, I was
standing right where you are now.
I was given a position
in Fuel Purity.
Just over there.
[snaps fingers]
I found an entry on a Varnesian
input account that didn't match.
Two hundred Kovarn
charging rods.
Doesn't seem like much, does it?
Well, I walked it back.
Every shift, I'd make time from my
quota to dig just a little bit deeper.
Then one day, after
months of searching,
screens started lighting
up across the room.
[inhales deeply]
I had uncovered a cabal of
corrupt purchasing agents
who were stealing Imperial
supplies in four sectors.
[gulps nervously]
There's a future here...
for those who dare.
[insects buzzing]
[♪ mellow music playing]
[Beela] I can try again tonight.
[Wilmon] We better wait.
[Beela] She's just watching
me all the time now.
[Wilmon] Everyone's nervous.
[Beela] My dad even tried
and she wasn't having it.
[Wilmon] Hey.
Once things calm
down, we'll be okay.
Not if you've gone away.
But if we do, I'll come back.
Just promise you won't leave
without saying goodbye.
[Wilmon sighs softly]
Promise.
[transport approaching]
[♪ tense music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
Hello, boys.
- Do you take credits?
- I can do.
- Any cold drinks?
- In the case over there.
[soldier] Got any Peezos?
[Kellen] Sorry.
Where you coming from?
[soldier 2] We just
finished Five Hundred.
[Kellen] You boys are
working fast. Where to next?
[soldier 2] I don't know. You'd
have to ask the Lieutenant.
[Kellen] I haven't met him yet.
[soldier 3] You will.
He's checking out the storage.
[Krole] Hello.
- [tool clatters]
- Hi.
Just finishing up?
Just replacing the bushings.
Have you seen the new silos?
I have. We were based in the Six
Hundred block a few months ago.
I'm not sure they're
worth the cost.
[chuckles nervously]
I guess we'll know
after this next harvest.
I guess so.
[breathes deeply]
So quiet out here.
It's a simple life, isn't it?
It is.
Mechanics, though. [chuckles]
You get to move around a
bit, right? [taps machine]
Yeah, it's true.
Have you been to the Rau?
Some of these farmers live
their whole lives and never go.
It's not much of a city, but you'd
think over time, they'd get curious.
[Bix] I've been there.
[air hissing]
It's changed. Rau.
I hadn't seen it in a few years.
We had a decent meal
there last night.
It's not that far.
It's a beautiful
ride over the fields.
I'm only here for
another couple of days.
Maybe you'd like to join me.
I'm not sure my
husband would approve.
Ah.
Sorry to hear that.
Is he here?
He's off-planet for a few days.
Is he a mechanic as well?
A very good one.
Does he worry about you?
In what way?
We've just shut
down all the comms.
It's not up to
me. It's a policy.
We freeze the zone
during an audit.
It's supposed to stop things sneaking
away while we're doing all our counting.
That's good to know.
[Brasso] Zala.
[Bix] I'm done. You ready?
Yeah. Sorry.
[Krole] Hello.
What's your Council?
[Bix] We're based in 207.
[Brasso] We move around.
We go where there's a need.
Like this.
Well...
nice to meet you.
See you along the way.
[sighs in relief]
[♪ mellow music playing]
[bird calls]
[Perrin] I'd come up here with
my uncles. It was good hunting.
It was all private
back then, of course.
Signs up everywhere.
Keep the poachers out.
I remember the signs.
Didn't stop you.
I wasn't much for warnings.
Well, hasn't been bad for
business though, has it?
[Sculdun chuckles]
- I've always wanted to.
- I see.
Mother wouldn't allow it.
It'll be different now.
[indistinct conversation]
Having fun?
[Vel sighs] When was the
last time this happened?
[Mon] Wedding
hike? Perrin and I.
- It rained.
- [Vel] Ah. I remember.
Is Leida happy? Is this
really what she wants?
Everything old is new again.
As if I needed another
reason to stay away.
What happens at the
top? I don't remember.
We gaze at the ancestral
lands. Some children sing.
The Elder waves her hand and
we'll all have been purified.
[Vel sighs]
No word from your friend?
- Cinta?
- Mmm.
No.
Luthen knows, but
he won't tell me.
That's not acceptable.
If she wanted to
see me, she would.
It was never going
to be perfect.
Or good, really.
Bad timing.
I'm sorry.
Well, there's work to be done.
Yeah, we have to live to
do it, though, don't we?
[insects trilling]
- He should be back by now.
- [Gerdis] I think I know that.
What if they've grabbed him?
[Gerdis] We'd hear about it.
- I don't know about that.
- They could be messing with us.
Taking it to another level.
- How is that another level?
- Snatching him?
- If Plug was a hostage...
- [Snur] That changes everything.
How would that change anything?
We have the pilot.
They have a ship that
goes nowhere without us.
- They could have more food than we think.
- And you can't trust Plug with food.
He'd flip sides for a meal.
Yeah, he'd sure be at
the front of the line.
They don't have any food. Do
they have any food on that ship?
No.
[Gerdis] We have the food.
[Flek] Not really.
I just ate my meal bar.
- All of it?
- Hold on.
[Plug yells]
- [Snur] It's Plug!
- [Plug] Don't shoot!
- [Bayso] Oh, oh.
- [Plug grunts]
Hang on. Just... [panting]
- We were getting worried.
- We should be.
- We should be getting worried.
- [Gerdis] About what?
- [Bardi] One, two, three!
- [♪ tense music playing]
- [all grunting]
- [metal strains]
[Plug] They're trying
to turn it around.
The guns at the front.
- They're trying to put us down the barrel.
- No.
- Look, can they do that?
- They're tryin'.
- [all grunting]
- [metal strains]
[thudding]
- It moved!
- [Nazy] Check it.
[Bardi] Rowd?
[breathing heavily]
Another few centimeters.
[Bardi] Okay. Bit by bit.
[Tick] That's a lot of bits.
Square up. Let's go.
Do you realize how
long this could take?
[Gerdis] 50 centimeters an hour?
- [stutters] At most.
- [Bayso] All night long?
[Snee] Let's say it's 50.
- [Gerdis] Uh, 50 by 10 is...
- [sighs]
If they're lucky, they'll
make 5 meters by midnight.
[scoffs] They will be close.
[all grunting, gasping]
[Bardi] Fall back! Fall back!
Fall back! Take cover!
[person cheers in distance]
[♪ operatic music
playing over speakers]
[doors sliding open]
[music stops abruptly]
[doors sliding open, closes]
[Syril] You're back.
I just got here.
It was okay?
Whatever... it was?
It was quick.
Is that everything?
I was sure if I went
shopping, you'd be delayed,
and we wouldn't have to do this.
No such luck.
We could... pretend
that you're not back.
We can't cancel again.
We can't.
Tomorrow, then.
[indistinct chatter]
Hello, darling.
[woman] Sagrona teema.
Let me assure you. It's
so good to see you.
I've been looking for you.
I have to say, Mon.
This is remarkable.
[Mon] Mmm.
No one's seen anything
like this for a long time.
Well, perhaps there's
good reason for that.
- [indistinct chatter]
- [chuckles]
And I know apologies
are in order.
I've been so distracted by
all of this. It's impossible.
I was whining.
It's the last thing
anyone wants to listen to.
You've been having a difficult time.
That's when we need to be heard.
I have called your office.
And I've been remiss.
The last time we spoke, you told
me you had new business coming in.
You told me you were waiting.
I think I told you I
was tired of waiting.
This is sounding serious.
It wasn't then.
It might not be now.
I still have several things
pending, it's just...
I have concerns.
The Foundation is
up and running.
Your financial blemishes
have been smoothed over
without anyone being the wiser.
Davo Sculdun obviously
has what he came for.
[♪ somber music playing]
Everyone seems quite pleased
with how they've landed,
and I'm left wondering about
the risk I've taken on.
Please say something.
I'm shocked.
I'm sorry. I feel terrible.
I really had no idea.
Do you know, the irony is it's
the rebellion that's hurt me most.
Rebel activity soured
my investments.
You can see how I might feel...
undervalued.
[breathes shakily]
Absolutely.
How I wish you'd made
this clear sooner.
Yeah, I should've.
Perhaps I thought
it was obvious.
If I haven't, I'm
sorry for that.
Well...
Let me get through this weekend and
I promise we'll figure something out.
I hate having to
say all this, Mon.
Oh.
To an old friend?
After all you've
done for me? Please.
Now, let's celebrate.
Indeed.
[Kellen] I chatted up one
of the soldiers today.
They're moving tomorrow.
[Bix] Where they headed?
It looks like they're going
to Three Hundred next,
but there's no guarantee.
What if we move behind
them to Five Hundred
and just wait till they're done?
Most of the arrests have
been people running.
There must be work there.
[Kellen] We can't move all this.
They want to know
who is living here.
I'll say it's me. I'm legal.
[Kellen] We're doing
everything we can.
Thank you.
[chuckles wearily]
Don't thank me yet.
Not until these
bastards are gone.
We'll have to see what they do.
Just... get prepared.
[whirring]
- [♪ suspenseful music playing]
- [footsteps approaching]
[beeping]
[beeps]
[radio whirring]
[feedback static]
[tuning]
[indistinct chatter]
- He's been chasing you all night.
- [Mon] I'm just stunned.
With no warning?
Well, I suppose I have been
avoiding him. Now I know why.
Perrin said he had to be
carried home last night.
His wife's left him...
Was there a number?
I said I'd get into it once
we'd survived the wedding.
So nothing specific.
Well, he's had some
bad investments.
He sees all this...
It's very troubling.
We'll find a number.
Is there any chance
he'd go to Sculdun?
No, he wouldn't dare.
He can't.
[glasses clinking]
It's Perrin. He's about
to speak. I have to go.
Wait.
We can't leave this
be. You must know that.
I will set a meeting on
Coruscant with Tay next week.
We will find a number.
[guests cheering]
[guest 1] Speech! Speech!
[guest 2] Perrin!
Perrin!
[Perrin] Come on, come on!
Thank you.
Sagrona! Sagrona! Sagrona!
Welcome! Welcome.
Praise to the families
and clans of Chandrila.
Praise to those who have traveled to
share in our most treasured tradition.
As the, uh...
As the father of
the intended maiden,
it is my Chandrilan duty
to greet you, sagrona...
To toast your health,
sagrona teema...
And in our very old
ritualistic, and,
- well, insanely economic fashion...
- [scattered laughter]
...it is also my duty to share
just a single, truthful insight,
sagrona teema solom.
Leida. My sweet Leida.
Stekan...
Pain will find you.
Trouble and disagreement
will arrive without summons.
There's no choice in this.
There's no effort required.
You simply stand still and
the galaxy will deliver
a daily basket of
fresh anxieties
- to your door without fail.
- [scattered chuckling]
But my solom...
My solom seyna...
The Elders know what I'm
talking about, right?
My hope... My hope...
My hope is that you learn to reach
past this constant cloud of sadness.
Pleasure. Gaiety. Amusement.
These are the hidden things.
The music buried beneath
all that noise...
- Joy. Joy!
- [scattered laughter]
Joy...
But joy has no wind at its back.
Joy will not announce its arrival.
You need to listen for it,
and be mindful of how fleeting
and delicate it can be.
But search out these treasures.
A moment of... of
pleasing sensation,
the memory of laughter
and good company,
the comfort of a fine meal.
And for me... [chuckles]
For me, right now, it's
the smile that I can't hide
as I see these two young people
sharing our greatest tradition.
[glasses clinking]
Sagrona.
[all] Sagrona teema solom!
[insects trilling]
[Gerdis] Didn't get
very far, did you?
[Bardi] We're not done yet!
[Gerdis] You'll starve
before you get there!
What's the plan anyway?
Shoot the pilot?
Kill us all?
That'll get you out of here!
You can't live on these melons!
How's he know that?
They've been sneaking.
What is the plan?
Shut up.
[Bardi] Are you backing down?
[Gerdis] I'm
dropping a challenge!
[♪ pensive music playing]
- [thunder rumbles]
- [Gerdis] We're going out.
No shooting unless
they shoot first.
[Flek] Stand together.
- [Gerdis] For Maya!
- [Bayso] For Maya!
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Oi!
[both grunting]
Watch him. Eyes open.
[breathing heavily]
[Bardi] That's far enough.
I'll count to three.
Everything... means everything.
[Gerdis] On three.
One.
Two.
Three.
[thunder rumbles]
What are they doing?
Droppin' their weapons.
- [♪ tense music playing]
- You must be awfully desperate.
If you could see what you look
like, you wouldn't say that.
Five Hands.
Roski rules.
[Gerdis] Roski rules.
Everybody hear that?
Roski rules.
[Cassian] What does that mean?
[Flek] Total submission.
[Gerdis] Pick your second.
[Bardi] Rowd, step up.
[Gerdis] Bayso.
[Bayso] One, two, three...
One, two, three...
[yells]
Let your weapon fall.
[♪ tense music playing]
One, two, three...
[Bayso] One, two, three...
- [grunts]
- Don't move, or I'll kill you.
[Bayso] One, two, three...
[Snee grunts]
- [thunder rumbles]
- One, two, three...
- [yells]
- [Bardi] Come on!
[cheering nearby]
[Bardi] Come on!
[men exclaiming]
One, two, three...
[Bayso laughs] Come on.
[deep rumbling nearby]
[vegetation snapping]
[Bardi] What was that?
- [Snee] I keep thinking it's thunder.
- [Nazy] It's not.
- [roaring]
- [all screaming]
[Plug] No, no, no, no, no!
- [blasters firing]
- [Nazy] What was that?
[♪ tense music playing]
- [Bayso] Bardi! Gerdis!
- [all yelling]
[Rowd] Over there! Over there!
[Doodar roaring]
[Plug] Here! The treeline.
[Plug] Over there! Not this
side... in the treeline!
He's getting away!
They're everywhere!
[Bayso] We're surrounded!
[grunts]
The pilot! He's out!
He's getting away!
[all shouting]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ music fades]
[♪ thrilling music playing]
[♪ mellow music playing]
[♪ music fades]