The restraints are nothing to be feared.
It's much safer for you to
be tethered as we engage.
It doesn't take long.
It won't feel that way to you.
No!
- No! No!
- Bix. Wake up.
You're okay. You're okay...
You're fine. You're safe.
Spiders are not the most
unique thing in ghorman.
There's a mineral underground. Doctor!
Deep substrate foliated kalkite.
The kalkite extraction, I'm
assuming it's an invasive process.
The extent of our withdrawal
may render the planet unstable.
There is a risk of... total collapse.
We don't have a large presence
on ghorman at the moment.
He's planned for that.
We're building a new armory in palmo.
Excuse me?
We're starting tomorrow.
Propaganda will only get you so far.
You need a radical
insurgency you can count on.
You need ghorman rebels you
can depend on to do the wrong thing.
- Did krennic offer you the job?
- You know that he did.
Then it's done. We're in it.
Ghorman will be yours
to run as you wish.
You'll only answer to krennic and
he's got no time for anything but results.
There are no small jobs here
at the bureau of standards.
You may hear that and
wonder how it can be true.
But... not that long ago, I was
standing right where you are now.
Syril, dedra was just telling
me how well you're doing here.
Was she?
And I told her that came
as no surprise to me.
No sign of your husband?
He'll be back.
There you are.
He told me everything.
I know you wanted him to live, but
cassian said he'd seen your faces, so...
You tried.
He knows that.
Wherever he is.
Wasn't much of a soldier, was he?
They'll never find his body.
His family will never
know what happened.
I
I forgot to ask his name.
Might be a bit late now.
Everyone has their own rebellion.
Right?
Breathe. Breathe.
Same thing again? Dr. Gorst?
- You wanna talk about it?
- Just go back to bed.
It's been a while now.
It's being home. Here.
Whatever this place is.
It's when I relax.
We still need to do something
about these windows.
Yeah. We can do that tomorrow.
Get some decent plates.
And towels.
If we're gonna keep coming back,
- we might as well settle in.
- Hey. Hey.
You sure you don't wanna talk about it?
Bix.
I can barely see you.
Turn it.
Mother?
- The other way?
- It's the connection.
The other way.
You might as well be in the outer rim.
- I'm seeing you clearly.
- How nice for you.
There. There, you had it.
- Don't worry about me.
- I'll try to remember what you look like.
- It's an imperial signal.
- It should be fine.
Where are you?
I am in my office.
Requesting a transfer, I hope.
I like it here.
I think you've got spiders in your brain.
Or whatever those things
are called. The web weavers?
Ghorlectipods.
- Good morning, sir.
- The thought of it.
No one understands
what you're doing out there.
And when you say "no one," I'm
assuming you mean uncle harlo?
He says you're deluded if you
think ghorman was a promotion.
His advice is always uplifting.
You're being cast aside.
You're being discarded
and too naive to see it.
- Morning.
- I'm in charge here, mother.
They've put you on the shelf,
syril. You've been played.
You, of all people, should understand
the attraction of being in charge.
- In charge? Of what?
- Counting spiders?
Let's not forget your last
foray into the provinces.
This is the bureau of
standards field office in ghorman.
It's hardly the provinces.
What it is, hardly, is Coruscant.
You were here.
I'd fixed it. You'd made it back.
People die trying for a
desk at headquarters.
And then they die at those desks.
You were here, syril.
You'd found a woman actually
willing to make a life with you,
and you just walk away?
A respectable career,
a relationship, finally?
All of it cast aside,
thrown away, and for what?
A field office on ghorman?
- I'm assuming you won't be visiting.
- They won't get another credit of mine.
I'm not buying ghorman again.
I'm sick of it.
They were always too
good for the rest of us.
You are watching too
much imperial news.
My opinions were well-established
before you relocated.
These are decent people.
Syril, I have met some
ghormans in my time.
Uncle harlo used to wear
nothing but ghorman twill.
Who wouldn't, if you could afford it?
But the attitude. The arrogance.
- Those holo-drops?
- This mockery of emperor palpatine?
You must have seen them. How
could you not? It's scandalous.
- It's propaganda.
- Mother, you're being sold these ideas.
My poor boy.
Your gullibility is breathtaking.
All this anti-ghormanism,
it's not just talk anymore.
We're getting new directives every
month and people are getting hurt.
You're too close to know
what's really going on.
I'll tell you how close I am.
There are people in my office.
I'm looking at two of them right now.
They'll be choking down loyalty
oaths next week just to keep their jobs.
I feel safer already.
I'm here. I see what I see.
This place is hardly
a threat to the empire.
Don't become too much
of an individual, syril.
I have spiders to count.
Same time next wee...
This place is hardly
a threat to the empire.
Don't become too much
of an individual, syril.
- I have spiders to count.
- Same time next wee...
Hey.
- What?
- Let me see the bag.
- What for?
- Seriously?
- I don't like this place.
I thought you meant the other one.
I meant the good one.
This is the good one.
- We need to mix it up.
- We haven't been here for a month.
Look at us.
I can't sleep. You can't shop.
The mission is dinner.
I think we can handle it.
Okay. Come.
Hello there. What can I do for you two?
We got some lovely new fruits in.
- What about the melons?
- Excellent choice. They're in season.
Fresh from ukio. I'll find a good one.
I need three.
Ripe tonight or tomorrow?
Tonight.
I haven't seen you for a
while. Thought I'd lost you.
I've been around.
These are lovely. For a lovely lady.
- Anything else today?
- No. No, no. We're good.
Are those moski peppers?
Extra hot.
My husband wants a taste.
Is he strong enough?
He's tougher than he looks.
Okay.
One? Got two.
This is a lovely one.
- You, sir?
- Seriously?
Perhaps you've changed your mind.
- Really? Tonight's the night?
- Well, these are special.
I'm not a tourist. You know it.
- This one's different.
- I'm not buying another spider.
This one's free.
What do you want?
You're right. You're not a tourist.
Perhaps you wish to know
more about where you live.
There's a candy inside with
information on the wrapper.
- About what?
- There's a meeting.
You should come. You have the address.
We should've done this before.
There's already tarnish.
We were tired. We needed the rest.
Clean it with dirjo.
There's not much left.
Put it on the list.
Who else stays here?
You ever think about that?
No one's been here while we were gone.
You should see if we can leave stuff.
If we're gonna keep coming back.
I'll ask him.
What are you gonna tell him?
About what?
About what happened on
the mission. The soldier.
Luthen cares about results.
The deal went through. We won.
It had to be done.
There's nothing else to say.
What?
Hey, he was a threat.
He was a soldier.
Bix, you put on the uniform,
you take your chances.
I should stop thinking about him.
It's tough like this.
Boxed in.
It's like you said. It's when we relax.
I can't stop seeing his face.
It fades.
I wanna tell you it goes
away forever, but... I'd be lying.
Look at us.
Look at this place.
We're in a war.
Not everybody knows
it yet, but it's happening.
- People die.
- I wonder if he knew.
Well, he does now.
He was a soldier. He was a threat.
He was an imperial threat.
You and I are here
now because he's dead.
It had to be done.
It's good.
You sound surprised.
You're better than I am.
No, no. No, no, no. I'm
not gonna fall for that one.
Can we walk tomorrow?
That sounds nice.
The park. The big one.
I told you, they... They put cameras in.
We can cover up.
There's other places.
We're safe here.
I know it's not what we want, but...
The insanity of the city keeps us safe.
Then why are we being so paranoid?
- Just trying to protect us.
- You mean me.
- What's so wrong about that?
- It's warping things.
I don't wanna lose you again.
That's not up to us anymore.
You can't protect me.
Doing this... living like this...
Mission after mission.
If it's a war,
and you keep saying it is,
and I know that you're right,
but if it's a war, it's not
up to us what we save,
what we lose.
I love you.
And I regret every second
that we didn't spend together.
But I'm trying not to
count on anything anymore.
What am I messing up?
I can handle more than you think.
Which is why you are
awake every other night.
I'm not maarva. I'm not your sister.
- I can...
- seriously.
- I can handle it.
- What am I messing up?
You didn't kill that boy
because we're at war.
You killed him because he saw my face.
What's the difference?
I don't know.
But if I'm giving up everything.
I want to win. We have to.
I, left some files in the office.
Syril karn, division chief,
bureau of standards.
I know you.
It's gonna want after-hours clearance.
It'll take five minutes.
Sorry. We're not authorized.
I have a presentation with the
sector committee tomorrow morning.
I left my notes on my desk
like an idiot. I have to have them.
Take me five minutes.
Or I could tell you where they are.
- Where are you?
- The safe room.
- You were careful?
- Yes, of course, always.
- Look, I don't have much time.
- Sorry. Tell me.
They made contact.
I've been invited to a meeting.
- A meeting with who?
- I don't know. It's public.
It's a town hall. But this is them.
It's ghorman front. I know it.
- How? How do you know?
- I told you I was being watched.
They started breaking into the apartment.
I know they're tapping the office comms.
I assume I'm being followed all the time.
It has to be them. Who else could it be?
- The meeting's tomorrow.
- Good.
Very good.
Well, let's wait and see what happens.
Well, I thought you'd
wanna brief partagaz.
No.
He'll want more than that.
The 12 raids, conducted over all
three planets were highly successful.
Giving us a total of eight
seizures, yielding 200,000 credits,
75 restricted imperial
weapons and 34 arrests.
All of which leads us where?
We're ingesting the data.
- This was ten days ago?
- Yes, sir.
We? Who's the "we" at
this buffet of rebel plunder?
It's my sector, sir.
Supervisor heert.
- Yes, sir.
- The axis desk,
I notice you've taken
an interest in this seizure.
The weapons, sir. There are some pieces
that have come from
the axis supply chain.
Have we nothing more definitive?
- No, sir. Not yet.
- Not yet?
Ten days, two supervisors,
30 suspects in custody,
and we are still
ingesting and speculating.
Where's the intel?
So what do we squeeze
from these arrests that matter?
- No argument there, sir.
- Hardly the tempo required
for effective counterinsurgency.
It's disappointing on many levels.
I see a variety of causes.
Pick one!
We're arresting too many people.
We can't take it all in.
Go on.
Many of us...
Some of us...
Some of us have more people
in custody than we can process.
Supervisor jung raises a serious issue.
The problem is not unknown to me.
Colonel yularen and myself have a
meeting scheduled with the emperor
to discuss amplifying our intake process.
Well played, lonni.
Thank you for reminding us all
how this room is meant to function.
Let's get to work.
Thank you. I mean it.
- I'm having the same problems.
- I can't keep up.
We should talk it over. Not here, but.
I'm in all day.
You're onto something.
That's the job, isn't it?
Seventy-five restricted
imperial weapons?
You've had that ten days?
It's my desk now, dedra.
You don't call me in?
You don't think I could be helpful?
I won't hesitate if I need it.
Do you really think I care
about how it happens?
Andor must be found.
You can have all the glory.
Has it ever crossed your mind
that partagaz put me on axis
because I don't seek glory?
Well...
You've given me a lot to think about.
My door is open.
That doesn't look happy.
Yeah. She's been transferred.
Everything's pissing her off.
- I won't ask.
- But you, thank you.
He was gonna chew his way
through lagret and eat me for fun.
I don't know what I was thinking.
How do I repay you?
You can buy me lunch.
Done.
The p.O.R.D. Was presented as an
emergency measure, an overreaction.
It was never meant to be permanent.
The emperor might disagree.
Well, then, why ask for an extension?
Why?
Perhaps he just likes to see us dance.
Ghorman needs this
legislation more than anyone.
If I can't count on your
support, what's the point?
I need votes.
And you've been hiding from me. Why?
Sector boundaries, civil liberties,
personal freedom,
respect for local traditions.
You've been voting with
me on these issues for years.
This is security, mon.
You're confusing
criminality and politics here.
Really?
Are we finding criminals
or making them?
Why?
Why this? Why that?
I can't support the bill because
I can't risk chafing the emperor.
But why I'm in this position and
why it seems to be intensifying,
and why ghorman is
being persecuted so intently,
are questions no one
seems prepared to answer.
Go back two years.
Take the 75 planets with
the lowest crime rates.
Look at them now.
They're up 19%.
We can all game the numbers, mon.
And whose numbers are they?
I believe what I feel.
All doubts aside, there
is one glaring certainty.
If we do not stand
together, we will be crushed.
I know how hard
you're working this, mon.
I am close on the votes.
That's not what I hear.
Look at just the conviction
numbers we're allowed to see
in the places we know are peaceful.
An 18% rise in kaifo. Tepasi, 21.
A 38% increase in ghorman.
Ghorman, of all places.
I'm not sure linking anything to
ghorman right now is a good idea.
- The blockade.
- Who was there for you?
Who rallied the votes to lift the embargo?
I have never stopped thanking you.
Then help me kill the p.O.R.D.
Ghorman is a single-product economy.
We import almost
everything we need to survive.
The blockade didn't have to go very
long to remind us how vulnerable we are.
Dasi...
No.
I am constantly begging
my people to stay calm
and do nothing that
might make things worse.
Voting against the emperor right now
would be a total violation of that request.
Ghorman cannot take the risk.
I'm sorry, mon.
Hello, lonni.
- You've kept me waiting.
- I've been careful.
- Three months.
- I didn't have anything solid until today.
Well, let's have it.
You ask two questions.
One answers the other.
Spit it out!
Dedra meero is running ghorman.
She's been on it all year.
All this time. Hiding it.
I doubt there's three
people in the building
that know what I've just told you.
Why? Why ghorman?
I don't know. I can't believe
they've kept it so quiet.
Everybody thinks that she's
been put out to pasture since ferrix.
What's the obsession with
ghorman? What are they after?
I don't know. I'm trying to rethink
this all with her in the picture.
It doesn't make sense.
All the propaganda.
That can't be isb. It's too
slick. That's outside help.
And meero. Why? She's
a hunter, not a spin doctor.
- Maybe she's oversight.
- Of what?
A smear campaign is an
opening move, not an endgame.
I need the endgame!
I don't have it.
I'm trying.
Are you sure of this?
As of today.
And meero's off axis for good?
Not by choice, but yes.
I can't wait another three months,
lonni. There's too much going on.
You used to tell me to wait.
Those days are gone.
You're up-to-date on
the signal sequence?
Yes.
We'll be standing by.
Le... lezine!
What do you think?
It's very passionate.
How much do you understand?
Not enough.
She lost her family
in the tarkin massacre.
There was a promise that
the new imperial building
would never cast a
shadow across the memorial.
Now they know the truth.
Lezine!
People think the new building
is meant to be a fortress.
He's telling them he doesn't know.
What do you think?
Hello.
- How are you?
- Her name is enza.
Syril.
He's an imperial spy. Be careful.
It's not funny.
- It's not true, is it?
- No. I...
He invited me.
I'm at the bureau of standards.
Yeah. That's a relief.
- Hey.
I was thinking of
introducing you to my father.
Elector rylanz.
Syril karn.
I saw you from the stage.
I stand out that much?
No, that's what's interesting.
You're very brave to be here.
Am I in danger?
Certainly not from us.
This is ghorman.
I was wondering about your people.
There are no restrictions
on my movements in palmo.
And what will you take
away from this evening?
The strength of feeling.
Will you be writing a report?
No, I... to who?
I'm here as myself.
What a refreshing position.
It might be helpful to have your advice.
There must be some way to
make our appeals more effective.
I'm not sure that's allowed.
Is there a law against
seeking imperial counsel?
I suppose not.
We're drowning in rumors, syril.
Many people are starting to think this
new building is more than just an annex.
I'm not sure why the empire would
build an armory in the middle of palmo,
but I'm running out of answers.
Well, I have nothing
to do with the annex.
You must've seen the floor plans.
Those are classified.
Certainly lends weight to the rumors.
I wouldn't know.
Sixteen years ago, grand moff tarkin
killed 500 peaceful, unarmed
ghormans in the middle of that Plaza.
You can imagine how
upset we would be to find out
there's an imperial military facility
rising over the monument to the fallen.
Yes.
Ghormans yearn for
peace and prosperity.
If you are writing a report...
Make that your headline.
Maybe we can do some good together.
Hey, you okay?
Yeah.
Couldn't sleep.
Dr. Gorst?
Not tonight.
Have a look.
It's flashing.
We just got back.
Ever been to ghorman?
Where they make the fabric? No.
I want you to try something different.
This will be clean work. You
bring nothing but your wits.
I need an assessment.
Of what?
Of who. Carro rylanz.
Businessman, city official.
- He's running the ghorman front.
- You know him?
In my way.
We never met.
Kleya put a radio in,
there was a rebel pilot that went
down and we tried to help, but.
I can't go. He's too visible.
I'm not sure about the group.
It's a different kind of mission,
but it's not without danger.
And bix?
No, not this time.
No.
You have to go alone.
I have to think about that.
Think about this.
Think about the empire
choking ghorman so hard
that even carro rylanz
gets off his comfortable ass
to do something about it.
Ghorman would be a
remarkable place to turn our way.
I need to know more
before we get involved.
Bix will be fine.
You don't know that.
And I haven't said yes.
Reach out to kleya.
I want this done quickly.
Look at you.
Look at all your loveliness.
How I have dreamt of this.
Is she healthy?
Yes.
Everything's here?
All the tools? Full kit?
Eight variations. Six gauges.
Think of it, comrades. Fuel on demand.
All the rhydo that you can steal.
A galaxy of opportunities!
Work up a thirst. Find a vein.
Take what you want, when you want it.
Yes.
Has it been tested?
It works.
Who taught you this?
Why is that important?
Why?
What's more dangerous
than rhydonium?
Not many old pipe-poachers out there.
Not many who've lived to tell the tale.
Who taught you this?
I'm here to teach the variations.
More than that, I'm not allowed to say.
Look at this.
A brave one!
But how brave?
Have you ever seen a
man die from rhydonium?
Maybe you're like me,
maybe you, you love...
The smell of it.
And maybe you breathe
just a little too deeply.
Burned from the inside.
You watch your skin
blister as it melts away.
Or, you die loud.
Cut a line? Drop a wrench? Let it spill?
Don't even need a spark, do you, boy?
Do you?
Boom!
Burn from the outside.
What do they call you?
- Wilmon.
- Wil. Mon.
Wilmon the boy.
Have you ever done this for
real? Or just in a classroom?
I've done it.
Never alone, but I've done it.
- Twice.
- And you're still alive.
Pluti.
This is pluti.
He's smarter than he
looks. He'll be your student.
- Which variation?
- Pick one.
Start with your favorite.
Well, we should concentrate on
the station you're planning to hit.
You'll teach them all.
You'll know where we're
going when I tell you.
- But I need to leave tomorrow.
- Really?
- Is that what you need?
- It was an agreement.
This was negotiated.
I'll let our friend know that
you're being taken care of.
Find him a place to sleep.
You're here till I get what I need.