If it's a war, and you keep saying it is,
it's not up to us what
we save, what we lose...
But if I'm giving up
everything, I want to win.
I thought you were a local boy.
My father's chandrilan.
I was born in Naboo.
My mother's ghorman.
Bounced around until she passed
away, and then mon stepped in.
Ghorman needs this
legislation more than anyone.
I am constantly begging
my people to stay calm
and do nothing that
might make things worse.
They're finally wanting to do something
and you tell them to be careful.
You're thinking small.
You're thinking like a thief.
I'm thinking like a soldier.
Think like a leader.
Tell me what you saw.
I sense the weight of
things, things I can't see.
He's a messenger.
I'm meeting with tay next week.
I'll warn him off. I'll find what it takes.
- I'll get a number.
- You know the number.
We'd be vulnerable forever.
You need to be protected.
I'm not sure what you're saying.
How nice for you.
Luthen wants to know
if you're ready to work.
What does he need me for?
Isb supervisor, dedra meero.
She's there in ghorman,
waiting to be killed.
- What's all this?
- It's a personal trip.
That is unacceptable, and you know it.
All set.
They're on the verge of promoting him,
and then he goes and does
something like this morning.
He'll be there when you need him.
Think about a planet
like ghorman in rebellion.
A planet of wealth and status.
And if it goes up in flames?
It will burn... very brightly.
Open fire!
This is palmo one.
We are under siege.
We're being slaughtered.
The imperial murder
of ghorman has begun.
As I say these words,
hundreds of murdered
ghorman lay dead in palmo Plaza.
Thousands more on the streets.
More every minute.
We're being destroyed!
Who are you?
- If you can...
- If you can hear me...
If you believe in truth, if
you have any faith left in truth,
please, please Mark this
message and pass it forward.
Help us!
Is there no one who can help us?
Is there no one?
I am a senator! With the
full rights and protections...
What's going on?
- Ambassador oran...
- He's being arrested.
- Stand back and get your arms off!
- What?
- Stormtroopers!
- In the senate!
No warrant! No charges!
This is the senate chamber,
I have every right to be here.
Will no one help me?
Ghorman is being slaughtered!
It's my people today and yours tomorrow!
Remember this day!
Remember ghorman!
This will be you soon enough.
Remember this day!
Have you seen the
numbers? The ghorman dead?
It's beyond belief.
Don't put on the imperial news.
- I've seen it. It's insane.
- The winner writes the story.
Well, they haven't won yet.
I need to make a speech tomorrow.
They'll never let you take the floor.
Well, I've seen you work miracles before.
Has to be done, bail.
I can't take it anymore.
And yes, I know there's no
telling what the emperor's...
Capable of at this...
At this point, anything is possible.
But they've gone too
far and we all know it.
We need to speak out. We need
to stand up, and speak the truth,
and then we need to leave. Both of us.
We need an exit plan, and we need to
make it now while we still have the time.
We have a plan. That's not the issue.
Then what is it?
I'm not going anywhere.
- Are you telling me to be silent?
- It's not like that.
Senator.
We talked about this. What
might happen. If this isn't the limit,
- then what is?
- It's not so easy.
Compared to what? Nothing we will ever do
will be as hard as hiding all these years.
Mon.
It's not that... at all.
It's me.
I have to stay. We have to buy time.
We're not ready. Yavin isn't ready.
We need to stall.
But you're right,
something needs to be said.
And yavin needs your
leadership. I just can't go with you.
Not yet.
You'd be a hostage.
Let's hope not.
Work on the speech, and be very careful.
Senator ton found a
listening device in her office.
And tell no one.
Be ready to leave the
moment you're done.
And be very careful.
They're calling an early
session at the senate.
If she speaks, we need to be ready...
So we're keeping you a journalist.
It's perfect.
Ronnie googe, mid-rim network.
You're coming straight
from the ghorman massacre
to cover the political fallout.
There's a senate
catering entrance we like.
These credentials will work inside, but
they scan for weapons at the entrance.
You'll wanna hang on to this one.
It's a surface pass, it's good all season.
I won't be needing it.
I'm not coming back.
I'm done after this.
Are you?
What does that mean?
Done?
Done with what? With us? With all of it?
He'll know what it means.
So, it's a private thing,
something I wouldn't understand.
- I didn't say that.
- Can I guess?
You're tired. It's too much. It's too hard.
You were a witness to
the ghorman massacre,
one would think there'd
be no stopping you.
The senator you'll be saving
is about to risk everything
putting a voice to the
atrocity you just survived.
Tell her you're "done."
When have I not come through?
I need to start making my own decisions.
I thought that's what we were fighting for.
Clean yourself up.
I'll find you some clothes.
I need to keep looking.
We have to be sure.
I need to practice the speech.
Not here. Not yet.
Get some air. Go to the Plaza.
It's not on our end.
So it just went dead?
The death of truth is
the ultimate victory of evil.
When truth leaves us...
When it is ripped from our hands,
vulnerable to the appetite of
whatever monster screams the loudest...
How did you know I would be here?
Erskin Semaj works for me.
He wanted to tell you
himself, but here we are.
All this time?
He's protected you in
ways you'll never know.
Well, isn't that wonderfully cryptic?
Who else am I trusting that I shouldn't?
Everyone?
Well, let me guess. In the end,
it's only you I can trust. Is that it?
Tonight, that's true.
Is it?
Bail organa's team is corrupted.
Which team is that?
The one that's taking you
to yavin after your speech.
I don't know everything, mon,
but I know what I owe you.
You don't care about me.
You're just terrified what'll
happen if I get arrested.
You need to think clearly.
Be careful what you ask for.
You can't leave with bail's people.
And you can't tell anyone
what I've just told you.
Do you remember tay kolma?
The banker? My childhood friend?
Another false savior.
I often think of tay kolma.
How quickly you decided he was a
risk. How quickly all that happened.
If you go with bail's plan,
you'll be in a cell before sunset.
It makes me quite a risk, doesn't it?
Right now, I'm more
afraid of you than anything.
We've all been bent
by secrecy, haven't we?
And I'm sorry about erskin,
but what I'm telling
you about bail is true.
Don't you dare!
What I'm telling you cannot be shared.
I'm sending someone I trust,
someone I know I can trust.
You'll ask if he's alone.
He will say, "I have friends everywhere."
"I have friends everywhere."
Those words.
Supervisor grandi isn't
in yet. I'm still on call.
Is it something that can wait?
Senator mothma, we
have a field agent with her.
Yes, I know. Her driver.
He's been calling in.
Apparently, she's not
left the senate tonight.
Is that unusual?
He seems to think so.
We were told to pay particular attention
to the senate for the next few days,
given the situation in ghorman.
Do we have a console?
The technicians said
there's no malfunction
or communication issues on our end.
Right here, these are all senators
the select council have approved
for increased surveillance.
It's always a bit quiet this early,
but... that's senator mothma.
It's gone dead.
Plus the driver, it
seemed worth mentioning.
We free to speak?
I've searched everything.
I'm not sure I've felt
this... Betrayed in my life,
and I've... Had some experience.
When... did you start?
After the wedding.
Two years.
That's obscene.
I've tried to protect you.
And you've failed.
I'm sorry you feel that way.
You're dismissed.
Immediately.
It's been an honor.
I wasn't sure you'd come.
Wilmon?
There was someone he needed to find.
Excuse me. We have
an immediate problem.
Did you talk to mothma?
What are we doing?
I shouldn't have told her about erskin.
Is she speaking or not?
I don't know.
Somebody knows.
- Where are you?
- I'm walking to the senate.
I'm out. She threw me out.
Is she going through with it?
Ask luthen. We didn't have
much of a conversation.
We get her out, she
goes to yavin and not you?
No yavin for me.
There's still some
Bridges you haven't burned.
We'll take care of that today.
You've stayed here long enough.
I'm not finished yet.
They're gonna find you, luthen!
You act as if we had a choice.
Eventually, they'll hang
us both, won't they?
We set that course the first time we met.
Speak for yourself.
You see no truth in that?
I make my own decisions.
Is that what you've been doing?
Sometimes, I wonder.
You appeared when I needed you.
Aldhani.
Narkina. Ferrix.
Sienar. Mina-rau. Ghorman.
And here we are.
She threw him out.
We don't know if she's speaking,
what she'll say, or how they'll react.
All we know about bail organa's
team is that there's something wrong.
It's hardly ideal.
There's no choice but to try.
We have nothing. He's
never even been inside.
Erskin knows the building.
Putting a lot of faith in erskin.
Mothma knows the building.
And doesn't trust me.
And doesn't know him.
Bail's people might be there already.
And? If she gets arrested?
It all comes down.
Hello?
Identify yourself.
Kloris, sir. Exmar kloris.
Have you located senator mothma?
- No, sir.
- She's been in there all night.
Or she's gone home without you.
Without letting me know?
That's not like her. I doubt it.
She was upset, sir. The
news out of ghorman.
Let us know if anything changes.
Will do. Yes, sir.
Scan docs, please.
Proceed.
Yes, madam. Thank you.
- Ronnie goo...
- "Goo-ja."
Did someone call it in?
Mid-rim network.
I see that. I just don't have
a bay assigned for you.
You'll have to float this morning.
That's the best I can do today.
- You've met?
- Just now.
What are we doing?
Senator mothma's making a speech.
When she's done, we'll
escort her to the Plaza
where there's a ride waiting.
Weapons?
We have a box inside, but the plan
is for a quick and quiet extraction.
Gate 9. She'll meet us there.
We'll pull the gear
and meet you up there.
To make a difference here...
I represent the people...
Well, I'm stuck here now, so
let me know if anything changes.
There are rumors that
prominent senators may try
to challenge the imperial
narrative on ghorman.
I've just been told the
morning agenda is set.
The chair has no intention of
letting any of them take the floor.
Here we are. This day has finally come.
You don't have to do this.
If you're brave enough to stay,
I should be brave enough to go.
There'll be an escort team
waiting. A team of three.
You need to leave the
moment you're done.
They'll be at gate 9.
Get down there. Do what they tell you.
- Do you trust them?
- Of course.
Do you know them?
Personally? No. I can't.
It's not safe.
Don't worry about me.
Once I get you started,
I'll have my head down.
Next year. In yavin.
Take care of yourself, bail.
We do what we can.
Tear the shit out of this place.
The senate is called to chamber.
Make your presence known.
Stewards, you may count the quorum.
You'd think it'd be full today.
They call an early session when
they want to keep the numbers down.
The stewards have declared a quorum...
Have we met?
It's possible.
I have friends everywhere.
Immediately following this session,
we shall submit a list of
our fallen, imperial patriots,
martyrs who gave everything
on the brutal streets of ghorman.
A list that, even now, grows longer
as the full measure of ghorman
perfidy comes into focus.
There's a rope line at the gate.
Take this. It's the only way in,
and I'm the last person she wants to see.
Were we not warned?
Were there not voices raising
the alarm about ghorman long ago?
As the threat grew,
did we not Mark the arrival of
every new ghorman provocation?
The tragic broth we sip this morning
has been brewing in plain sight!
The only surprise about
yesterday's insurgency
was the savagery of the ghorman attack!
We, too, lost a citizen
yesterday on the ghorman Plaza.
We, too, are grieving and wondering
what more we might've
done to stop this insurrection.
Watch the door. I'll get the blasters.
And to those who fail to see
this as an emergency, I say,
"what will you tell your people"
"when it is one of your citizens
who've been slaughtered?"
Sir... one of supervisor jung's
agents is calling from the senate.
She says it's urgent.
Line 2.
Hello?
Hello.
Identify yourself.
What're you doing?
Who're you talking to?
It was work.
- Show me that.
- Sure.
Hello?
The chair recognizes the
senior senator from hodi.
Graciously accepted, thank you.
I would, as senior senator,
like to yield a moment of my time
to the senior senator of Alderaan
who has a point of order to address.
Thank you, senator erveen.
I need instructions.
I'm putting on the supervisor in charge.
She... she's back on, sir!
I know there's a strict
agenda this morning,
but as per the latest imperial
ruling on senate protocols,
a-17-252, was, as you may recall,
proposed directly by
the emperor's council...
And specifically states that,
"a senior senator, in
the case of emergency"
"may yield the floor freely,"
"without interruption to
another senior senator."
Now, senator karloo
spoke so passionately
about the imperial martyrs from
yesterday's events in ghorman.
I listened very
carefully, as did you all...
And he clearly, and repeatedly,
used the word "emergency,"
and as there's been no objection
to this description from the floor,
I am invoking article 17-252
and yielding the floor to the
senior senator from chandrila.
Shut down the senate feed.
Imperial authority.
Shut it down.
Yes.
Fellow senators, friends, colleagues...
Allies, adversaries.
I stand before you this
morning with a heavy heart.
The chandrilan emblem on the door.
I've spent my life in this chamber.
I came here as a child.
- Hey.
- Thank you.
And as I look around me now,
I realize I have almost no
memories that pre-date my arrival...
And few bonds of affection
that cleave so tightly.
Through these many years,
I believe I have served
my constituents honorably
and upheld our code of conduct.
- Where were you?
- Where's charval?
He was with you.
- This chamber...
- He said to meet you.
Is a cauldron of opinions...
And we've certainly all had
our Patience and tempers tested
in pursuit of our ideals.
Disagree as we might.
I am hopeful that those of you who
know me will vouch for my credibility
in the days to come.
I stand this morning
with a difficult message.
I believe we are in crisis.
What are they doing?
The distance between
what is said... Shut it down!
And what is known to be
true has become an abyss.
It's locked. Why is it locked?
It's supposed to be.
It hasn't been locked all year.
- We know. We fixed it.
- What?
- We checked the protocol...
- open it!
- You need the sequence key.
- So let's have it!
We took it up to the
security office yesterday.
Of all the things at risk
the loss of an objective reality
is perhaps the most dangerous.
The death of truth is
the ultimate victory of evil.
When truth leaves us,
when we let it slip away,
when it is ripped from our hands,
we become vulnerable to the appetite
of whatever monster screams the loudest.
I don't care if you have to cut
power to the whole chamber!
Get her off the air!
This chamber's hold on the truth
was finally lost on the ghorman Plaza.
What took place yesterday...
What happened yesterday on ghorman
was unprovoked genocide!
Yes! Genocide!
And that truth has been
exiled from this chamber!
And the monster screaming the loudest?
The monster we've helped create?
The monster who will come
for all of us soon enough...
Is emperor palpatine!
They shut her down. They
shut down the broadcast.
Where's cassian?
He went up.
Look, we can't wait here much longer.
Senator.
I can't speak right now.
I was in ghorman yesterday.
I saw everything. In the Plaza.
I've made my statement.
No. We need to speak.
I have friends everywhere.
Detained immediately. She
does not leave the building!
Your cousin vel is a friend.
Anyone could say that.
We're the last survivors
of the raid on aldhani.
I see her in yavin.
I live there.
I know luthen can be hard...
But if he's right about this...
You have no choice but to come with me.
You just keep walking.
I'll be right behind you.
Senator mothma!
The senator has no
comment at the moment!
Let her through! Let her through!
Can we get a comment, please?
Move, please! Please!
Excuse us! The senator has a
very important meeting to get to.
- Who are you?
- We're here to help you.
- She doesn't need your help.
- Let's move ahead.
- Stand down, everyone!
- She's got a gun!
- What're you doing?
- Shut up! Back off!
This is an isb authorized arrest!
Call your supervisor now!
Back away! That means you!
- She's a rebel spy!
- No!
Anyone else?
- Who are you?
- Nobody.
We just met, I swear!
- We have no time to figure this out.
- I know.
Go, I'll get there.
We need three minutes.
- I... I'm not isb...
- shut up!
Down!
Are you sure?
I've got this, go!
Okay.
Don't run. Don't run!
You killed that woman!
Put this on.
We need to get to the rear loading
dock. There's a ride waiting for us.
I'm not sure I can do this.
Welcome to the rebellion.
- What?
- The loading dock.
She's gone.
They're shutting down the building.
Forget the loading dock.
He's asking to evacuate the building.
No! Seal it up! Lock it down!
Where's jung's agent?
We're still trying!
They're at gate 9.
They've killed jung's agent.
- You were told to stand by!
- Right, I am standing by. I was just
- call when you have something to report!
- Yes. Of course. I was just making...
Where are they?
You have to get back to the gallery.
They're coming down
here. You have to warn them.
I'll find them!
Look, I'm trying, but
we've got to be ready.
Go to the gallery.
Secure the area! Cover all the exits!
We're in lockdown! No
one goes out! Move it out!
What's going on up there?
I wish I knew.
That's my driver.
- Would he help?
- No, no, no, he's an isb plant!
- What's his name?
- What?
- Name!
- Kloris.
Kloris! Kloris!
- What are you doing?
- We found her!
And who are you?
Hey. Look at me!
Hey, hey, hey, look at me.
Give me your hand.
Colonel yularen on line 3.
All right, everything on the table.
Fall in! Let's go!
Quit your moving about!
Last call on ordnance,
if you've got a weapon
and it's not on that table,
it means you're either
too stupid to follow orders
or you're a threat to base security.
Once the duty officer
has made inspection,
everything that meets
approval will be returned.
Who belongs to this?
I think that's mine.
Are you all right?
I can't believe you made it.
You must be exhausted.
Is he back there?
Made it out. Dreena saved the day.
He needs a real doctor.
Kleya.
Luthen.
He's safe.
He knows you made it back here.
Almost home.
You need to leave right away.
She may need a few
minutes to catch her breath.
She's not going with you.
There's a ship waiting. They
want her to make a speech.
They want her coming
in with a yavin escort.
They wanna rewrite the story.
What does luthen want?
He wants wilmon with a doctor.
Get him ready.
You know this place.
Yeah.
I lived here once.
I'm not sure...
How to thank you.
Make it worth it.
- Let's lift him by the arms.
- Careful.
- Let's go.
- One. Two.
Be careful.
Hey, go with them.
They'll fix him up.
Get some rest. Go.
Is it bad?
No.
It's clean. He's young.
Who's his nurse?
She survived the ghorman massacre.
She'll fit right in.
We are not gonna log this
in. Any of this. That's the plan.
Gold squadron will
deliver the senator to yavin.
She's making a speech, we
need it broadcast as far as possible.
It's the result that matters.
We can listen in my office if you like.
I've heard her before.
There's a dead kx unit bagged up inside.
Kx droid?
I think we got all the pieces.
What is it?
Nerian leaf.
You need to sleep.
Is that what I need?
I'm done, bix.
- Have your tea.
- I'm serious.
I'm done. I'm not doing it anymore.
I've done what I can.
And I've done a lot, but...
But I want... this.
Right here.
I wanna be with you.
I'm gonna talk to Draven tomorrow.
We'll leave before it
gets too complicated.
We'll find someplace quiet.
There's still places to go to.
We have what we need.
Why aren't you saying anything?
I'm listening.
The only special thing about me is luck...
And I've overplayed my hand already.
Nothing's worth more than this.
- I mean it.
- I know.
I know you do.
Bix?
My love. You're sleeping now.
You look so peaceful.
I wanna be brave, but I can't.
If I was brave, I would
stay and do this in person...
But I know you and
you'd just talk me around,
and I've been thinking about
this too long to let that happen.
I have to leave.
I have to go away.
I'm not sure where or for how long,
I just know that I can't
stay here with you now.
I believe what you said.
It is a choice.
It just can't be me.
I can't be the reason you leave here.
If you ever gave this up for me, I'd.
I'd never forgive myself.
We have to win.
We have to beat them.
And I believe you have purpose in
making that happen. I need to believe that.
So, I'm choosing for the both of us.
I'm choosing the rebellion.
Hey! You can't stand there!
We're waiting on a freighter,
we gotta keep this clear.
The outbound. The
transport, where are they?
Everything that's
leaving went this morning.
- And when it's done...
- When it's over...
And we've won...
We can do all the things we ever wanted.
Everything we'd know we've missed.
I'll find you.
- Captain and or?
- They were looking for you.
They're getting ready to power
up the droid you brought in.
The kx unit?
So...
It either works or... it doesn't.
We can tweak endlessly once it's stable.
It's really just a question of whether
the cortex-swap is rejected or not.
You'll hear a lot of blather
about "re-programming,"
which makes it sound as though it's a
problem solved behind a console, but...
That's nonsense, frankly.
It's really all about
"impulse suppression,"
which is an entirely...
Engineering and wiring issue.
Right. We have some
protective goggles here.
I'll take a weapon.
You may wish to take a step back.
Turn it on.
It's just... I'm not sure that's safe.
Hit the switch.
Very well.
If that makes us ready.
Three.
Two.
One.
Hello.
If I've offended you, I apologize.
If not, I'd appreciate you
pointing that elsewhere.