Six years.
- No, no, wait!
- Take him.
Change of guidelines.
- I didn't do anything! Hey!
- Take it up with the Emperor.
I'm just a tourist!
Welcome to Narkina Five.
This is an Imperial factory facility.
You've all been assessed as labor-worthy.
It's the shop owner on Ferrix.
She's looking for Cassian Andor.
His mother is ill.
She may have a lead.
Likely, the ISB working her radio.
- You're guessing!
- And you're slipping.
My name is Kino Loy.
I'm the Five-Two-D unit manager.
The forty-nine men
in this room answer to me.
You see the white lights?
That's the floor.
White is cold, red is hot.
They doubled everyone's
number last month.
P-O-R-D.
He's never heard of it.
- The resentencings.
- I don't know anything about it.
Don't look at the number.
- You're here 'til they don't want you.
- Melshi!
Get straight with that? Your worries...
That's enough.
You have engaged the curiosity of the ISB.
I'm just trying to clear my name.
One would think
you'd want to leave Ferrix far behind.
One would be wrong.
Caleen!
Bix Caleen.
- Run!
- Get her!
- No, no, no, no!
- He railed it!
- Who?
- Veemoss!
You're the ones gonna be
shorthanded all day tomorrow.
Think about that
when you're gettin' fried.
Hello, Bix.
I don't like wasting time.
But one must be careful.
You pull in the net and the easy thing,
the quick thing,
is to assume that everything
you've dragged to shore is a fish.
I have colleagues who believe
that's the prudent mindset
in defense of the Empire.
But I take a more nuanced view.
I try.
So here's what we'll do, Bix.
I'll tell you everything I know,
and in doing so, perhaps convince you
to cooperate without intervention.
Failing that,
we have Dr. Gorst,
who's developed a unique interview system
some of us are very excited about.
As you now know,
we brought in Salman Paak last night.
We tracked him
to a radio hidden in his yard
and thought he might cooperate
without encouragement.
For a man with very little actual
rebellious activity on his resume,
he was remarkably resistant,
which of course just makes us think
there's more to be learned.
Which leads to a longer session.
And suddenly, it's morning.
And there we are, wasting time.
In the end,
it was a very poor decision on his part.
We learned everything we needed to know,
and quite frankly,
it hardly seems worth the price he's paid.
Paak attended a separatist meeting
two years ago in Jondora
where he met a woman who said
that if he was serious about politics,
he might like to act as liaison
for Ferrix when he returned home.
He was sent the fractal radio unit
you used yesterday afternoon.
Now this unknown woman
who recruited him to the cause
seemed less interested
in generating political activity on Ferrix
than she was in using
your planet's unique commercial position
to acquire stolen Imperial equipment.
Did you know Salman Paak
was paid to keep that radio alive?
Did you know
you were the only one to use it?
Were you aware that the buyer,
your contact,
met Paak only once
before being turned over to you?
You're in my net, Bix.
Are you a fish or are you a thief, hmm?
Seems a shame
to end up on the carving board
if your motivation here is just money.
You have no recorded history
of political troublemaking.
You're a business owner.
Now, I would prefer a conversation
rather than put Dr. Gorst back to work.
But that, for the moment,
is entirely up to you.
You're ISB, aren't you?
Worst of the worst.
You're going to tell me absolutely
everything you know about the buyer.
You seem to enjoy this.
You're going to tell me all about
Cassian Andor and their relationship.
They don't have a relationship.
You will be giving me a full,
detailed accounting of every single piece
of stolen Imperial equipment
you've passed along,
where it came from,
who was bribed along the way,
and where it has gone.
I don't know the buyer.
- Really?
- Really.
Well, Salman Paak says you've had
at least six meetings he's aware of.
He says you sit up on that radio
for hours at a time.
I signal.
Sometimes he answers,
he comes, he buys, he leaves.
Six face to face meetings.
He and Andor, blowing up buildings
and killing security guards.
You're injured trying to warn them.
Your coworker is killed
trying to win your freedom.
Andor and the buyer escape together.
It sounds to me
like a nest of relationships.
When was the last time
you spoke with Cassian Andor?
The very worst thing
you can do right now is bore me.
You're not gonna
believe me anyway, are you?
No.
I suppose not.
- She's all yours, Dr. Gorst.
- Thank you.
Turn.
Ready?
Your side. Fly.
Table three.
They won't be shorthanded all day.
There's a new man coming down.
But we can take the shift if we push.
- We're already up on Four.
- I could use a proper meal.
Two, that's a threat.
Ulaf?
- What do you say, old timer?
- Short timer.
Make a run for the win?
My hand. I might need some help.
- Let's switch.
- What?
- Come on.
- He's right. Switch.
- Why?
- Keef is faster.
- There's a better way of saying that.
- The hand.
- What's all this?
- Just a little rebalancing.
- And...
- Ulaf, what do you owe?
Be 41 shifts tomorrow.
You are the next man out.
You are the shortest of the short.
This swap your idea?
Me? No, no. It's Taga.
Are you kiddin'?
- Turn.
- Wise move.
Ulaf is going home.
New man for them today?
Always the next day, right?
You know the drill.
Oh, the...
The restraints are nothing to be feared.
It's much safer
for you to be tethered as we engage.
There's nothing intrinsically physical
about this process,
but we've had some early trials
that were a bit chaotic.
There's an Outer Rim moon
called Dizon Fray.
There was a sentient species there,
quite unusual.
Extremely hostile to the concept
of an Imperial refueling center
that was being planned.
I say "was"
because they created such a stir
that the local commanders were granted
permission to use any means necessary.
And, um, well, what's important
for our purposes here today
is that the massacre of the Dizonites
was broadcast and recorded
as proof of mission.
They make a sound as they die.
A sort of choral, agonized pleading.
It was quite unlike anything
anyone has ever heard before.
There were three communications officers
monitoring the documentation,
and they were found
hours later huddled together
in various states of emotional distress,
in a crawl space
beneath the ship's bridge.
We've taken the recordings
and modified them slightly,
layering, adjusting.
And we found a section
of what we believe are primarily children,
which has its own particular effect.
Doesn't take long.
It won't feel that way to you inside.
But, um...
Let me know
when you're willing to cooperate.
Oh, and if you're having
difficulty speaking,
just shake your head from side to side.
You'll want to be sure of that, Bix,
that you're cooperating fully.
It's repeat listenings
that cause the most damage.
Are we ready?
Let's get on with it.
Drill away.
I'm taking my run.
On program.
New man on the floor.
Everyone, hold positions.
New man on the floor!
Hold your positions!
Step on to the lift and stop.
Two men back. Two weapons.
- Move forward.
- No boots.
...on that lift.
Silence!
He's touching the rail.
Believe me now?
- The elevator's not wired.
- Up!
Nothing that moves can fry you.
I have a new idea.
Don't wait.
We attack while they're coming down. Now.
- They'll just go back up.
- No.
We make it stop.
We shut it down half way.
Take one guard, one weapon.
This is Unit Five-Two-D.
Level five, room two.
The "D" is for Day-shift.
The 49 men in this room answer to me.
Don't put them away.
Shall we begin?
When was the last time
you spoke with Cassian Andor?
- Let me. Let me, let me.
- I can do it.
- I know.
- Ready up.
I'm ready.
Ready now.
Where do we stand?
Are we in the game?
We're up a rack with an hour left.
What? What's on now?
We just talked about this.
We told you two minutes ago.
Do you think I don't wanna win?
Am I working or not?
One rack up. Ours to lose.
- Turn.
- What are you waiting for?
Keep her here.
Keep her alive.
As a hostage?
She's a witness.
She's the only one
we've got who can identify Axis.
- And Salman Paak?
- I don't care.
I'd like to hang him.
What's left of him anyway.
Make sure they know who's in charge.
As you wish.
The senator from Chandrila
stands with those in opposition
to the Emperor's new
public safety legislation.
Long live the Empire!
Is there a more important issue facing
this body right now
than Imperial overreach?
The Public Order Resentencing Directive
is the next step
on an all too predictable march
toward complete unchallenged authority.
She speaks the truth!
- Boo!
- Keep it down!
Our first responsibility
is to the citizens who have sent us here.
Our second vow is to protect the power
and independence
of this remarkable chamber.
Listen to her!
I stand here today to speak with
senators who've come with open minds,
those of you who still believe
that when we enter this building
we are in a temple.
Drive.
They called from the residence.
Your cousin, she's arrived.
What?
Your cousin.
At the embassy?
She's there now?
Well, they said you'd want to know.
- Where are they coming from?
- Don't know.
Keep it down!
They could keep us here forever
if they wanted.
That's enough from you, Melshi.
Right, everybody settles down right now.
Something's wrong.
Whatever it is,
they're taking their time about it.
What's going on?
What are they saying?
I think it's level two.
- All right.
- It gets stale in here.
Can't be much longer.
You all right, Ulaf?
I'm fine.
Level two, far side.
Taga, something broken?
What's he saying?
Level two.
He's coming this way around now.
- What's he saying?
- Quiet!
What's goin' on?
What was that?
What is that?
It's nothing. Someone didn't load in.
They are counting.
So they cut the power?
What do you think's happening?
Something's wrong on two.
- They're going too fast. I can't read it.
- Everybody, calm down!
Something's really wrong on two.
Look at me.
You haven't got a clue
what they are saying.
"Level two, far side. Level two."
Are you all scrambled or something?
It takes a week for one word
to get all the way up here.
And you're panicking about something
that's happening
on the other side of the building!
How many hands does it take
for one word to get through up here?
It's a long way, yes.
But you've got to admit...
Stand in place.
On program. Feet down.
Face front. Hands on heads.
We will have immediate facility compliance
or we will begin activating
floors without warning.
Bridges on program
will have their doors opened.
All shifts to proceed
immediately to their stations.
It's amazing.
Aunt Vel's been to Tassio Moon,
look what she brought me.
Your father may have an opinion.
We'll see if he lets you wear it.
He lets me do anything I want.
Well, why don't you go try it on?
Where have you been?
- Traveling.
- Six months?
There's a lot to see.
I don't have enough to worry about.
Look at you.
The Empire doesn't rest, Mon.
The Rebellion comes first.
We take what's left.
Tell me you're going home for a visit.
They've been after me to find you.
Of course.
Just came through to see you first
and get cleaned up a bit.
Seriously, Vel,
what does he have you doing?
Who?
You're one to worry about.
Trapped here, boxed in.
- Please tell me you're being careful.
- Things are happening.
There's risk.
There's no other way.
I'm starting to think
we're in over our heads.
- He's got us spinning...
- Stop.
You took a vow.
It fits.
You never think about escaping?
You know I won't answer that.
I'll take that as a no.
Take what you like.
You flap that mouth of yours any longer,
you'll regret it.
I'm sure you've thought about it.
How many guards on each level?
You want out of here alive,
turn that part of your mind off.
Okay.
How many shifts you have left?
217.
So, tell me what you know before you go.
You've been warned.
You think they care what we say?
You're on your own with this.
Why?
You think they're listening?
You think they care enough
to make an effort?
Like you would know.
I know this.
They don't need to care.
All they need to do
is turn this floor on twice a day
and keep their numbers rolling.
Why bother listening to us?
We are nothing to them.
Melshi's right.
We're cheaper than droids
and easier to replace.
Good luck to you.
You think they care what we say?
Nobody's listening.
Nobody.
How many guards are on each level?
Nobody's listening.
Nobody's listening!
You took Gorst.
Good to see that's working out.
Yes, sir.
The interrogation was thorough.
We've no reason to believe
anything was withheld.
But no ID on your Axis.
He's still just 'The Buyer'?
It's disappointing, I know.
But it does suggest
the scope of what he's doing.
Axis obviously runs
a very disciplined operation.
And one that's large enough to not be
reliant on any one network or supplier.
Caleen gave us a list of every piece
of gear that came through Ferrix.
And we think we've already got a match
to a targeting unit recovered
from a safe house
operated by a rebel cell
associated with Maya Pei.
Andor, he's all the way through this.
Yes, and that's what
I'd like to highlight.
He's the local thief, right?
The runaway murderer?
Andor returned to Ferrix three nights
after Aldhani with money in his pocket.
Couldn't that be
from the sale of the Starpath?
Can't be. They left it behind, right?
You're trying to connect Aldhani?
That's a bit of a stretch.
He was clean-shaven.
Andor had shaved.
Question, "Describe his appearance."
Answer, "He'd shaved his beard."
The rebels at Aldhani were clean-shaven.
Two soldiers from the garrison
who got a look at him
felt some similarity
to our reference picture.
Well, that's worth running down.
An Aldhani connection
would certainly amplify interest.
Let's follow that up.
You didn't question the mother?
I decided to wait.
Better now leaving her in place
and standing back.
She's too old and frail
for anything serious,
and if nothing else, she's our bait.
She's the reason Andor came back.
Perhaps they communicate.
If they are, we'll know.
We're on her full-time.
Did you hear it?
- Have you heard?
- What?
What happened to unit two-five.
- We weren't told anything.
- You're kidding.
They don't know about it.
They were fried out!
- They're killed. They're all gone.
- Who said?
- Both shifts.
- A hundred men.
That can't be right.
You've heard nothing.
What did he say?
- I don't know.
- They're all dead.
Who's saying this?
- Maintenance tech.
- We had a team go down.
- They said they fried the whole bridge.
- Speak up.
He told Zinska.
Why?
Ask him.
That's incredible.
Zinska?
He heard they were making trouble.
On program. Feet down.
We will have immediate facility compliance
or we will begin...
What did he say?
What happened on two?
We... We don't know.
They set 'em all free.
- Get on program!
- Kino! Kino!
We need to be careful.
The less they think we know, the better.
Hold your program!
Tighten up and listen!
It's a rumor.
Maybe it's true.
Maybe it's not.
We have heard nothing.
It's just another day, another shift.
So let's keep our mouths shut,
keep our heads down
until we know what's going on.
You're up early.
Home late, up early.
Dressed and groomed.
Trimmed your hair.
Hmm. Something I should know?
I told you not to leave
dinner out last night.
Your message was so brief.
One worries.
You're so busy these days,
perhaps you're forgetting to eat.
You've been searching my room again.
It's called cleaning.
I like a tidy house.
You've been in my private box.
I have ways of knowing.
I find you a job, I press your uniform,
I prepare two meals a day,
I move mountains
to scrape you off the floor
and put you back on your feet,
and what do I reap?
What is the return on my investment?
We were talking about you snooping on me.
The shadow of a son, a tenant, a stranger.
That's new. You'll wanna remember that.
All that time away on Morlana.
What if I'd let your neglect
drive me insane?
Imagine that.
Look back just months ago
when you could easily ignore me.
Imagine.
Imagine I'd cracked
under the weight of your neglect.
and wasn't here now to pick up the pieces.
I've been promoted.
I knew they'd recognize your promise.
The demands of my time will be increased.
Uncle Harlo will be so pleased.
- Drill in.
- Right.
Ulaf, come on, mate.
Pull away.
- Come on, boys. Let's go.
- One, two.
- Let's go.
- I'm there. I'm there. I got it.
That's it. That's it.
- All right.
- Okay, let's go.
Come on, Ulaf.
Hands away.
- Clear.
- Ulaf, hands.
Turn.
Come on, boys. We can do this.
I'll do it. Just... Just get it in.
Come on, boys.
Just the one night, Vel?
I'm afraid so.
Heading back to Chandrila today?
Yes. The Pilgrimage.
Find yourself a husband?
Wasn't on my list of things to do.
Well, you need a widower at this point.
Who's left of any value at your age?
Yes. All the good ones are taken.
We've had an influx
of Chandrilans here recently.
- You remember Tay Kolma?
- I do.
Mother's old boyfriend.
What?
Is that something you've told her?
The key word is "old," darling.
We were in grade school together.
At least you've not gone political, Vel.
All the interesting people
are getting very tedious these days.
No one ever calls me tedious.
Tay Kolma?
Money.
Is that all it is?
I don't have enough to worry about?
Anything I can do?
Yes.
Be a spoiled, rich girl for a while.
Remind people that's who you are.
I'll try.
What have we done, Vel?
We've chosen a side.
We're fighting against the dark.
We're making something of our lives.
- Syril Karn.
- I know who you are.
- What are you doing here?
- I...
I wanted to thank you for the promotion.
I had nothing to do with it.
Well, my boss seems
to think that you did.
We simply gave you a clean bill of health.
Have you been waiting out here?
Yes.
I'd never lie to you.
I...
I needed to find you
and it's not that easy
to thank you for what you did
and what you're doing.
And to follow on and...
Try to follow on the conversation
we had last month.
That wasn't a conversation.
You were brought in for questioning.
Are you stalking me?
I know you work here and I come
sometimes to see if I'll see you.
I am an ISB supervisor.
Do you have any idea
how much trouble you're in right now?
I thought I had ruined my life.
I thought I was done.
After meeting you and discovering,
you understood how dangerous
Cassian Andor was. Just...
Just being in your presence, I...
I've realized that life is worth living.
I realized that if nothing else,
there was justice,
and beauty in the galaxy
and if I just kept going...
Perhaps my deranged belief that there
was something better fated for me
in the future was a dream
worth clinging to.
I could have you arrested,
you are aware of that?
I want what you want.
I sense it. I know it.
You're out of your mind.
I have already given you a second chance.
You come near me again,
you pursue any of this,
and I swear
I'll have you in a cage on the Outer Rim.
There you are. Just came in.
They picked up a rebel pilot an hour ago.
- From our target list?
- No, random.
But he's using
a stolen Imperial masking unit.
- One of ours?
- Well, Corv is checking but...
- Where are they holding him?
- A destroyer off Steergaard.
Get Dr. Gorst,
send him out there immediately.
I already did.
He's own his way.
- Do you want to go?
- Yes. No. There's no time.
I'll interrogate remotely.
Good work.
Go.
I've been over the accounts.
I wish you'd called me sooner.
There were better ways to do this.
It was so easy at the beginning.
If we plan
on making any further donations,
we need to be sure
that the work you've done so far
- isn't gonna come back to haunt you.
- They can't all be hidden?
There's a 400,000 credit withdrawal
that's proving a bit of a problem.
It appears on the ledger,
then it vanishes.
- It needs to be papered over.
- How?
Easiest thing would be a deposit.
If I had that much sitting around,
I wouldn't have burdened you.
How much trouble am I in?
There's no trouble at all
unless they scan the accounts.
But that's coming.
Time is not unlimited.
I need a loan.
A certain kind of loan.
You seem to have thought this through.
We need a Chandrilan banker
with treasury relationships,
and a book of business
that's incomprehensibly huge.
You have someone in mind.
It's not a long list.
- And yet you're afraid to say who it is.
- Davo Sculdun.
He is not a banker.
- He's a thug.
- The wealthiest thug of them all.
Don't tell me
you've spoken to him already.
- I wanted to bring you a solution.
- Have you told him?
That you're feeling constricted
by the new tax laws.
- It's common enough.
- A senator, 400,000 missing.
What will he think?
He'll think you're just like
everyone else he works with.
You want what's yours.
At what cost?
I'm not sure.
He wants to meet you.
He wants to meet here.
Davo Sculdun, here. You must be joking.
I pushed back but...
I could keep looking.
It was a routine customs check.
- Totally random.
- Just the pilot?
- He was the only one on board.
- And no witnesses.
The beauty of it, sir.
He flashed an Imperial profile
for a moment then vanished.
They thought it was odd and pursued.
Any chance he radioed home
before they got him?
He swears he didn't.
He thought he'd get away.
This was a Dr. Gorst interview?
Yes, sir. Confidence is high.
He got the pilot
talking almost immediately.
The Imperial masking device
he used is one of the items stolen
- from the naval yard in Lozash last year.
- Incredible.
Apologies. We were offsite.
We've got a rebel pilot in custody.
One of Anto Kreegyr's group.
He was picked up at a customs check.
We don't think Kreegyr knows
he's gone missing yet.
He's telling us there's a raid planned
on the power station at Spellhaus.
Where was he heading?
- On his way to Kafrene.
- They'll count him missing soon.
Exactly. We don't want
Kreegyr getting spooked.
We can't hang on to him.
We can't let him go.
Destroy the ship.
Make it look like an accident.
There's too much at stake.
If I were Kreegyr, I'd be suspicious.
We want Kreegyr moving forward.
What if we foul the ship?
An accident. Something mechanical.
Have the pilot found dead in the cockpit.
What would happen?
They'd have to find it.
But they'd tow it into Kafrene.
If we did it quickly, staged it properly,
let it drift into traffic.
Make it so. Top priority.
Quickly and carefully.
We leave no trace.
Excellent work.
I want a meeting with military
intelligence immediately about Spellhaus.
Let's go.
Inmates, on program.
Program in place.
Low yield tables in position.
Table two takes the shift
by six racks and three.
Table one in the box.
- Ulaf.
- Come on. Let's get this done.
- Can he stand?
- Yeah.
On program.
Cover him. Cover him. Cover him.
- Hang on.
- Inmates on program.
Program in place.
Low yield tables in position.
Ulaf. Hey, look at me.
Okay.
Almost there. Almost there.
Kino, he needs a doctor.
Get him to the cell.
We're late. Come on. Keep moving.
Keep moving. Keep moving.
One, two, three.
All right. All right.
- Take his head.
- I got you.
Zinska, tell 'em we need
a med tech-up here.
You, get going. Now.
Hang in there, Ulaf.
You've only got a few shifts left.
Then you're going home.
On program.
Step off. Let's go.
Here he comes, Uli.
He'll have you back in your cell
soon enough.
Haven't seen you for a while.
I haven't gone anywhere.
His name's Ulaf.
I've seen him before.
Hold that.
He's only got 40 shifts left.
Just wanna get him up and about.
He's tough as an old rock.
Look at me, brother.
His name is Ulaf.
I don't wanna know his name.
He's got 40 shifts left.
So we just want something
to get him through the next few days.
Get him back on his feet.
That's not an option.
What?
What, you can't save him?
There's nothing to save.
He's had a massive stroke.
What are you doing?
I can't help him.
I can't help anyone.
I need a bag and a trolley.
It's coming.
He's lucky.
He'll pass peacefully, which is more
than I can say for the rest of us.
Another week like this, and you'll
be begging for what he's getting.
What do you mean?
You heard me.
Hold his shoulders. You, hold his legs.
What happened on level two?
You'll want to keep your men in line.
Now hold him.
He'll feel nothing.
He's passed.
What do you mean...
keep my men in line?
What happened down on two?
We need a bag and a trolley.
I said it's coming.
They made a mistake.
A man who was just released on four
ended up back on two the next day.
Word got out on the floor,
and then they killed them all.
You need those other men there?
They're just leaving.
Now.
If he was released...
You heard me.
No one's getting out, are they?
Not now.
Not after this.
At least your friend is free.
You two, on program now.
Up. Hands on your heads.
Move.
Let's go. Come on, let's go.
Now. Let's go.
How many guards are on each level?
Never more than 12.